<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.0</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ISIS1</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>ISIS 1</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>1969-009A</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>International Sats for Ionosph Studies</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>ISIS-A</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>ISIS 1 was an ionospheric observatory instrumented with sweep- and fixed-frequency ionosondes, a VLF receiver, energetic and soft particle detectors, an ion mass spectrometer, an electrostatic probe, an electrostatic analyzer, a beacon transmitter, and a cosmic noise experiment. The sounder used two dipole antennas (73 and 18.7 m long). The satellite was spin-stabilized at about 2.9 rpm after antenna deployment. Some control was exercised over the spin rate and attitude by using magnetically induced torques to change the spin rate and to precess the spin axis. A tape recorder with 1-h capacity was included on the satellite. The satellite could be programmed to take recorded observations for four different time periods for each full recording period. The recorder data were dumped only at Ottawa. For non-tape-recorded observations, data for the satellite and subsatellite regions could be acquired and telemetered when the spacecraft was in the line of sight of telemetry stations. The selected telemetry stations were in areas that provided primary data coverage near the 80-deg-W meridian and in areas near Hawaii, Singapore, Australia, the UK, Norway, India, Japan, Antarctica, New Zealand, and Central Africa. NASA support of the ISIS project was terminated on October 1, 1979. A significant amount of experimental data, however, was acquired after this date by the Canadian project team. ISIS 1 operations were terminated in Canada on March 9, 1984. The Radio Research Laboratories (Tokyo, Japan) then requested and received permission to reactivate ISIS 1. Regular ISIS 1 operations were started from Kashima, Japan, in early August 1984. ISIS 1 was deactivated effective January 24, 1990. A data restoration effort began in the late ninties and successfully saved a considerable portion of the high-resolution data before the telemetry tapes were discarted. More information about this effort and access to the data on CDAWeb and nssdcftp can be found at

http://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/space/isis/isis-status.html</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Irvine.Paghis</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/John.E.Jackson</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Larry.H.Brace</PersonID>
        <Role>TeamLeader</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/spacecraft/display.action?id=1969-009A</URL>
        <Description>Information about the ISIS 1 mission</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <ObservatoryGroupID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ISIS</ObservatoryGroupID>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.NearSurface.Ionosphere</ObservatoryRegion>
</Location>
</Observatory>
<Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ISIS1/CEP</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Cylindrical Electrostatic Probes</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The purpose of this experiment was to study the global variations of electron temperature and electron concentration at S/C altitudes during solar maximum, and to study characteristics of the S/C ion sheath. The measurements were made with two cylindrical probes, operating as Langmuir probes. There were a boom probe and an axial probe. The axial probe extended 48.3 cm from the S/C, along the spin axis, and was centered among the four telemetry antennas on the underside of the S/C. This probe was capable of measurements undisturbed by the satellite motion only when the probe preceded the S/C in its motion through the plasma. The boom probe extended horizontally and outward (in S/C frame of reference) from a boom 1 m long, which in turn extended from an upper surface of the S/C at an angle of about 45 deg to the spin axis. This probe provided some observations during each S/C spin cycle that were free of S/C wake effects. The probes consisted of three concentric, electrically isolated, stainless steel tubes. The outer (0.24-cm diam and 23-cm long) tube floated at its own equilibrium potential and served to place the collector well away from the S/C plasma sheath. The middle tube (0.165-cm diam) extending 23 cm outward from the outer tube acted as an electrical guard for the collector. Its electrical potential was controlled. The collector (0.058-cm diam) extended 23 cm outward from the driven guard. During each 2-min sequence, a volt-ampere curve was obtained from the sawtooth voltage (-2 to +10 V) applied to the collector. This was interpreted in electron densities over a range from 1.E2 to 1.5E6 electrons per cc, and temperatures from about 400 to 5.E4 deg K. NSSDC has all the useful data that exist from this investigation.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Larry.H.Brace</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1969-009A&amp;ex=7</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Cylindrical Electrostatic Probes experiment on the ISIS 1 mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>LangmuirProbe</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Cylindrical Electrostatic Probes on ISIS 1</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ISIS1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ISIS1/Ephemeris</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>ISIS1 Positions</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>ISIS1 Ephemeris</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2013-04-09T00:00:00Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>ISIS1 spacecraft positions in various coordinate systems</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Robert.E.McGuire
</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
      </Contact>
        </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Platform</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Spacecraft position</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ISIS1</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ISIS1/SFS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>ISIS1 Swept-Frequency Sounder</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>Topside Sounder</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The ISIS 1 (International Satellites for Ionospheric Studies) Swept-Frequency Sounder measured the
                ionospheric electron density in the altitude range 300 to 3500 km, and provided correlative data for the other
                ISIS 1 experiments, particularly those measuring ionospheric parameters. The ionosonde was a radio transmitter
                that recorded the time delay between a transmitted and returned radio-frequency pulse. A continuum of frequencies
                between 0.1 and 20 MHz was sampled every 19 or 29 s, and one of six selected frequencies was also used for sounding
                for a few seconds during each 19- or 29-s period. In addition to the sweep- and fixed-frequency modes of operation,
                a mixed mode was available in which the transmitter frequency was fixed at one of six possible frequencies while
                the receiver swept. Several virtual-range (delay-time) traces resulting from ground reflections, plasma resonances,
                birefringence of the ionosphere, nonvertical propagation, etc., were normally observed.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/James.H.Whitteker</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1969-009A-01</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Sweep-Frequency Sounder on ISIS 1</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Sounder</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Swept-Frequency Sounder on ISIS 1</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ISIS1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/John.E.Jackson</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Mr. John E. Jackson</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Deceased - formerly at GSFC and NSSDC</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Larry.H.Brace</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Mr. Larry H. Brace</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>GSFC-Code 910.4</OrganizationName>
    <PhoneNumber>+1-301-286-8575</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Irvine.Paghis</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Irvine Paghis</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Deceased - formerly at CRC, Canada</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
      <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/James.H.Whitteker</ResourceID>
      <PersonName>James. H. Whitteker</PersonName>
      <OrganizationName>Communications Research Centre</OrganizationName>
   </Person></Spase>


