<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.0</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Magion-4</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Magion-4</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>1995-039F</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>S2-X</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>Tail Subsatellite S2-X</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>Interball S2-X</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Interball Project is a multi-national effort that consists of four spacecraft: two main spacecraft of the Prognoz series, made in Russia, each with a small subsatellite made in Czechoslovakia. The main objective is to study the physical mechanisms responsible for the transmission of solar wind energy to the magnetosphere, its storage there, and subsequent dissipation in the tail and auroral regions of the magnetosphere, ionosphere, and atmosphere during magnetospheric substorms. A ground-based support group will provide coordinated and simultaneous ground-based data of many types, including observations from auroral and polar cap regions. Interball is an IACG-related mission. Key physical parameters will be generated, and will be available for exchange with other projects. Campaigns for intercomparison with the Wind and Geotail spacecraft are expected. One pair of spacecraft, Tail Probe and its subsatellite S2-X (X for the first letter of the Russian word for ``Tail''), will be launched into the magnetospheric tail. The second pair, Auroral Probe and S2-A (A for ``Auroral''), will have an orbit that crosses the auroral oval to observe the acceleration of auroral particles and the flow of electric currents that connect the magnetospheric tail with the conducting ionosphere. To study the equilibrium tail structure, during about half of each year the Tail Probe pair will cross the main parts of the magnetotail every four days. The Tail Probe, with approximately 30 earth radii apogee, will cross the noon-midnight plane on December 1, so the measurements in the magnetotail will cover the period from October 1995 to February 1996. The Auroral Probe pair will support the Tail Probe pair with auroral region measurements.

Each main spacecraft has more than twenty scientific instruments. The spacecraft is cylindrical, with spin axis toward the sun (within 10 degrees), and with spin period of ~120 s. The electric and magnetic field sensors are on booms connected to the ends of the solar panels.

The subsatellites are small, each with about ten scientific instruments. The spin axis will be directed within 10 degrees of the sun, with a spin period of ~120 s, as with the main spacecraft. The subsatellites also carry gas-jet thrusters for limited control of the orbit. Separation distance will range from hundreds of kilometers to several tens of thousands of kilometers for the Tail Probe pair. Separation distance will range from hundreds of meters to hundreds of kilometers for the Auroral Probe pair. The Tail Probe has two telemetry systems, at up to 32 Kbps in real-time, with a memory mode capacity of 30 Mb in the RTK telemetry system and 120 Mb in the SSNI system. The Auroral Probe has similar capability plus the additional real-time-only STO system, capable of 40 Kbps. Each subsatellite has only the STO real-time telemetry system. For S2-X the rate can be varied from 2--40 kbps.

The Tail Probe has an adapting alert mode while in the memory mode, allowing time resolutions that are the same as in the real-time mode. The aim is to have the highest time resolution available at the thin borders of magnetospheric regions or the sharp borders of some features. In the alert mode (triggered by an on-board computer monitoring plasma and field parameters), the bit rate is increased for plasma, field, and wave measurements. The duration of these alert periods is about 10 minutes, and there can be 5--6 of them during one orbit.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Jan.Merka</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>Magion-4 Spacecraft (IKI page)</Name>
        <URL>http://www.iki.rssi.ru/interball/magion.html</URL>
        <Description>Magion-4 spacecraft description at the Russian Space Research Institute (IKI)</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/spacecraft/display.action?id=1995-039F</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Interball S2-X mission</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <ObservatoryGroupID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Interball-Tail</ObservatoryGroupID>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Heliosphere.NearEarth</ObservatoryRegion>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Magnetosheath</ObservatoryRegion>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere</ObservatoryRegion>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Main</ObservatoryRegion>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Polar</ObservatoryRegion>
</Location>
</Observatory>
<Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Magion-4/MPS-SPS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Energetic Electron and Proton Spectrometers MPS, SPS</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The main objective of the charged particle and plasma experiments in the INTERBALL project is to study the spatial structure of the terrestrial magnetosphere as a global system in various scales and for varying external conditions. The subsatellites (Interball S2-T or S2-X for the Tail subsatellite and S2-A for the Auroral one) are equipped with ion/electron spectrometers similar to those aboard the two main Interball spacecraft.
The MPS spectrometer aboard S2-T is designed to carry out a long-period monitoring of the solar wind parameters and to register the ion fluxes in the bow-shock region when the satellite will be in the appropriate regions. MPS is oriented along the Sun-Earth direction. The SPS spectrometer is designed for estimating the ion energy and angular distributions and for measurements of the electron energy distributions.
The MPS (carried on both S2-A and S2-T) has two channels, and covers the ion energy range 0.2 to 20 keV in 16 steps (variable on command). Energy resolution is less than 10%. It utilizes a 127-degree electrostatic analyzer and channeltron. The angular aperture is 4 degrees both in the plane perpendicular to the main axis and in the plane parallel to it.
The SPS has three channels for ions, one for electrons, and covers the energy range 0.2 to 20 keV in 16 steps (variable on command). Energy resolution is less than 10%. SPS utilizes a double hemispherical analyzer with microchannel plates. The angular aperture in the plane parallel to the main axis is 3 x 45 degrees for ions and 135 degrees for electrons. In the plane perpendicular to the main axis, the aperture is 4 degrees.
The MPS and SPS spectrometers have limited angular characteristics; for this reason the S2-T spacecraft includes the VDP-S instrument (95-039F-08), which is designed for rapid determination of the ion flux direction variations.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Jana.Safrankova</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039F&amp;ex=6</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Energetic Electron and Proton Spectrometers MPS, SPS experiment on the Interball S2-X mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Energetic Electron and Proton Spectrometers MPS, SPS on Interball S2-X</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Magion-4</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Magion-4/KEM3</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Wave Complex, Electric and Magnetic Fields, (KEM-3)</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The wave complex KEM-3 is designed to measure the parameters of electromagnetic waves in the VLF and ULF ranges. It measures one component of the electric field and three components of the magnetic field. The electric antenna is a 1.6 m long dipole made up by two spherical carbon EDS detectors each with a preamplifier. The detectors are fixed at the ends of the folding booms. The magnetic component is measured in two ranges: ULF (1 Hz - 2kHz) and VLF (1 - 50 kHz). The MSU detector of the ULF range is located on the folding arm of the subsatellite. Its antennas are search-coil detectors with low-noise preamplifiers. The same detector is also used for the VLF device. The one-component MSV detector of the VLF range is a search-coil detector with a preamplifier and is located on another folding boom. The output signal of the detectors either is processed by the device electronics for transmitting the wave form by means of analog telemetry, or the amplitude of spectral lines is transmitted by means of digital telemetry. The amplitudes are obtained either in the VLS filter unit or in the step spectrum analyzer SAS.
The frequency range and sensitivity for the various components are as follows. For Ex: 0.1 Hz to 400 kHz, and 5*10^-8 E^(-1/2) (2 kHz). For Bx, 1.0 - 50 kHz, and 10^-5 nT Hz E^(-1/2) (2 kHz). For the components Bx,y,z: 1.0 Hz - 2 kHz, and 3*10^-5 nT Hz E^(-1/2) (100 Hz).</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Pavel.Triska</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039F&amp;ex=1</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Wave Complex, Electric and Magnetic Fields, (KEM-3) experiment on the Interball S2-X mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Antenna</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Wave Complex, Electric and Magnetic Fields, (KEM-3) on Interball S2-X</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Magion-4</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Magion-4/VDPS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Plasma Flow Detector VDP-S</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This instrument consists of four Faraday cup detectors, registering ions and electrons with energies above 170 eV. The detectors are oriented at +/- 45 degrees from the main axis of the spacecraft, and have an angular aperture of 100 degrees. The maximum frequencies used are 1, 2, 4, and 8 Hz (depending on the telemetry mode).</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Georgy.Zastenker</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039F&amp;ex=8</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Plasma Flow Detector VDP-S experiment on the Interball S2-X mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>FaradayCup</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Plasma Flow Detector VDP-S on Interball S2-X</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Magion-4</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Magion-4/Ephemeris</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Magion-4 Orbit</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>Magion-4 Ephemeris</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2009-05-20T21:10:12Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>Interball Tail orbital and attitude modeling</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Victoria.I.Prokhorenko</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Jan.Merka</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>IKI Satellite Situation Center</Name>
        <URL>http://www.iki.rssi.ru/vprokhor/</URL>
        <Description>This page maintains the Situation Analysis for the IKI International Space Missions and its coordination with the Inter-Agency multimission campaigns.</Description>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Platform</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Spacecraft position</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Magion-4</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Magion-4/EMF</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Wave-form Analyzer ULF, Electric &amp; Magnetic</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The ULF instrument is designed for collecting and processing information on three components of magnetic field and one component of electric field. The instrument provides the analog and digital processing of the magnetic and electric field signals through the telemetry system STS. The three-component magnetic sensor is a component of the instrument KEM-3 (95-039F-01). The dynamical range of the instrument (106 dB) is from -76 dB to +30 dB. There are two operational modes: (1) Transmission of all 4 components at 20 or 40 kbits/second with the digitizer frequency of 280 Hz; (2) Transmission of one selected component for the telemetry rates 5 or 1.25 kbits/second with the digitizer frequency 70 Hz.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Frantisek.Jiricek</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039F&amp;ex=3</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Wave-form Analyzer ULF, Electric &amp; Magnetic experiment on the Interball S2-X mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>WaveformReceiver</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Wave-form Analyzer ULF, Electric &amp; Magnetic on Interball S2-X</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Magion-4</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Magion-4/RF</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Soft Solar X-ray Photometer RF</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The X-ray photometer RF is designed to measure the solar X-ray radiation in the soft spectral range. In addition to continuous monitoring of the solar radiation in the X-ray range, the instrument can be used as an indicator for automatic switching-on of the scientific instrumentation for registering the processes of the active solar events, assuming a change in the solar X-ray radiation as a precursor of these phenomena. The photometer is oriented along the -Z-axis of the subsatellite, i.e. toward the Sun. The photometer consists of two units: the detector unit and electronics unit. The photometer is the scintillating detector with an aluminium foil in front of it to prevent penetration of soft particles and X-rays. The output signal is passed to the two-channel amplitude analyzer where it is selected in two ranges: 10-15 keV and 15-60 keV. The impulses from the channels with a fixed amplitude are transferred to the electronics unit where they are accumulated during 0.8 s (time of one exposure step). The maximum capacity of the detector is 183441 impulses/0.8 second, so for higher flux intensity (which is hardly probable) the detector data are not valid.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Frantisek.Farnik</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039F&amp;ex=7</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Soft Solar X-ray Photometer RF experiment on the Interball S2-X mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Photometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Soft Solar X-ray Photometer RF on Interball S2-X</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Magion-4</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Magion-4/LSP</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Two-component Current Langmuir Slit Probe, LSP</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Langmuire Slit Probe is used to measure two components of the current density in space. The input signal frequency range is 0.3 Hz to 50 kHz. The output 1 has a linear characteristic over the whole frequency range; in output 2 the characteristic is proportional to the frequency in the range 15 to 1000 Hz.
The noise threshold normalized to the input is 10^-13 A/cm^2. The dynamical range of the input signal variations is 80 dB for the first output. The dynamical range is measured from the noise level for a given frequency band to the maximum signal on the detector input. The gain is 70 +/- 10 for output 1 and 3500 +/- 500 for output 2. To calculate the transmission coefficient Ct for a parameter under measurement one should multiply these values by 42.45 V m/kA cm^2.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Sergey.Savin</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039F&amp;ex=9</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Two-component Current Langmuir Slit Probe, LSP experiment on the Interball S2-X mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>LangmuirProbe</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Two-component Current Langmuir Slit Probe, LSP on Interball S2-X</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Magion-4</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Magion-4/SAS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Electric and Magnetic Spectrum Analyzer SAS</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The SAS instrument consists of two SFA analyzers plus a time transformer and analog telemetry unit. The instrument is designed as the well-known step-frequency analyzer with two intermediate frequences: 465 kHz and 5 kHz.
The signals under analysis are as follows: (1) electric component, 1-400 kHz (32-2000 Hz); (2) magnetic component, 400 Hz - 20 kHz; (3) magnetic component, 32-2000 Hz (Bx, By, Bz selected through the multiplexer); (4) current density XZ, 0.4-20 kHz; (5) current density YZ, 0.4-20 kHz; (6) analog frequency range, 1-480 Hz divided into 8 subranges.
The analog output to telemetry is wide-band of 60 kHz.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/J.Juchniewicz</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039F&amp;ex=2</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Electric and Magnetic Spectrum Analyzer SAS experiment on the Interball S2-X mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Unspecified</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Electric and Magnetic Spectrum Analyzer SAS on Interball S2-X</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Magion-4</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Magion-4/MAG</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Three-Component Magnetometer SG-R8</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This magnetometer is designed for studying space and time variations of the magnetic field intensity. In addition, it enables one to determine the attitude of the subsatellite with respect to the magnetic field vector. SG-R8 is a triaxial flux-gate magnetometer with automatic switching of sensitivity among the four ranges (+/-) 65536, 8192, 1024, and 128 nT. Resolutions in these ranges are, respectively, 8 nT, 1 nT, 0.125 nT, and 15.6 pT.
The data from the magnetometer pass through a digital converter, which has 13 bits and the sign. Its operation is synchronized with the STS telemetry system. The main output of the magnetometer is digital. For emergency situations the device has one analog output, from which one can obtain the Hx , Hy , and Hz data with lower accuracy (8 bits). The detector is fixed at the top of a rigid short boom, which enables one to determine precisely the attitude of the magnetometer axes with respect to the construction axes of the subsatellite.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/M.Chobanu</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039F&amp;ex=4</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Three-Component Magnetometer SG-R8 experiment on the Interball S2-X mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Three-Component Magnetometer SG-R8 on Interball S2-X</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Magion-4</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Magion-4/DOKS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Energetic Electron and Proton Spectrometer DOK-S</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The DOK-S spectrometer is designed to measure the energetic spectrum and angular distribution of electrons in the energy range 20-180 keV and of ions in the range 20-1300 keV.
In the main operational mode the range of measurements includes 8 energy channels. The instrument consists of two units: detector unit and electronics unit. Two pairs of silicon detectors are used; before one of them in each pair a magnetic filter is placed. The filter deflects from the field of view the electrons with energies lower than 600 keV. A mylar foil is placed before the other detector in each pair to capture the protons with energies up to 400 keV.
The electronics unit is based on the M80C85 processor, the amplified signals are accumulated in 8 energy channels during 150 ms and then are transformed to digital and analog forms for the instrument data analysis.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Karel.Kudela</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039F&amp;ex=5</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Energetic Electron and Proton Spectrometer DOK-S experiment on the Interball S2-X mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Energetic Electron and Proton Spectrometer DOK-S on Interball S2-X</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Magion-4</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Jana.Safrankova</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Jana Safrankova</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Charles University</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Frantisek.Jiricek</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Frantisek Jiricek</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Czech Academy of Sciences</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/J.Juchniewicz</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. J. Juchniewicz</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Polish Academy of Sciences</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Sergey.Savin</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Sergey Savin</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Russian Academy of Sciences</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Karel.Kudela</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Mr. Karel Kudela</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Slovak Academy of Sciences</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Frantisek.Farnik</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Frantisek Farnik</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Czech Academy of Sciences</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Georgy.Zastenker</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Georgy Zastenker</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Academy of Sciences</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Jan.Merka</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Jan Merka</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>NASA Goddard Space Flight Center</OrganizationName>
    <Address>Code 672, Greenbelt, MD 20771, USA</Address>
    <Email>jan.merka@nasa.gov</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+1 301 286 8751</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Pavel.Triska</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Pavel Triska</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Czech Academy of Sciences</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Victoria.I.Prokhorenko</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Victoria I. Prokhorenko</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Space Research Institute</OrganizationName>
    <Address>Space Research Institute, Russian Academy of Sciences, ul. Profsouznaya, 84/32, Moscow, 117997, RUSSIA</Address>
    <Email>vprokhor@iki.rssi.ru</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+7(095) 9361258</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/M.Chobanu</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. M. Chobanu</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Academy of Sciences of Romania</OrganizationName>
  </Person></Spase>


