<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_3_1.xsd">
   <Version>2.3.1</Version>
   <Observatory>
      <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/GOES/5</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>GOES 5</ResourceName>
         <AlternateName>1981-049A</AlternateName>
         <AlternateName>GOES-E</AlternateName>
         <ReleaseDate>2019-07-01T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
         <Description>GOES 5 was the seventh in a series of NASA-developed, NOAA-operated, geosynchronous, and operational spacecraft. The spin-stabilized spacecraft was stationed at 75° W, and carried (1) an infrared spin-scan radiometer, VISSR, atmospheric sounder, VAS, to provide high-quality day/night cloudcover data, to take radiance-derived temperatures of the earth/atmosphere system, and to determine atmospheric temperature and water vapor content at various levels, (2) a meteorological data collection and transmission system to relay processed data from central weather facilities to APT-equipped regional stations and to collect and retransmit data from remotely located earth-based platforms, and (3) a space environment monitor, SEM, system to measure proton, electron, and solar X-ray fluxes and magnetic fields. The cylindrically shaped spacecraft measured 190.5 cm in diameter and 230 cm in length, exclusive of a magnetometer that extended an additional 83 cm beyond the cylindrical shell. The primary structural members were a honeycombed equipment shelf and thrust tube. The VISSR telescope was mounted on the equipment shelf and viewed the earth through a special aperture in the side of the spacecraft. A support structure extended radially from the thrust tube and was affixed to the solar panels, which formed the outer walls of the spacecraft to provide the primary source of electrical power. Located in the annulus-shaped space between the thrust tube and the solar panels were stationkeeping and dynamics control equipment, batteries, and most of the SEM equipment. Proper spacecraft attitude and spin rate (approximately 100 rpm) were maintained by two separate sets of jet thrusters mounted around the spacecraft equator and activated by ground command. The spacecraft used both UHF-band and S-band frequencies in its telemetry and command subsystem. A low-power VHF transponder provided telemetry and command during launch and then served as a backup for the primary subsystem once the spacecraft had attained synchronous orbit. On July 30, 1984, GOES 5 VAS experienced a failure, thus NOAA was prompted to reactivate GOES 1 and 4, to relocate GOES 6 to a more central 98° W position, and to reactivate GOES 1 and GOES 4 for the acquisition and relay of VISSR information, respectively, from the western United States.</Description>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/William.E.Shenk</PersonID>
            <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
         </Contact>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>NSSDC Master Catalog</Name>
            <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/spacecraft/display.action?id=1981-049A</URL>
            <Description>Information about the GOES 5 mission</Description>
         </InformationURL>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>Earth Observation Resources Webpage on GOES</Name>
            <URL>https://earth.esa.int/web/eoportal/satellite-missions/g/goes-2nd-generation</URL>
            <Description>Detailed information about GOES Series</Description>
         </InformationURL>
         <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/GOES5</PriorID>
      </ResourceHeader>
      <Location>
         <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Main</ObservatoryRegion>
      </Location>
      <OperatingSpan>
         <StartDate>1981-05-22T00:00:00Z</StartDate>
         <StopDate>1984-07-30T23:59:59</StopDate>
         <Note>Useful operating span</Note>
      </OperatingSpan>
   </Observatory>
<Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/GOES/5/EPS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Energetic Particle Sensor</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-07-02T15:25:42Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The energetic particle monitor consisted of three detector assemblies, each covering limited regions of the overall energy spectrum. The first two detector assemblies monitored protons in seven energy ranges between 0.8 and 500 MeV and alpha particles in six energy ranges from 4 to &gt;400 MeV. There was also one channel for the measurement of electrons in the energy range above 500 keV. The third detector, high energy proton and alpha detector (HEPAD), monitored protons in four energy ranges above 370 MeV and alpha particles in two energy ranges above 640 MeV/nucleon. In all, there were 25 channels of data, each channel sampling at a slow rate of once in a few seconds, or once in a few minutes.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Herbert.H.Sauer</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Terry.Onsager</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1981-049A-02</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Energetic Particle Monitor experiment on the GOES 5 mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>Data Provider README</Name>
        <URL>https://satdat.ngdc.noaa.gov/sem/goes/goes_docs/avg/readme.txt</URL>
        <Description>Caveats and more information about data from this instrument.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/GOES5/GOES/EPS</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Energetic Particle Monitor on GOES 5</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/GOES/5</ObservatoryID>
    <Caveats>From http://goes.ngdc.noaa.gov/data/avg/readme.txt:

Energetic Particle Sensor (EPS)

Solid-state detectors with pulse-height discrimination measure proton, ?-
particle, and electron fluxes.  E1 and I1 channels are responding primarily to
trapped outer-zone particles.  The I2 channel may occasionally respond to
trapped particles during magnetically disturbed conditions.  The remaining
proton integrals measure fluxes originating outside the magnetosphere -- from
the Sun or the heart of the Galaxy.

Users of GOES particle data should be aware that significant secondary responses
may exist in the particle data, i.e. responses from other particles and energies
and from directions outside the nominal detector entrance aperture.  The
integrated protons displayed in these plots have been partially corrected for
these effects.

Ion Data Quality

Users of GOES particle data should be aware that significant secondary responses
may exist in the particle data, i.e. responses from other particles and energies
and from directions outside the nominal detector entrance aperture. A
description of the algorithm that partially corrects for these effects is
described below.

Electron Data Quality

The Electron detector responds significantly to protons above 32 MeV; therefore,
electron data are contaminated when a proton event is in progress. Beginning
with GOES-8 the electron data have had a preliminary correction applied,
however, even these data are not to be considered research quality at this time.

The GOES-5 electron channel is noisy from 1986 onwards and readings are a
possible factor of 2 high. One component of the GOES-6 particle detector system
has had radiation damage since 1986 that reduced its counting efficiency
progressively. At present the E1 and P4 channels derived from this component
record at only a few percent of their proper rates. In 1991 the telescope
component of the GOES-7 energetic particle detector system experienced episodes
of malfunction (noise). The first period began at 0330 UT, October 18, 1991 and
extended to November 5, 1991. The detector was commanded off for 12 hours. At
turn-on the detector appeared to have recovered, but failed again on November
11, with a rerecovery on November 12 after a second turn-off of three hours. The
detector has since operated normally. The noise periods may be identified by
unusually high rates being shown by the P1 channel and the derived &gt; 1 MeV
integral channel. Currently, the GOES-7 Energetic Particle Sensor is left turned
off for 4 hours after eclipse to minimize bad data.
</Caveats>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/GOES/5/XRS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Solar X-ray Monitor</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The X-ray monitor consisted of two ion chambers, mounted behind a slim rectangular field-of-view (48 deg x 3 deg) collimator made of lead-lined aluminum. The chamber for the lower wavelength band of 0.05 to 0.40 nanometer was filled with Xe-He mixture with an entry aperture made of 20 mil Be sheet. For the other band, 0.1-0.8 nm, the gas was Ar-He mixture and the aperture was a 2 mil Be. The threshold sensitivities were 1.0E-12 J per sq cm per s for the lower wavelength band, and 1.0E-11 J per sq cm per s for the higher band; each had a dynamic range of four decades. Entry of charged particle were prevented by the strong magnetic field located at the chamber windows.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Howard.A.Garcia</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1981-049A-03</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Solar X-ray Monitor experiment on the GOES 5 mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>Data Provider README</Name>
        <URL>https://satdat.ngdc.noaa.gov/sem/goes/goes_docs/avg/readme.txt</URL>
        <Description>Caveats and more information about data from this instrument.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/GOES5/XRS</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>IonChamber</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Solar X-ray Monitor on GOES 5</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/GOES/5</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/GOES/5/MAG</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Biaxial Fluxgate Magnetometer</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The spinning twin-fluxgate magnetometer, located at a few meters away from the spacecraft was designed to provide the orthogonal components of the magnetic field: Hp was parallel to the spin axis that was held nearly in the direction of Earth's axis, He was directed toward Earth center, and Hn pointed eastward. The magnetometer had a range of +/- 400 nT (without saturation) and a resolution of 0.1 nT over a range of +/- 50 nT. The sensitivity of the magnetometer was about 0.2 nT. The instrument and its electronics were carried on board GOES-4,-5,-6,and -7, without significant changes. Since 9 September, 91, only the Hp component is available, since the Earth-limb locator data that are necessary to obtain the transverse components have remained uncertain.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Howard.J.Singer</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1983-049A-04</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Biaxial Fluxgate Magnetometer experiment on the GOES 5 mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>Data Provider README</Name>
        <URL>https://satdat.ngdc.noaa.gov/sem/goes/goes_docs/avg/readme.txt</URL>
        <Description>Caveats and more information about data from this instrument.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/GOES5/MAG</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Biaxial Fluxgate Magnetometer on GOES 5</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/GOES/5</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/GOES/5/SEM</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Space Environment Monitor (SEM)</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2011-06-03T20:40:26Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Space Environment Monitor Subsystem (SEM) measures in situ the effect of the sun on the near-earth solar-terrestrial electromagnetic environment on a real-time basis. This information is provided to the Space Environment Services Center where it is used for "near-space weather" reports. These reports, which include solar activity, are important to the operators of communication, navigation, electric power transmission systems, and satellites.
The SEM consists of four instruments. The Energetic Particle Sensor (EP8,formerly called EPS) makes flux measurements of protons in the 0.8 to 500 MeV range. The High Energy Proton and Alpha Detector (HEPAD) monitors protons in four energy ranges above 350 MeV and alpha particles in two energy ranges above 640 MeV/nucleon. The solar X-Ray Sensor permits real-time determination of the solar x-ray emission in two spectral bands: 0.5-5 angstroms and 1-8 angstroms. The Magnetic Field Sensor (MFS) allows for the real-time determination of the magnitude and orientation of the magnetic field. Data will be telemetered twice a second for magnetic fields having a magnitude of +/- 1000 nanotesla (nT).</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Ronald.D.Zwickl</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Terry.Onsager</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/GOES5/SEM</PriorID>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InstrumentType>IonChamber</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Space Environment Monitor (SEM) on GOES 5</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/GOES/5</ObservatoryID>
    <Caveats>From http://goes.ngdc.noaa.gov/data/avg/readme.txt: Electron Data Quality

The Electron detector responds significantly to protons above 32 MeV; therefore, 
electron data are contaminated when a proton event is in progress. Beginning 
with GOES-8 the electron data have had a preliminary correction applied, 
however, even these data are not to be considered research quality at this time.

The GOES-5 electron channel is noisy from 1986 onwards and readings are a 
possible factor of 2 high. One component of the GOES-6 particle detector system 
has had radiation damage since 1986 that reduced its counting efficiency 
progressively. At present the E1 and P4 channels derived from this component 
record at only a few percent of their proper rates. In 1991 the telescope 
component of the GOES-7 energetic particle detector system experienced episodes 
of malfunction (noise). The first period began at 0330 UT, October 18, 1991 and 
extended to November 5, 1991. The detector was commanded off for 12 hours. At 
turn-on the detector appeared to have recovered, but failed again on November 
11, with a rerecovery on November 12 after a second turn-off of three hours. The 
detector has since operated normally. The noise periods may be identified by 
unusually high rates being shown by the P1 channel and the derived &gt; 1 MeV 
integral channel. Currently, the GOES-7 Energetic Particle Sensor is left turned 
off for 4 hours after eclipse to minimize bad data.
</Caveats>
  </Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/GOES/5/Ephemeris</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>GOES 5 Positions</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>GOES 5 Ephemeris</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2011-10-04T18:17:00Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>GOES 5 spacecraft position.</Description>
      <Acknowledgement>NOAA</Acknowledgement>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Howard.J.Singer</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Platform</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Spacecraft position</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/GOES/5</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Ronald.D.Zwickl</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Ronald D. Zwickl</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>NOAA Environmental Research Labs</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Herbert.H.Sauer</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Herbert H. Sauer</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>NOAA Environmental Research Labs</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Howard.A.Garcia</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Mr. Howard A. Garcia</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>NOAA Space Weather Prediction Center</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/William.E.Shenk</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Mr. William E. Shenk</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Deceased - formerly at GSFC-Code 912</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
        <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Terry.Onsager</ResourceID>
        <PersonName>Terry Onsager</PersonName>
        <OrganizationName>Space Weather Prediction Center</OrganizationName>
        <Address>Space Weather Prediction Center, W/NP9 325 Broadway, Boulder CO 80305</Address>
        <Email>Terry.Onsager@noaa.gov</Email>
        <PhoneNumber>303-497-5713</PhoneNumber>
    </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Howard.J.Singer</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Howard J. Singer</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>NOAA Space Weather Prediction Center</OrganizationName>
    <Address>Space Weather Prediction Center, W/NP9 325 Broadway, Boulder CO 80305</Address>
    <Email>Howard.Singer@noaa.gov</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>303-497-6959</PhoneNumber>
  </Person></Spase>


