<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.0</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ACE</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>ACE</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>Advanced Composition Explorer</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>1997-045A</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>Explorer 71</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The objective of the Advanced Composition Explorer (ACE) is to collect observations of particles of solar, interplanetary, interstellar, and galactic origins, spanning the energy range from that of KeV solar wind ions to galactic cosmic ray nuclei up to 600 MeV/nucleon. Definitive studies will be made of the abundances of essentially all isotopes from H to Zn (Z = 1-30), with exploratory isotope studies extending to Zr (Z = 40). The ACE payload includes six high resolution spectrometers, each designed to provide the optimum charge, mass, or charge-state resolution in its particular energy range. Each spectrometer has a geometry factor optimized for the expected flux levels, so as to provide a collecting power greater by a factor of 10-1000 times that of previous or planned experiments. The payload also includes three additional instruments of standard design to monitor energetic electrons, H and He ions, and a magnetometer. The ACE spacecraft is based on the design of the Charge Composition Explorer, built at JHU/APL for the Active Magnetospheric Particle Tracer Explorer (AMPTE) program. The spacecraft spin axis is pointed towards the Sun to within +/- 20 degrees, and it occupies a halo orbit about the L1 Earth-Sun libration point. Powered by solar cells, the spacecraft has a design life of at least five years, and it returns data in daily tape recorder dumps, received through NASA JPL's Deep Space Network and initially processed at NASA-GSFC. The average data telemetry rate is 6.7 Kbs.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Edward.C.Stone.Jr</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>ACE Home Page</Name>
        <URL>http://www.srl.caltech.edu/ACE/</URL>
        <Description>ACE mission home page at Caltech with data download</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/spacecraft/display.action?id=1997-045A</URL>
        <Description>Information about the ACE mission</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://vspo/observatory/2</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Heliosphere.NearEarth</ObservatoryRegion>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Heliosphere.Inner</ObservatoryRegion>
</Location>
</Observatory>
<Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ACE/SWICS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Solar Wind Ion Composition Spectrometer (SWICS)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>SWICS</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Solar Wind Ion Charge Spectrometer (SWICS) determines elemental and ionic-charge composition, temperatures, and mean speeds of all major solar wind ions from H through Fe at solar wind speeds ranging from a minimum of 145 km/s to a maximum of 1532 km/s for Fe IX. Ions in the full energy/charge range of 0.11 keV/Q to 66.7 keV/Q are measured every 13 minutes. The range of total ion energies measured is about 35 to 600 keV, and the typical mass resolution is less than or equal to 3.5 percent. SWICS combines an electrostatic analyzer with post-acceleration, time-of-flight (TOF) measurement, and energy measurement. Ions enter the electrostatic deflection analyzer through a large area multi-slit collimator, which serves as a filter for ions in a given energy-per-charge interval and allows the ions to pass into the TOF vs energy system. Field of view of the entry aperture is 4 deg. x 69 deg.; geometric factors range from 0.002 sq.cm.-sr for isotropic incidence to 0.009 sq.cm for directional beams. Ions are then post-accelerated by a 30 kV potential drop before passing through a thin foil and into a solid state detector for measurement of residual energy. Secondary electrons from the foil and the energy detector are detected by multichannel plates (MCP) which respectively generate start and stop signals for the TOF measurement. A smaller deflection analyzer region is also included to monitor solar wind protons, helium, and heavier ions. These ions are post-accelerated and counted by a single solid-state detector at two energy threshold levels corresponding to protons and heavies. Stepping of this latter deflection analyzer through its range provides energy-per-charge spectra and allows determination of bulk speed, temperature, and density of the solar wind. The SWICS experiment manager is Prof. G. Gloeckler of the University of Maryland.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/George.Gloeckler</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1997-045A-02</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Solar Wind Ion Composition Spectrometer (SWICS) experiment on the ACE mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Space Science Reviews Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-94-011-4762-0_18</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Solar Wind Ion Composition Spectrometer (SWICS) and Solar Wind Ion Mass Spectrometer (SWIMS)on the ACE mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>ElectrostaticAnalyser</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Solar Wind Ion Composition Spectrometer (SWICS) on ACE</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ACE</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ACE/SWEPAM</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>ACE Solar Wind Electron, Proton and Alpha Monitor (SWEPAM)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>ACE SWEPAM</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2021-07-20T13:41:27Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Solar Wind Electron, Proton, and Alpha Monitor (SWEPAM) instrument sensors measure solar wind electrons at 1 - 900 eV energy and ions at 0.26 - 35 keV. The instrument consists of separate electron and ion analyzers originally built as spares for the Ulysses mission. The two sensors both utilizes curved-plate electrostatic analyzers (ESAs) consisting of spherical sections cut into sectors. Biased channel electron multipliers (CEMS) are spaced along the exit apertures of the ESAs for ion and electron detection. Different CEMs sample different portions of the fan-shaped fields of view. The ion sensor consists of a 105-degree bending angle ESA with an average radius of 100 mm and a plate spacing of 2.84 mm. Sixteen CEMs contiguously spaced along the exit gap of the ESA give about 5-degree polar angular resolution over the approximately 70-degree opening angle of the acceptance fan. The electron sensor consists of a 120-degree bending angle ESA with an average radius of 41.9 mm and a plate spacing of 3.5 mm. Seven large-funnel CEMs along the exit gap give about 20-degree angular resolution over a 160-degree fan angle. The sensor geometric factors are 0.002 cm2-sr for isotropic response and 0.009 cm2 for unidirectional. Energy resolution is five percent for ions and twelve percent for electrons. SWEPAM data consists of ion and electron rates collected at each energy/charge (E/Q) step, polar lock direction, and azimuthal spin direction. A single spacecraft spin period of 12 seconds is sufficient for accumulation of count matricies to fully calculate the electron and ion distribution functions from which bulk moments (solar wind speed, density, temperature) can be calculated by ground data processing. Accumulated counts will actually be summed over one-minute intervals for increased statistical accuracy and for reduction of telemetry requirements. Limited data from single spins will be provided for timing of the passage of transient solar wind structures.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <!-- David McComas -->
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/David.J.McComas</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <!-- R. Skoug -->
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Ruth.Skoug</PersonID>
        <Role>TechnicalContact</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>SWEPAM home page at LANL</Name>
        <URL>https://www.swepam.lanl.gov/</URL>
        <Description>Information about the SWEPAM instrument, with links to data and other documentation</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1997-045A-07</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Solar Wind Electron, Proton and Alpha Monitor (SWEPAM) experiment on the ACE mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Space Science Reviews Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-94-011-4762-0_20</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Solar Wind Electron, Proton, and Alpha Monitor (SWEPAM) instrument on the ACE mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/instrument/1997-045A-07</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>ElectrostaticAnalyser</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Solar Wind Electron, Proton and Alpha Monitor (SWEPAM) on ACE</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ACE</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ACE/EPAM</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>ACE Electron Proton Alpha Monitor</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>ACE EPAM</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>1997-045A-08</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>EPAM is composed of five telescope apertures of three different types.
      Two Low Energy Foil Spectrometers (LEFS) measure the flux and direction of electrons above 30 keV (geometry factor = 0.397 cm^2 sr),
      two Low Energy Magnetic Spectrometers (LEMS) measure the flux and direction of ions greater than 50 keV (geometry factor = 0.48 cm^2 sr),
      and the Composition Aperture (CA) measures the elemental composition of the ions (geometry factor = 0.24 cm^2 sr).
      The telescopes use the spin of the spacecraft to sweep the full sky. Solid-state detectors are used to measure the energy and composition of the incoming particles.
</Description>
      <Contact>
        <!-- Dennis Haggerty -->
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Dennis.Haggerty</PersonID>
        <Role>TechnicalContact</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <!-- Robert Gold -->
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Robert.E.Gold</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>Instrument description</Name>
        <URL>http://sd-www.jhuapl.edu/ACE/EPAM/</URL>
        <Description>Description of the ACE EPAM instrument design and instrument characteristics, with links to data and other documentation</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1997-045A-08</URL>
        <Description>Information about the EPAM experiment on the ACE mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Space Science Reviews Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://link.springer.com/article/10.1023/A:1005088115759</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Electron Proton Alpha Monitor experiment on the ACE mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/instrument/1997-045A-08</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Electron Proton and Alpha Monitor (EPAM) on ACE</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ACE</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ACE/Ephemeris</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>ACE Positions</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>ACE Ephemeris</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2009-05-20T21:10:13Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>ACE spacecraft positions</Description>
      <Contact>
        <!-- Jan Merka -->
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Jan.Merka</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
      </Contact>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Platform</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Spacecraft position</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ACE</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ACE/CRIS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Cosmic Ray Isotope Spectrometer (CRIS)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>CRIS</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Cosmic Ray Isotope Spectrometer (CRIS) provides measurements with significant statistics of galactic cosmic ray nuclei from He to Zn (Z=2 to 30) at energies of 100 to 600 MeV/nucleon. CRIS makes more exploratory measurements of ultra-heavy nuclei from Ga (Z=31) to Zr (Z=40). The detector system consists of a Scintillating Optical Fiber Telescope (SOFT) hodoscope and four identical stacks of large-area silicon solid-state detectors. SOFT uses the optical fiber scintillation to provide position information in three x-y planes (H1, H2, H3) for trajectory measurement, while also providing a trigger counter (T) with two signals from the x-trigger and y-trigger fibers for the CRIS coincidence logic. Each detector stack includes eight four-inch diameter lithium-drifted (LiD) silicon solid-state detectors (SSD), designated as E1 to E8. Detectors E1 - E3 are 3-mm thick, while E3 - E8 are 6-mm thick and each consisting of a pair of 3-mm detectors. All detectors except E9 are pulse-height analyzed. Detectors E2 - E8 have a central active area surrounded by an annular integral guard ring used in anti-coincidence to elimiate side-penetrating events. Penetration of the entire stack is signaled by an E9 detector trigger. The total geometric factor for all four stacks is about 200 cm2-sr, dependent on energy, with a 45-degree conical (half-angle) field of view. Mass resolution for isotope analysis is at or below 0.25 amu. Most of the CRIS telemetry is devoted to event data, about 224 bits per analyzed event, while only 16 bps are needed for rate and housekeeping data. Since all analyzed events cannot be recorded during large solar flare events, a priority system ensures that the most significant events are selected for readout. In order of descending priority these are stopping heavy nuclei (Z &gt; 2), penetrating heavies, stopping hydrogen and helium, and penetrating hydrogen and helium. Under all interplanetary conditions CRIS can then record most accumulated heavy nuclei events.
</Description>
      <Contact>
        <!-- Alan Cummings -->
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Alan.C.Cummings</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <!-- Richard Mewaldt -->
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Richard.A.Mewaldt</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Richard.Leske</PersonID>
        <Role>TechnicalContact</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>Instrument description</Name>
        <URL>http://www.srl.caltech.edu/ACE/CRIS_SIS/cris.html</URL>
        <Description>Description of the ACE CRIS instrument, with links to data</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1997-045A-06</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Cosmic Ray Isotope Spectrometer (CRIS) experiment on the ACE mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Space Science Reviews Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://link.springer.com/article/10.1023/A:1005075813033</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Cosmic Ray Isotope Spectrometer (CRIS) experiment on the ACE mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/instrument/1997-045A-06</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>ParticleDetector</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Cosmic Ray Isotope Spectrometer (CRIS) on ACE</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ACE</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ACE/SEPICA</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Solar Energetic Particle Ionic Charge Analyzer (SEPICA)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>SEPICA</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Solar Energetic Particle Ionic Charge Analyzer (SEPICA) is designed to measure ionic charge state, kinetic energy, and nuclear charge of energetic ions at energies above 0.2 MeV/nucleon. Principal science goals include measurement of such ions from solar flares, coronal and interplanetary shocks, co-rotating interaction regions, and the solar wind termination shock, the latter being the probable source of the anomalous cosmic ray component. The SEPICA sensors combine electrostatic deflection of incoming ions in a collimator analyzer with a differential energy loss (dE/dx) vs. residual energy telescope. Energetic ions entering the multi-split collimator, which focuses the ions on a line in the detector plane, are electrostatically deflected between a set of electrode plates at voltage potentials up to 30 kV. The amount of deflection, inversely proportional to energy per charge, is measured in a multi-wire thin-window proportional counter. This counter is also used to measure the dE/dx of the ion. Residual energy of the ion is then determined in a solid-state detector behind the proportional counter. A CsI anticoincidence scintillator behind the solid state detector is used to supress background events from penetrating high energy particles. The SEPICA instrument array consists of three pairs of telescopes with collimators, electrostatic deflection electrodes, proportional counters, and solid state detectors. Each pair shares a high-voltage deflection electrode. Two of the pairs have collimators with larger geometric factor for higher sensitivity to smaller solar energetic particle (SEP) events. The third pair uses a fine collimator to reduce the geometric factor for improved charge state resolution. The field of view (FOV) of each telescope is 24 deg. x 50 deg. with 0.36 sq.cm.-sr for the large geometric factor sensors and 0.06 sq.cm.sr for those with the fine collimator. Charge resolution is about 10 percent with the fine collimator. The SEPICA data rate of 604 bps includes readout of 46 bits/events for 12 pulse height analysis (PHA) events/s, sectored (8) counting rates for He and Z&gt;2 ions at 60-sec resolution, 64 PHA matrix rates at 300-sec resolution, and various housekeeping data. The SEPICA experiment manager is Dr. Eberhard Mobius of the University of New Hampshire.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Eberhard.S.Moebius</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1997-045A-04</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Solar Energetic Particle Ionic Charge Analyzer (SEPICA) experiment on the ACE mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Space Science Reviews Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://link.springer.com/article/10.1023/A:1005084014850</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Solar Energetic Particle Ionic Charge Analyzer (SEPICA) experiment on the ACE mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>ElectrostaticAnalyser</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Solar Energetic Particle Ionic Charge Analyzer (SEPICA) on ACE</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ACE</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ACE/MAG</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>ACE Magnetic Field Instrument</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>ACE Magnetometer</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>ACE MAG</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>ACE MFI</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>1997-045A-09</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The ACE Magnetometer (MAG) experiment consists of two triaxial fluxgate magnetometers mounted remotely on booms extending beyond the spacecraft solar panels at four meters from the spacecraft center. Each identical sensor (M1, M2) has a wide dynamic range of sensitivity at +- 0.004 to +- 65536 nT and measures the three vector components of the magnetic field. Usage of twin magnetometer sensors for measurements of weak interplanetary magnetic fields is a proven approach based on experience from many past space missions. The MAG sensors were originally built as spares for the MFI instrument on the Wind spacecraft and have been given minor modifications for inclusion on ACE. Readout of MAG data includes three data types: (1) average magnetic field vectors from the primary and secondary sensors, (2) "Snap-Shot Memory" data, and (3) Fast Fourier Transform (FFT) data. The average vector readout includes 216 bps corresponding to six vectors per second. These vector readouts can be split between M1 and M2 in the ratios of 3:3, 5:1, or 6:0. The "Snap-Shot Memory" stores field vectors at the maximum sampling rate of 30 vectors per second and is read out at 48 bps. The FFT readout includes 17 seconds accumulation of vector data transformed into spectral matrices of the components and total magnitude at a transmission rate of 32 bps. Prof. Norman F. Ness of the Bartol Research Institute at the University of Delaware is the MAG Experiment Manager.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <!-- N. Ness -->
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Norman.F.Ness</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <!-- C. Smith -->
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Charles.W.Smith</PersonID>
        <Role>TechnicalContact</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>Instrument description</Name>
        <URL>http://www.ssg.sr.unh.edu/mag/ACE.html</URL>
        <Description>Description of the ACE magnetometer design and instrument characteristics, with links to data and other documentation</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1997-045A-09</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Magnetometer (MAG) experiment on the ACE mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Space Science Reviews Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://link.springer.com/article/10.1023/A:1005092216668</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the triaxial fluxgate magnetometer on the ACE mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/instrument/1997-045A-09</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Magnetometer (MAG) on ACE</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ACE</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ACE/ULEIS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Ultra-Low Energy Isotope Spectrometer (ULEIS)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>ULEIS</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Ultra Low Energy Isotope Spectrometer (ULEIS) measures energetic ion fluxes over the charge range
   from He through Ni from about 20 keV/nucleon to 10 MeV/nucleon with mass resolution less than or equal to 0.3 amu.
   Ultra-heavy species (above Ni) are also measured in a limited energy range near 0.5 MeV/nucleon. The ULEIS telescope
   is a time-of-flight (TOF) mass spectrometer which identifies ions by TOF and by residual kinetic energy E of
   particles which enter the 24 deg. x 20 deg. aperture and stop in one of an array of silicon solid state detectors.
   The geometric factor is about one sq.cm.-sr. The TOF measurement is determined by start and stop signals from
   microchannel plate (MCP) assemblies detecting secondary electrons emitted from incident ion passage through a
   thin entrance foil and other such foils within the telescope. In order to prevent electronic pile-up during intense
   flux periods, a mechanical shutter ('iris') slides partially closed under on-board control dependent on the start
   MCP singles counting rate. The iris can decrease the ULEIS geometric factor by up to a factor of 100 during the
   most intense events. Full analysis of individual ions requires 128 bits/event for up to six events per second. Two
   types of rate data are included: sectored singles rates for each detector with 8 sectors for 18 rates at 12
   bits/rate in compressed format; sectored counts of 5 particle species in 20 energy ranges and 8 sectors at 12
   bits/s (compressed). These rate data are read out every 60 seconds at 189 b/s. Housekeeping and other
   miscellaneous data require 43 b/s, the total data rate being about 1 kbps. The ULEIS experiment manager
   is Dr. Robert E. Gold of the Applied Physics Laboratory of Johns Hopkins University.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Robert.E.Gold</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1997-045A-03</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Ultra-Low Energy Isotope Spectrometer (ULEIS) experiment on the ACE mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Space Science Reviews Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://link.springer.com/article/10.1023/A:1005079930780</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Ultra-Low Energy Isotope Spectrometer (ULEIS) experiment on the ACE mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>MassSpectrometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Ultra-Low Energy Isotope Spectrometer (ULEIS) on ACE</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ACE</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ACE/SIS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Solar Isotope Spectrometer (SIS)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>SIS</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>1997-045A-05</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Solar Isotope Spectrometer (SIS) experiment provides measurements at isotopic resolution of elements from He through Zn (2 &lt; Z &lt; 31) at energies of 10 - 100 MeV/nucleon. This energy range includes energetic ions accelerated by solar flares, coronal shocks, interplanetary shocks, and the solar wind termination shock (i.e., the anomalous cosmic ray component). Measurements of galactic cosmic ray ions are made at lower energies not covered by the Cosmic Ray Isotope Spectrometer (CRIS) instrument. The detector system consists of two identical charged particle telescopes composed of large-area silicon solid-state detectors. Each telescope consists of a hodoscope system made up of a pair of 2-D position-sensing detectors (M1 and M2), followed by an energy loss stack with eight detectors (T1 to T8) of varying thicknesses. Precise measurements of incident ion trajectories are provided by the position-sensing detectors (PSD's), each being 60 microns thick with 64 parallel "X" or "Y" strips on the top and bottom. Each such strip is separately pulse-height analyzed for energy loss determination and identification of multiple track events. The T1 - T8 detectors are composed of various combinations of 1-mm thick solid state elements linked electronically. T1 to T5, and T8, consist of one 1-mm element, whereas T6 includes three such elements and T7 includes six. Detectors T1 - T7 are pulse-height analyzed for energy loss measurements, and T8 is used to identify penetrating events. Acquisition of pulse-height event, counting rate, and housekeeping data is similar to that for CRIS, except that the pulse-height data volume varies from event to event and is minimal for the more abundant events from solar flares. The average event length is about 200 bits, which gives 10 events per second at the nominal 2 kbps telemetry rate. Since data for all heavy (Z &gt; 5) ion events cannot be acquired in some large solar flare events, a priority system selects events for telemetry based on estimated charge, energy (range in the detector stack), and event quality, the more penetrating heavy ions having greatest priority.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <!-- Alan Cummings -->
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Alan.C.Cummings</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <!-- Richard Mewaldt -->
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Richard.A.Mewaldt</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <!--Christina Cohen-->
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/C.M.S.Cohen</PersonID>
        <Role>TechnicalContact</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>SIS Home Page at CALTECH</Name>
        <URL>http://www.srl.caltech.edu/ACE/CRIS_SIS/sis.html</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the SIS instrument at Caltech, including links to data</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1997-045A-05</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Solar Isotope Spectrometer (SIS) experiment on the ACE mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Space Science Reviews Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://link.springer.com/article/10.1023/A:1005027929871</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Solar Isotope Spectrometer (SIS) on the ACE mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/instrument/1997-045A-05</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>ParticleDetector</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Solar Isotope Spectrometer (SIS) on ACE</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ACE</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ACE/SWIMS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Solar Wind Ion Mass Spectrometer (SWIMS)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>SWIMS</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Solar Wind Ion Mass Spectrometer (SWIMS) measures every few minutes the mass and energy of most solar wind ions and many isotopes with velocities in the range from 200 - 1500 km/s for He to 200 - 500 km/s for Fe. Abundances of rarer isotopes and ultra-heavy ions (A &gt; 60) are determined every few hours. Mass resolution is less than one percent. The instrument consists of a versatile deflection system followed by a time-of-flight (TOF) telescope. Solar winds ions enter a wide angle three-chamber deflection system acting as an energy-per-charge passband filter, the range of the passband being adjustable by change of the deflection voltage. The entry aperture field of view is 50 deg. x 60 deg. Ions within the passband enter the mass analyzer section of the instrument by passing through a thin carbon foil, from which the incident ions emerge mainly as neutrals or singly charged ions. The start signal for TOF analysis is generated by secondary electrons ejected from the tin foil and deflected into a microchannel plate (MCP) assembly. The ions are then deflected in an electrostatic square potential and stop in a large area MCP assembly, thereby triggering a stop signal for TOF determination of velocity. SWIMS telemetry includes pulse height analysis (PHA) and counting rate data for ion events, and housekeeping data. Readout of five PHA events per second requires 64 bits per event, while rates add another 180 bits/s. Another 5 bits/s is required for housekeeping and status data. The SWIMS experiment manager is Prof. G. Gloeckler of the University of Maryland.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/George.Gloeckler</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1997-045A-01</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Solar Wind Ion Mass Spectrometer (SWIMS) experiment on the ACE mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Space Science Reviews Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-94-011-4762-0_18</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Solar Wind Ion Composition Spectrometer (SWICS) and Solar Wind Ion Mass Spectrometer (SWIMS) on the ACE mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Solar Wind Ion Mass Spectrometer (SWIMS) on ACE</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ACE</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Eberhard.S.Moebius</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Eberhard S. Moebius</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>University of New Hampshire</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Norman.F.Ness</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Norman F. Ness</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>University of Delaware</OrganizationName>
    <Email>nfness@bartol.udel.edu</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+1 302 831 8116</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Robert.E.Gold</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Robert E. Gold</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Applied Physics Laboratory</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Dennis.Haggerty</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Dennis Haggerty</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Applied Physics Laboratory</OrganizationName>
    <Email>dennis.haggerty@jhuapl.edu</Email>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Charles.W.Smith</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr Charles W. Smith</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>University of New Hampshire</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Edward.C.Stone.Jr</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Prof. Edward C. Stone, Jr.</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>California Institute of Technology</OrganizationName>
    <Email>ecs@srl.caltech.edu</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+1 626 395 8321</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/David.J.McComas</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. David J. McComas</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Southwest Research Institute</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Richard.A.Mewaldt</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Richard A. Mewaldt</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>California Institute of Technology</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Alan.C.Cummings</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Alan C. Cummings</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>California Institute of Technology</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/C.M.S.Cohen</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr C. M. S. Cohen</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>California Institute of Technology</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Ruth.Skoug</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Ruth Skoug</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Los Alamos National Laboratory</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Richard.Leske</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Richard Leske</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>California Institute of Technology</OrganizationName>
    <Email>ral@srl.caltech.edu</Email>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Jan.Merka</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Jan Merka</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>NASA Goddard Space Flight Center</OrganizationName>
    <Address>Code 672, Greenbelt, MD 20771, USA</Address>
    <Email>jan.merka@nasa.gov</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+1 301 286 8751</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
        <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/George.Gloeckler</ResourceID>
        <ReleaseDate>2011-06-15T00:00:00</ReleaseDate>
        <PersonName>Prof. George M. Gloeckler</PersonName>
        <OrganizationName>University of Michigan</OrganizationName>
        <Email>gglo@umich.edu</Email>
    </Person></Spase>


