<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.0</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Aeros-A</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Aeros-A</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>1972-100A</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>Aeros 1</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The AEROS satellite had a circular cylindrical shape, 0.914 m in diameter and 0.710 m in height. It was launched into an elliptical, polar, nearly sun-synchronous earth orbit. The spacecraft was spin stabilized at 10 rpm and oriented with the spin axis toward the sun. The purpose of the mission was to study the state and behavior of the upper atmosphere and ionospheric F region, especially with regard to the influence of solar ultraviolet radiation. Five experiments provided data on the temperature and density of electrons, ions, and neutral particles, the composition of ions and neutral particles, and solar ultraviolet flux.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Siegfried.J.Bauer</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Peter.Laemmerzahl</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/spacecraft/display.action?id=1972-100A</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Aeros-A mission</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.NearSurface</ObservatoryRegion>
</Location>
</Observatory>
<Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Aeros-A/RPA</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Energy Distribution of Ions and Electrons</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>A retarding potential analyzer measured the energy distribution of electrons and ions. The corresponding temperatures were derived from these distributions. The experiment operated in an electron mode and in an ion mode. The instrument was essentially a collector shielded by plane parallel grids. Spectra of the ionospheric-charged particles were obtained by sweeping the retarding voltage of the grid. The particles would pass through the grid and reach the collector only if their kinetic energy exceeded the retarding potential. NSSDC has almost all the useful data that exist from this investigation.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Karl.Spenner</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1972-100A&amp;ex=2</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Energy Distribution of Ions and Electrons experiment on the Aeros-A mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Energy Distribution of Ions and Electrons on Aeros-A</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Aeros-A</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Aeros-A/NATE</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>The Neutral Atmosphere Temperature Experiment (NATE)</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Neutral Atmosphere Temperature Experiment (NATE) on AEROS-A, which was designed primarily to make in situ measurements of temperature, also functioned in an alternate mode as a neutral mass spectrometer to measure argon, atomic oxygen, nitrogen, and helium densities. Mounted at the satellite periphery was a spherical antechamber with a knife-edged orifice facing normal to the spin axis. This chamber, sealed under vacuum before launch, was opened to the atmosphere on command when the spacecraft was in orbit. The incoming atmospheric species underwent collisions with the chamber walls, and some of this thermalized gas entered a small dual-filament ion source that produced an ion beam proportional to the chamber density. The beam was directed into a quadrupole analyzer, that transmitted selected ions to an electron multiplier where individual ions at the input were converted to pulses of electrons, which were counted at the multiplier output. These output pulses were amplified and sent to a data processor that provided digital output signals to the telemetry system. Because of a difficulty in the timing system of the spacecraft, proper synchronization of the data frame with the spin position was not achieved--a requirement essential for the analysis of the data in the temperature mode. The instrument performed well as a mass spectrometer throughout the lifetime of the spacecraft, and good quality nitrogen, oxygen, and helium data were obtained from perigee to an altitude of about 550 km. For argon, the signal-to-noise ratio decreased rapidly above 350 km, and useful data were obtained only up to that altitude.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Nelson.W.Spencer</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1972-100A-05</URL>
        <Description>Information about Aeros-A NATE</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Spectrometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>The Neutral Atmosphere Temperature Experiment on Aeros-A</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Aeros-A</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Karl.Spenner</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Karl Spenner</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Unknown - formerly at Inst fur Physikalische, Fre</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Siegfried.J.Bauer</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Siegfried J. Bauer</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Universitat Graz</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Peter.Laemmerzahl</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Peter Laemmerzahl</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Max-Planck-Institut fur Kernphysik</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Nelson.W.Spencer</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Nelson W. Spencer</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Deceased - formerly at GSFC-Code 910</OrganizationName>
  </Person></Spase>


