<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.0</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Cluster-Samba</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Cluster FM7 (Samba)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>Cluster 2/FM7 (Samba)</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>2000-041A</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>FM7</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>Samba</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>Cluster-3</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This Cluster II spacecraft, FM7 (Samba), was launched together with FM6 (Salsa) by a
   Soyuz-Fregat rocket from Baikonur. The four similar spacecraft of the Cluster II mission are part
   of ESA's and NASA's Solar-Terrestrial Science Program (STSP). The current Cluster II mission is a
   near-replica of the original four-spacecraft mission lost at launch in 1996. (NSSDC will carry the
   name "Cluster96" in its information files to designate the unsuccessful 1996 four-spacecraft Ariane
   5 launch.) The purpose of the Cluster II mission is to study small-scale structures in three
   dimensions in the Earth's plasma environment, such as those involved in the interaction between
   the solar wind and the magnetospheric plasma, in global magnetotail dynamics, in cross-tail
   currents, and in the formation and dynamics of the neutral line and of plasmoids.

The four Cluster II spacecraft will orbit in a tetrahedral formation in near-polar orbits of nominally
4 x 19.6 Earth radii, with period about 57 hours, and inclination about 90.7 degrees.. Relative distances
between the spacecraft will be adjusted in the course of the mission, depending on the spatial scales of
the structures to be studied, varying from a few hundred km to a few Earth radii. The tetrahedral formation
is essential for making three-dimensional measurements and for determining the curl of vectorial quantities
such as the magnetic field.

The orbits of all four spacecraft will be frequently maneuvered so as to achieve the targeted investigations.

Each spacecraft will be spin-stabilized, normally at around 15 rpm, and will be cylindrical in shape,
with a 2.9-m diameter and 1.3-m length. It will have two rigid 5-m radial experiment booms, four 50-m
experiment wire booms, and two axial telecommunications antenna booms. Telemetry downlink bit rate will
be 2 to 262 kbit/s.

Each spacecraft will have AC and DC magnetometers, an electric fields and waves sensor, an electron
emitter/detector, an electron density sounder, electron and ion plasma analysers, an energetic particle
detector, an ion emitter, and a data processing unit.

Cluster operations will be performed by ESOC in Darmstadt, Germany, with support from NASA's Deep Space Network.
Cluster is also an IACG mission. The scientific data are distributed by ESOC using CD-ROM as a medium
to the Principal Investigators, Co-Investigators and the network of eight national data centres (6 in
Europe, 1 in USA and 1 in China) that form the Cluster Science Data System (CSDS). There are approximately
80 recipients world-wide. Science operations are carried out by the Joint Science Operations Centre,
co-located with the UK data centre at RAL, Didcot. A wide scientific community will have differing rights of
access to the Cluster data. Scientists wishing to access Cluster data should contact their national Data Centres.

ESA SP-1159, Paris, March 1993 is entitled "Cluster: Mission, Payload and Supporting Activities" Edited by W. R. Burke.
European Space Agency, ESA SP-1159, 1993.ISBN: 92-9092-073-4.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Melvyn.L.Goldstein</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/spacecraft/display.action?id=2000-041A</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Cluster 2/FM7 (Samba) mission</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>ESA Cluster Homepage</Name>
        <URL>http://sci.esa.int/cluster/</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Cluster 2/FM7 (Samba) mission</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Space Science Reviews Article</Name>
        <URL>https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-94-011-5666-0_1</URL>
        <Description>Detailed Information about the Cluster mission</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>ESA Bulletin no. 91 (August 1997) on the Resurrection of Cluster</Name>
        <URL>http://esamultimedia.esa.int/multimedia/publications/ESA-Bulletin-091/</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Cluster mission</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>ESA Bulletin 84 (November 1995) An overview of the original mission of Cluster</Name>
        <URL>http://esamultimedia.esa.int/multimedia/publications/ESA-Bulletin-091/</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Cluster mission</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Access to CDAWeb Cluster Data Archive</Name>
        <URL>https://cdaweb.gsfc.nasa.gov/cdaweb/istp_public/</URL>
        <Description>Cluster 2/FM7 (Samba) data access.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Cluster2-Samba</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <ObservatoryGroupID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Cluster</ObservatoryGroupID>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Heliosphere.NearEarth</ObservatoryRegion>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Main</ObservatoryRegion>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Magnetosheath</ObservatoryRegion>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Polar</ObservatoryRegion>
</Location>
</Observatory>
<Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Cluster-Samba/WBD</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Wide Band Data (WBD)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>WBD</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The WBD (Wide Band Data) investigation is designed to provide high-resolution frequency/time spectra of plasma waves in the Earth's magnetosphere. As part of the Wave Experiments Consortium (WEC), this instrument provides measurements of both electric and magnetic fields in selected frequency bands from 25 Hz to 577 KHz. Continuous waveforms are digitized, formatted, and transferred to the spacecraft telemetry system using either a 220 Kbps real-time mode or a 73 Kbps burst mode. The real-time data require direct acquisition by a NASA Deep Space Network receiving station, and the burst-mode data are stored on the spacecraft tape recorder for later playback. On the ground the waveforms are Fourier transformed to provide high-resolution frequency/time spectrograms. The extremely high (microsecond) time resolution provided by the WBD measurements will make it possible to utilize the signals from two or more of the Cluster spacecraft to perform very-long-baseline-interferometer measurements. The WBD instrument processes signals from one of four selectable sensors: two electric field signals (from the EFW experiment) and two magnetic field signals (from the STAFF). The EFW sensors are spherical electric antennas with sphere-to-sphere separation of about 100 m after full deployment. The STAFF sensors are search coil magnetometers with the measurement axis in the spin plane (By) or along the spin axis (Bz). Commanding of the WBD instrument is managed by the DWP instrument. In the burst data recording mode, the WBD data are transferred to the DWP at 220 Kbps. Then the DWP reduces the wideband data by a factor of three by digital filtering and re-sampling, and sends the lower rate data to the spacecraft data system for recording and subsequent playback. For more details of the Cluster mission, the spacecraft, and its instruments, see the report ``Cluster: mission, payload and supporting activities,'' March 1993, ESA SP-1159, and the included article ``The Wideband Plasma Wave Investigation,'' by D. A. Gurnett et al., from which this information was obtained.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Donald.A.Gurnett</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=2000-041A-10</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Wide Band Data (WBD) experiment on the Cluster 2/FM5 (Samba) mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Space Science Reviews Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-94-011-5666-0_8</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Wide Band Data (WBD) experiment.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Cluster2-Samba/WBD</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>WaveformReceiver</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Wide Band Data (WBD) on Cluster 2/FM7 (Samba)</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Cluster-Samba</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Cluster-Samba/STAFF</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Spatio-Temporal Analysis of Magnetic Field Fluctuations (STAFF)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>STAFF</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This experiment (STAFF: Spatio-Temporal Analysis of Field Fluctuations) is one of the five complementary experiments which form the Wave Experiment Consortium (WEC) on Cluster. STAFF consists of: (1) a triaxial boom-mounted search-coil magnetometer to measure the magnetic components of electromagnetic fluctuations (up to 4 KHz); and, (2) a spectrum analyzer to compute the 25 auto- and cross-correlation coefficients of the spectral matrix, using three magnetic and two electric components of the waves. The magnetic waveform (up to either 10 Hz or 180 Hz) is also transmitted. The Z-axis sensor is parallel to the spacecraft spin axis. Each sensor consists of a high-permeability core embedded inside two solenoids. The frequency response of the main winding is flattened by a secondary winding through a flux feedback effect, in the range 40--4000 Hz. Further, the secondary winding is used as a calibration loop to which an external AC signal is applied. In normal bit rate the wave-form data cover the 0.1--10 Hz frequency range, and the spectrum analyzer covers the range 8 Hz to 4 KHz. In high bit rate, the wave-form data cover 0.1--180 Hz and the spectrum analyzer covers 64 Hz to 4 KHz, using only the two highest frequency bands. In the base mode in normal bit rate the auto-spectra are averaged over 1 s, and the complete 25-component matrix is averaged over 4 s for five components. In high bit rate, only the two highest frequency bands are analyzed. In the fast modes, time resolution is 1 s for the cross-spectra, and either 0.125 s or 0.25 s for the auto-spectra. Other modes are also defined. The analysis will also use electric field waveform data from the EFW (part of WEC), and the hardware of the two instruments was designed to optimize correlation: low-pass filters are identical, sampling frequency is the same, and there is a synchronization signal for simultaneous sampling. The output signals of the STAFF magnetic preamplifiers are also sent to two other instruments: the WBD (part of WEC) and the EDI. Some of the magnetospheric structures to be studied are of small scale, and where the signature duration is of the order 1 s or less, the STAFF search coil data are complementary to those of the fluxgate magnetometer (FGM). For more details of the Cluster mission, the spacecraft, and its instruments, see the report ``Cluster: mission, payload and supporting activities,'' March 1993, ESA SP-1159, and the included article ``The STAFF (Spatio-Temporal Analysis of Field Fluctuations) Experiment for the Cluster Mission'', by N. Cornilleau-Wehrlin et al., from which this information was obtained.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Nicole.Cornilleau-Wehrlin</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=2000-041A-09</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Spatio-Temporal Analysis of Magnetic Field Fluctuations (STAFF) experiment on the Cluster 2/FM5 (Samba) mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Space Science Reviews Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-94-011-5666-0_5</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Spatio-Temporal Analysis of Magnetic Field Fluctuations (STAFF) experiment.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Cluster2-Samba/STAFF</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Spatio-Temporal Analysis of Magnetic Field Fluctuations (STAFF) on Cluster 2/FM7 (Samba)</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Cluster-Samba</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Cluster-Samba/CIS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Cluster Ion Spectrometry (CIS)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>CIS</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This instrument (CIS: Cluster Ion Spectrometry) is capable of obtaining full 3D ion distributions with high time resolution (in one spacecraft spin) and mass-per-charge resolution. The experiment consists of two different instruments, a Hot Ion Analyzer (HIA) and a time-of-flight Ion Composition and Distribution Function analyzer (CODIF). Extensive on-board processing is done, within its dual-processor Data Processing System (DPS). CODIF determines the distributions of the major ion species with energies from spacecraft potential to 40 KeV/charge with an angular resolution of 22.5 x 10.25 degrees and with two different sensitivities. The CODIF instrument uses electrostatic deflection to select by energy per charge, with subsequent time-of-flight analysis. The sensor primarily covers the energy range 0.02--40 KeV/charge, but with additional pre-acceleration for energies below 25 eV/charge, the range is extended to energies as low as the spacecraft potential. The HIA does not measure mass, but extends the dynamic range to the highest ion fluxes, and has angular resolution capability of 5.6 x 5.6 degrees for ion-beam and solar-wind measurements. The HIA is a symmetric quadrispherical analyzer of top-hat geometry, and uses microchannel-plate electron multipliers and position encoding by discrete anodes. A 2D distribution is obtained once per 62.5 ms, and a full 3D distribution of ions in the energy range ~5 eV/charge to 32 KeV/charge is obtained every 4 s. For more details of the Cluster mission, the spacecraft, and its instruments, see the report ``Cluster: mission, payload and supporting activities,'' March 1993, ESA SP-1159, and the included article ``The Cluster Ion Spectrometry Experiment,'' by H. Reme et al., from which this information was obtained.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Henri.Reme</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=2000-041A-02</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Cluster Ion Spectrometry (CIS) experiment on the Cluster 2/FM5 (Samba) mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Space Science Reviews Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-94-011-5666-0_12</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Cluster Ion Spectrometry (CIS) experiment.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Cluster2-Samba/CIS</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Cluster Ion Spectrometry (CIS) on Cluster 2/FM7 (Samba)</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Cluster-Samba</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Cluster-Samba/EFW</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Electric Field and Waves (EFW)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>EFW</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The EFW (Electric Field and Waves) instrument consists of four orthogonal spherical sensors deployed from 50 m cable booms in the spin plane of the spacecraft, plus four deployment units and a main electronics unit. Each deployment unit deploys a multiconductor cable and tip-mounted spherical sensor. Each opposing pair of cables will be symmetrically deployed to a tip-to-tip distance of approximately 100 m, except for about a week at the beginning of the mission when 70 m will be used for one boom pair (the Z-booms) and 100 m for the other pair. The potentials of the spherical sensor and nearby conductors are controlled by the microprocessor to minimize errors associated with photoelectron fluxes to and from the spheres. Output signals from the sensor preamplifiers are provided to the wave instruments for analysis of high frequency wave phenomena. There is a 1 MB burst memory and tow fast A/D conversion circuits for recording electric field wave forms for time resolutions of up to 36,000 samples/s. Data gathered in the burst memory will be played back through the telemetry stream allocated to the instrument by pre-empting a portion of the real-time data. Incoming data are continuously monitored by algorithms in the software to determine whether to trigger the burst-playback mode. A large number of sampling modes is possible, yielding four possible telemetry rates from 1.440--29.440 Kbps. This data stream is transferred via the DWP instrument. The main measured quantities will be, in various modes: (1) the instantaneous spin-plane components of the electric field vector, from 0.1--700 V/Km, with time resolution down to 0.1 ms, in four frequency ranges from DC to upper limits of 10 Hz, 180 Hz, 4 KHz, or 32 KHz; (2) the AC electric field components from 10 Hz to 8 KHz, within the dynamic range of ~3 mV/Km to 10 V/Km; (3) plasma density fluctuations within the range of 1--100/cm and in three frequency ranges from 0 Hz to upper limits of 10 Hz, 180 Hz, or 4 KHz; and, (4) density and temperature (in Langmuir sweeps) in the eV range, with a dynamic range of 1--100/cm. There is also a frequency counter covering the range 10--200 KHz. On-board calculations of least-square fits to the electric field data over one spacecraft spin period (4 s) will provide a baseline of high-quality two-dimensional electric field components that are present in the telemetry stream, except for periods when three or four sensors are in current mode. The spacecraft potential is calculated and transmitted via DWP to other instruments on board. The three components from the search coil instrument (WHISPER) are also available in EFW with a bandwidth of 4 KHz. For more details of the Cluster mission, the spacecraft, and its instruments, see the report ``Cluster: mission, payload and supporting activities,'' March 1993, ESA SP-1159, and the included article ``The Spherical Probe Electric Field and Wave Experiment for the Cluster Mission,'' by G. Gustafsson et al., from which this information was obtained.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Georg.Gustafsson</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=2000-041A-08</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Electric Field and Waves (EFW) experiment on the Cluster 2/FM5 (Samba) mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Space Science Reviews Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-94-011-5666-0_6</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Electric Field and Waves (EFW) experiment.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Cluster2-Samba/EFW</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>LongWire</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Electric Field and Waves (EFW) on Cluster 2/FM7 (Samba)</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Cluster-Samba</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Cluster-Samba/DWP</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Digital Wave Processor (DWP)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>DWP</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The DWP (Digital Wave Processor) is one of the five complementary experiments which form the Wave Experiment Consortium (WEC) on Cluster. The wide variety of plasmas to be investigated by the Cluster mission contains waves with a frequency range from DC to over 100 KHz with both magnetic and electric components. The characteristic duration of these waves extends from a few milliseconds to minutes and a dynamic range of over 90 dB is desired. Thus the instrument controllers and the on-board coordination controller (DWP) must be flexible. Various data compression methods are implemented within the WEC and DWP. Digital filtering with resampling is used with the WBD instrument; differential encoding is used with STAFF; data selection followed by pseudo-logarithmic compression is used with WHISPER; and averaging is used with the correlator within DWP. DWP is responsible for co-ordinating WEC operations at several levels. At the lowest level, it provides electrical signals to synchronize instrument sampling. At higher levels, it time tags data and provides a facility for constructing more complex WEC modes by means of macros. The sample synchronizing clock is not synchronous with the spacecraft spin rate. WBD data may be routed through the DWP to the spacecraft tape recorders. DWP reduces this data rate by a factor of three by applying a digital filtering algorithm to this data stream and then resampling it. Of particular interest in the DWP is the implementation of a particle correlator technique. This diagnostic technique is based on forming autocorrelation functions of the time series of particle detector counts as a function of energy and pitch angle. The basic operations will be carried out in DWP resident software. The particle correlator technique permits: (a) the detection of particle flux bursts on time scales short compared with the energy and dwell time;, and (b) an indication of regions of velocity space in which wave/particle interactions are occurring. The DWP has some automatic checks built into its software to monitor the performance of WEC instruments interfaced to it. These can be disabled by ground command if needed. For more details of the Cluster mission, the spacecraft, and its instruments, see the report ``Cluster: mission, payload and supporting activities,'' March 1993, ESA SP-1159, and the included article ``Implementation of the Digital Wave-Processing Experiment,'' by L. J. C. Wooliscroft et al., from which this information was obtained.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Hugo.Alleyne</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=2000-041A-07</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Digital Wave Processor (DWP) experiment on the Cluster 2/FM5 (Samba) mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Space Science Reviews Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-94-011-5666-0_9</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Digital Wave Processor (DWP) experiment.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Cluster2-Samba/DWP</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Unspecified</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Digital Wave Processor (DWP) on Cluster 2/FM7 (Samba)</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Cluster-Samba</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Cluster-Samba/FGM</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Fluxgate Magnetometer (FGM)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>FGM</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This instrument (FGM: Fluxgate Magnetometer) consists of two tri-axial fluxgate magnetometers mounted on one of the two 5 m radial booms, plus a data processing unit (DPU) on the main equipment platform. The magnetometer boom lies in the spacecraft spin plane, with the outboard sensor at the boom tip and the inboard sensor mounted 1.5 m inboard from the tip, to minimize the importance of the spacecraft background magnetic field and its variations. The sensors are mounted such that the X axes are aligned with the spacecraft spin axis, and the other axes are in the spin plane. There are five sensitivity ranges, from +/- 256 nT to +/- 65,500 nT (used only to facilitate ground testing). Range switching can be automatic or by command. Calibration is done by introducing a known current step into the feedback loop of the sensors. Telemetry allocation limits the normal output to about 20 vectors/s. For short periods at higher time resolution, data are stored at rates of up to 124.3 vectors/s in a memory block, the micro-structure analyzer (MSA). The MSA capacity is 32,000 vectors, more than 4 minutes of data at the highest sampling rate. This memory is continually over-written until a special event is detected, when its contents are frozen and held for readout interleaved with the normal lower-resolution data. The DPU has dual redundancy, including two CPUs. The CPU convolves the full bandwidth data with a Gaussian digital filter to match the rate and bandwidth of the transmitted vectors to the available telemetry rate. Unfiltered vector data are sent at 64.35 ms intervals to all but one of the other experiments. The DPU has a number of stored algorithms for recognition of events of particular interest, to trigger the MSA. The objective is to identify such events as boundary crossings or shocks when the high-rate capability of the MSA for short periods could capture the detailed signature of the event. The algorithms were defined at an early stage, but resettable thresholds for the event triggers will enable optimization in flight. There are eight different telemetry operating modes of the instrument, corresponding to both normal and burst modes, with MSA readout rates of 0, 9, 12, or 120 vectors/s. For more details of the Cluster mission, the spacecraft, and its instruments, see the report ``Cluster: mission, payload and supporting activities,'' March 1993, ESA SP-1159, and the included article ``The Cluster Magnetic Field Investigation: scientific objective and instrumentation,'' by A. Balogh et al., from which this information was obtained.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Andre.Balogh</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=2000-041A-04</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Fluxgate Magnetometer (FGM) experiment on the Cluster 2/FM5 (Samba) mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Space Science Reviews Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-94-011-5666-0_3</URL>
        <Description>Detail information about the Fluxgate Magnetometer (FGM) experiment.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Cluster2-Samba/FGM</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Fluxgate Magnetometer (FGM) on Cluster 2/FM7 (Samba)</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Cluster-Samba</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Cluster-Samba/WHISPER</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Waves of HF and Sounder for Probing Electron Density by Relaxation (WHISPER)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>WHISPER</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This instrument (WHISPER: Waves of HIgh frequency and Sounder for Probing of the Electron density by Relaxation) is part of the Wave Experiment Consortium (WEC) on Cluster. Its objectives are to: (1) measure the electron density via active sounding of plasma resonances; and, (2) record via passive wave analysis the natural wave emissions in the high-frequency range, from 4--80 KHz. An active sounder can provide the total local electron density, including the cold component, which is the dominant one in many of the regions to be explored. Most of the time, this cold component cannot be obtained from particle experiments, owing to the satellite's electric potential and photoelectron sheath disturbance. The sounder consists of three main parts: (1) a sensitive double-sphere antenna, measuring the AC electric field, provided as part of the EFW experiment; (2) a transmitter, a receiver, a digital spectrum analyzer, and a controller unit, which form the WHISPER instrument itself; and, (3) command and data processing systems, which are part of the DWP experiment, which also takes care of command and telemetry for the entire WEC unit. During the active part of WHISPER operation, in each frequency step a short (1 ms in normal mode; 0.5 ms also possible) wave train at the fixed frequency is transmitted. The receiver is then activated to receive until the end of the frequency step. This is repeated for a series of frequencies, sweeping a designated range of frequencies. The frequency step duration is a multiple of 13.33 ms to allow good synchronization with the EFW instrument's sampling period, and ranges up to ~250 ms. The sweep duration is a number of steps, and ranges from 0.5 s to ~10 s. The total frequency range available for the active transmitter is from 4--80 KHz. Different signal strength levels can be selected, e.g. 50, 100, 200 V peak to peak. During passive operations, there is no short pulse transmitted. The receiver signal is measured each 13.33 ms, and after A/D conversion it is analyzed in frequency by the vector signal processor (VSP), which performs a fast Fourier transform and delivers 64 to 512 useful bins in the range 0--80 KHz. The 512-bin option is always used in sounding mode. The operational details of the instrument are managed by the microcontroller, which also handles the interface to the DWP. Extensive data compression is used, either in the DWP (normal) or within WHISPER itself as backup. There is a considerable number of WHISPER modes, with a corresponding range of frequency resolutions and final data rates. In the standard WEC modes, the telemetry rate is about 980 bps in routine and 5800 bps in high rate. Plasma densities from 0.2 to 80 cm**-3 are measured, with a time resolution of 4 s routine and 1 s at best. Natural wave electric fields are measured with a sensitivity of 0.05 microV/(m sqrt(Hz)). Time and frequency resolutions are 3 s and 640 Hz routine, and 100 ms and 320 Hz at best. In any given mode, the dynamic range is about 100 dB, but 124 dB absolute range can be reached by commanded gain change. For more details of the Cluster mission, the spacecraft, and its instruments, see the report ``Cluster: mission, payload and supporting activities,'' March 1993, ESA SP-1159, and the included article ``WHISPER, a Sounder and High-Frequency Wave Analyser Experiment,'' by P. M. E. Decreau et al., from which this information was obtained.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Pierrette.Decreau</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=2000-041A-11</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Waves of HF and Sounder for Probing Electron Density by Relaxation (WHISPER) experiment on the Cluster 2/FM5 (Samba) mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Space Science Reviews Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-94-011-5666-0_7</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Waves of HF and Sounder for Probing Electron Density by Relaxation (WHISPER) experiment.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Cluster2-Samba/WHISPER</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>DoubleSphere</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Waves of HF and Sounder for Probing Electron Density by Relaxation (WHISPER) on Cluster 2/FM7 (Samba)</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Cluster-Samba</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Cluster-Samba/EDI</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Electron Drift Instrument (EDI)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>EDI</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This instrument (EDI: Electron Drift Instrument) measures the drift of a weak beam of test electrons that, when emitted in certain directions, return to the spacecraft after one gyration. This drift is related to the electric field and the gradient in the magnetic field, and these quantities can, by the use of different electron energies, be determined separately. As a by-product, the magnetic field strength is also measured. Conventional tungsten cathode electron guns are used, with a beam steerable in any direction within more than a hemisphere. Each detector is axially symmetric and can cover more than 2 pi steradians. A large effective area is made possible by double focusing. Electron guns and detectors are combined in pairs into single gun/detector units (GDUs). Two GDUs are used, mounted on opposite sides of the spacecraft. The detector in each GDU detects the beam electrons from the gun in the other GDU. The emitted electron beam has a finite opening angle of approximately 1 degree. This beam spreads along the magnetic field, but perpendicular to the field the beam is focused after one gyration. To detect the beam electrons in the presence of ambient electrons, and to measure their flight time, the beam is modulated and coded. The modulation frequency can be chosen between 500 KHz and 4 MHz. The pulses received by the detectors, and the delayed format of the code, are then fed into a correlator. Its output will be different from noise only if the delay time equals the electron gyroperiod. The delay times are initialized on the basis of the on-board magnetometer data. The delay time will then drift with a selectable rate until the actual flight times are within the range of the correlators. An auto-track feature then keeps the beam electron counts in a single correlator channel. A second, different correlator scheme is also used, having the advantage that beam electrons are always counted in one of the channels, but the disadvantage that the flight time is not determined unambiguously. The fundamental time step to determine the new parameters and direct the beams and the detectors is 2 ms. In some modes, this can be lengthened, to accommodate tracking tasks that operate on longer time scales. Inter-experiment links include: magnetic field information from FGM and STAFF, a blanking pulse received from WHISPER to warn of possible interference from that active experiment, and a similar blanking pulse sent to PEACE when the EDI electron beam could interfere with the PEACE electron measurement. For more details of the Cluster mission, the spacecraft, and its instruments, see the report ``Cluster: mission, payload and supporting activities,'' March 1993, ESA SP-1159, and the included article ``The Electron Drift Instrument for Cluster,'' by G. Paschmann et al., from which this information was obtained.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Goetz.Paschmann</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=2000-041A-03</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Electron Drift Instrument (EDI) experiment on the Cluster 2/FM5 (Samba) mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Space Science Reviews Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-94-011-5666-0_10</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Electron Drift Instrument (EDI) experiment.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Cluster2-Samba/EDI</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>ElectronDriftInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Electron Drift Instrument (EDI) on Cluster 2/FM7 (Samba)</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Cluster-Samba</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Cluster-Samba/Ephemeris</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Cluster-Samba Positions</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>Cluster-Samba Ephemeris</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2011-02-04T15:37:07Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>Cluster-Samba spacecraft positions in various coordinate systems</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/M.Tatrallyay</PersonID>
        <Role>DataProducer</Role>
      </Contact>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Cluster2-Samba/Ephemeris</PriorID>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Platform</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Spacecraft position</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Cluster-Samba</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Cluster-Samba/ASPOC</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Active Spacecraft Potential Control (ASPOC)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>ASPOC</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The objective of this instrument (ASPOC: Active Spacecraft POtential Control) is to ensure effective, complete measurement of the ambient plasma distribution functions, especially the very cold component. Additional benefits may be found in improved data for the long-wire electric field measurement, and the electron-beam probe for electric fields. The ASPOC instrument is a single unit consisting of an electronics box and two cylindrical ion-emitter modules. The emitters will produce indium ions at approximately 6 KeV, in a current of &lt;50 microamps. This will be done by field evaporation of indium in the apex field of a needle. The outgoing beam will diverge from parallel by +/- 15 degrees (half maximum). Design lifetime is 10,000 hours. In the basic feedback mode of operation, a measurement of the spacecraft potential is supplied to the instrument from either the electric field experiment (EFW) or the electron analyzer (PEACE). This information is then used to adjust the emission current to reduce the spacecraft potential to some predetermined value. By default, priority is given to the EFW data, because of the higher resolution (0.034 V vs. ~1.4 V) and the more straightforward way in which the potential is derived. There is also a stand-alone mode for backup. The electrical parameters of the ion beam will be available to all experimenters, and this will also enable them to interpret their data with respect to any remaining effects of the spacecraft potential. A calibration mode will measure the current-voltage characteristics of the spacecraft, at the beginning of the mission and occasionally later to account for changes in the photo-emission properties of the surface. This measurement is carried out by sweeping the ion emission current in incremental steps over some convenient range, allowing simultaneous measurements of the spacecraft potential. The length of each step is 2--4 spin periods. In addition to providing an improved environment for other experiments, ASPOC will permit scientific investigations of the photoelectric characteristics of the dependence of the spacecraft potential on plasma parameters, and of spacecraft charging in different plasma environments to be carried out in the so-called active mode. The ion current can be varied in a defined way for a short time to enable the co-operating plasma experiments to calibrate their response to spacecraft potential variations. Such experiments will be carried out at large, regular intervals, preferably in sections of the orbit which are not of prime interest to the mission as a whole. For more details of the Cluster mission, the spacecraft, and its instruments, see the report ``Cluster: mission, payload and supporting activities,'' March 1993, ESA SP-1159, and the included article ``Active Spacecraft Potential Control: an ion emitter experiment for Cluster,'' by W. Riedler et al., from which this information was obtained.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Willi.W.Riedler</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=2000-041A-01</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Active Spacecraft Potential Control (ASPOC) experiment on the Cluster 2/FM5 (Samba) mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Space Science Reviews Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-94-011-5666-0_11</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Active Spacecraft Potential Control (ASPOC) experiment.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Cluster2-Samba/ASPOC</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>SpacecraftPotentialControl</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Active Spacecraft Potential Control (ASPOC) on Cluster 2/FM7 (Samba)</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Cluster-Samba</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Cluster-Samba/RAPID</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Research with Adaptive Particle Imaging Detectors (RAPID)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>RAPID</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The dual-sensor spectrometer RAPID (Research with Adaptive Particle Imaging Detectors) analyzes suprathermal plasma distributions in the energy range from 20--400 KeV for electrons and from 2 KeV/nucleon to 1.50 MeV/nucleon for ions. Angular distributions are measured over a range of 180 degrees in polar angle for either species. Electrons are identified by the well-known energy-range relationship. The detection principle for ions is based on a two-dimensional analysis of a particle's velocity and energy. Moderate mass resolution of about four (for oxygen ions) permits the identification of ions and ion groups of significance. Particle species identified are electrons, protons, He and CNO group ions, and energetic neutral atoms of energies 10--100 KeV. RAPID science data are transmitted through a complex data format, using 17 Kbps in the telemetry nominal mode. Time resolution is as high as 16 samples/spin for certain elements. The nominal spin period for the spacecraft is 4 s. The RAPID field of view covers a range of 180 degrees with respect to the spin vector. The sensor systems, IIMS and IES, scan the full range of the solid angle as the spacecraft rotates. The data returned will be used to project the intensity distribution in distant particle sources on a spherical or plane image area with 192 pixels for IIMS and 144 pixels for IES. The Imaging Ion Mass Spectrometer (IIMS) sensor system is composed of three identical SCENIC (Spectroscopic Camera for Electrons, Neutral and Ion Composition) heads. The sensor systems of IIMS are identical to those in the HEP-LD instrument included in the Japanese Geotail spacecraft. The IIMS uses two-dimensional time-of-flight/energy analysis to determine particle mass. The addition of position-sensing techniques on the entrance foil, in combination with a geometrically small stop detector at the end of the flight path provides directional sensitivity. This approach divides the 180 degree polar segment into twelve contiguous angular intervals. Sectoring the spacecraft spin plane with a maximum of sixteen azimuthal intervals covers the unit sphere in velocity space completely with a total of 192 angular bins. The Imaging Electron Spectrometer (IES) achieves directional sensitivity by using novel microstrip solid-state devices in combination with a pin-hole acceptance. This technique divides the 180 degree polar range into nine angular intervals which, with sixteen sectors in the spin plane, corresponds to a total of 144 bins on the unit sphere. The RAPID spectrometer is connected to the magnetic field instrument FGM through the inter-experiment link. FGM sends 64 uncorrected magnetic field vectors per spacecraft rotation. These are used by the data processor to determine, for each of the sixteen azimuthal sectors, which look directions in the IIMS and IES fans are perpendicular to the current magnetic field vector. For more details of the Cluster mission, the spacecraft, and its instruments, see the report ``Cluster: mission, payload and supporting activities,'' March 1993, ESA SP-1159, and the included article ``RAPID: The Imaging Energetic Particle Spectrometer on Cluster,'' by B. Wilken et al., from which this information was obtained.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Berend.Wilken</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=2000-041A-06</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Research with Adaptive Particle Imaging Detectors (RAPID) experiment on the Cluster 2/FM5 (Samba) mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Space Science Reviews Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-94-011-5666-0_14</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Research with Adaptive Particle Imaging Detectors (RAPID) experiment.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Cluster2-Samba/RAPID</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Research with Adaptive Particle Imaging Detectors (RAPID) on Cluster 2/FM7 (Samba)</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Cluster-Samba</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Cluster-Samba/PEACE</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Plasma Electron and Current Experiment (PEACE)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>PEACE</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The primary task of this instrument (PEACE: Plasma Electrons and Currents Experiment) is to obtain the velocity moments of the distribution function of electrons as frequently and as accurately as the spacecraft telemetry will allow. Detector counts are collected in energy, polar-angle, and azimuth-angle bins to form a three-dimensional matrix. Two sensors are used: LEEA (low-energy electron analyzer) and HEEA (high-energy electron analyzer). The energy coverage is from 0.67 eV to 30 KeV in 92 levels. The first 16 levels are equally spaced linearly up to 10.7 eV; the remainder are logarithmically spaced. Both sensors can use the full range, but the HEEA will normally operate over a higher energy range than the LEEA. The LEEA specializes in coverage of the energies from 0.7--10 eV, and has a geometric factor one fifth that of the HEAA. Both sensors consist of hemispherical electrostatic analyzers of the top-hat type and a detector in the form of an annular micro-channel plate with a position-sensitive readout. Each sensor covers the range 0--180 degrees with respect to the spin axis, and they are mounted opposite each other with a view perpendicular to the spin axis, thus covering the complete angular range in a half rotation of the spacecraft. The field of view perpendicular to the fan is 2 degrees for the LEEA and 5.6 degrees for the HEEA. Energy resolution (Delta-E)/E is 0.13 for LEEA and 0.16 for HEEA. There are four sweep modes, synchronized to the spin period (4 s), to vary the azimuthal angular resolution. The spin phasing can be made coincident with that of the CIS instrument, to ensure that the electron and ion moments will be measured simultaneously. On-board processing is used to calculate the moments of the distribution with an accuracy of 1% and to select suitable parts of the complete distribution for transmission. The normal science data format is based on one spin period, and consists of core data followed by other optional distributions as can be fit into the available telemetry for that spin. The core data (moments, spacecraft potential, and pitch angle distribution) are always transmitted (if the spin is nominal). The next distribution is transmitted if, before the end of the spin, all the previous data have been sent. Thus the next spin of data will be transmitted slightly late, but all of its core data will be transmitted before the following spin of data is started on. Eventually the transmission will catch up and be able to transmit the distribution after the core again, but only after some time. This applies at all telemetry rates. The instrument can adapt automatically to six different telemetry rates: a basic 1.52 Kbps rate (CIS priority); a normal 2.52 Kbps rate; an enhanced PEACE priority rate of 3.54 Kbps; and three burst mode rates, with a maximum of 15.98 Kbps. For more details of the Cluster mission, the spacecraft, and its instruments, see the report ``Cluster: mission, payload and supporting activities,'' March 1993, ESA SP-1159, and the included article ``PEACE: a Plasma Electron and Current Experiment,'' by A. D. Johnstone et al., from which this information was obtained.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Andrew.N.Fazakerley</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=2000-041A-05</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Plasma Electron and Current Experiment (PEACE) experiment on the Cluster 2/FM5 (Samba) mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Space Science Reviews Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-94-011-5666-0_13</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Plasma Electron and Current Experiment (PEACE) experiment.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Cluster2-Samba/PEACE</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Plasma Electron and Current Experiment (PEACE) on Cluster 2/FM7 (Samba)</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Cluster-Samba</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Berend.Wilken</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Berend Wilken</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Deceased - formerly at MPI fur Aeronomie, Germany</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Andrew.N.Fazakerley</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Andrew N. Fazakerley</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>University College London</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Goetz.Paschmann</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Goetz Paschmann</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Max Planck Institut fur Extraterrestrische Physik, Garching, Germany</OrganizationName>
    <Email>gep@mpe.mpg.de</Email>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Hugo.Alleyne</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Hugo Alleyne</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>University of Sheffield</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Melvyn.L.Goldstein</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Melvyn L. Goldstein</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>GSFC-Code 692</OrganizationName>
    <Email>melvyn.l.goldstein@nasa.gov</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+1-301-286-7828</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Henri.Reme</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Prof. Henri Reme</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>CNRS Centre d'Etudes Spatiales des Rayonnements</OrganizationName>
    <Email>henry.reme@cesr.fr</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+1-33-61-556665</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/M.Tatrallyay</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>M. Tatrallyay</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Hungarian Data Centre (KFKI)</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Donald.A.Gurnett</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Prof. Donald A. Gurnett</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>University of Iowa</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Nicole.Cornilleau-Wehrlin</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Nicole Cornilleau-Wehrlin</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Centre National d'Etudes des</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Pierrette.Decreau</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Pierrette Decreau</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>CNRS Laboratoire de Physique et Chimie</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Willi.W.Riedler</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Prof. Willi W. Riedler</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Technische Universitat Graz</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Andre.Balogh</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Andre Balogh</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Imperial College of Science, Technology and Medic</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Georg.Gustafsson</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Georg Gustafsson</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Swedish Institute of Space Physics</OrganizationName>
  </Person></Spase>


