<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.0</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Helios1</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Helios 1</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>Helios-A</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This spacecraft was one of a pair of deep space probes developed by the Federal Republic of Germany (FRG) in a cooperative program with NASA. Experiments were provided by scientists from both FRG and the U.S. NASA supplied the Titan/Centaur launch vehicle. The spacecraft was equipped with two booms and a 32-m electric dipole. The payload consisted of a fluxgate magnetometer; electric and magnetic wave experiments, which covered various bands in the frequency range 6 Hz to 3 MHz; charged-particle experiments, which covered various energy ranges starting with solar wind thermal energies and extending to 1 GeV; a zodiacal-light experiment; and a micrometeoroid experiment. The purpose of the mission was to make pioneering measurements of the interplanetary medium from the vicinity of the earth's orbit to 0.3 AU. The spin axis was normal to the ecliptic, and the nominal spin rate was 1 rps. The outer spacecraft surface was dielectric, effectively (because of the sheath potential) raising the low-energy threshold for the solar wind plasma experiment to as high as 100 eV. Also, sheath-related coupling caused by the spacecraft antennae produced interference with the wave experiments. The spacecraft was capable of being operated at bit rates from 4096 to 8 bps, variable by factors of 2. While the spacecraft was moving to perihelion, it was generally operated from 64 to 256 bps; and near 0.3 AU, it was operated at the highest bit rate. Because of a deployment failure of one axis of the 32-m, tip-to-tip, dipole antenna, one axis was shorted, causing the antenna to function as a monopole. The major effect of this anomaly was to increase the effective instrument thresholds, and to introduce additional uncertainties in the effective antenna length. Instrument descriptions written by the experimenters were published (some in German, some in English) in Raumfahrtforschung, v. 19, n. 5, 1975.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/James.H.Trainor</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Herbert.Porsche</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/spacecraft/display.action?id=1974-097A</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Helios-A mission</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://vspo/observatory/43</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <ObservatoryGroupID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Helios</ObservatoryGroupID>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Heliosphere.Inner</ObservatoryRegion>
</Location>
</Observatory>
<Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Helios1/E2</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Fluxgate Magnetometer for Field Fluctuations</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>Helios 1 E2</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>Helios 1 MGB</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2009-05-20T21:10:02Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>
The instrument (E2) consisted of a triaxial fluxgate magnetometer mounted on a 2.75-m boom to make magnetic field measurements up to 4 Hz.
Data from each axis were first sent through a low-pass filter with the 3 dB attenuation point at 4 Hz.
Depending on the telemetry format and bit rate, the data were fed either into a time-averaging computer or directly connected to telemetry.
When there were discontinuities in the variations of the ambient magnetic field, a shock-identification computer triggered the storage of rapid-rate data in the spacecraft memory.
Two measurement ranges were used, plus or minus 100 and 400 nT with resolutions of plus or minus 0.2 and 0.8 nT, respectively.
The instrument was equipped with a flipper mechanism, which re-oriented each sensor by 90 deg periodically.
For detailed information, see p. 232 of Raumfahrtforschung, v. 19, n. 5, 1975.
      </Description>
      <Acknowledgement>User will acknowledge the Helios 1 MGB PI F. B. Neubauer in any publication resulting from the use of these data.</Acknowledgement>
      <Contact>
        <!-- Dr. Rainer Schwenn -->
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Rainer.Schwenn</PersonID>
        <Role>DataProducer</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <!-- Prof. Fritz B. Neubauer -->
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Fritz.M.Neubauer</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>E2 Fluxgate Magnetometer</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Helios1</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Helios1/E5a</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Helios-1 E5A Plasma Wave Experiment</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>Solar Wind Plasma Wave</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>
The University of Iowa plasma wave experiment on Helios 1 provided measurements of electric field intensities in the frequency range from 31 Hz to 178 kHz. This frequency range includes most of the characteristic frequencies of the plasma (the electron plasma frequency, the ion plasma frequency and the electron gyrofrequency) expected in the solar wind from 0.3 to 1.0 AU (the nominal perihelion and aphelion distances for the Helios mission).

This experiment (E5a) shared the 32-m, tip-to-tip electric antenna with experiments E5b and E5c. The electric dipole antenna extended outward perpendicular to the spin axis.

The instrument consisted of a 16-channel spectrum analyzer with approximately logarithmically equi-spaced center frequencies, 16 log compressors, 16 RC integrators for averaging the log compressed electric field amplitude between readouts, and 16 peak detectors which were reset after readout. The 16 averages and 16 peak log values were sampled almost simultaneously. The channels covered the frequency range of about 20 Hz to 200 kHz, with four channels per decade of frequency. The log compressors had a dynamic range of 100 dB. Sampling rate depended in detail on the spacecraft bit rate and telemetry format. The fastest real-time telemetered rate was for 16 averages and 16 peak values to be sampled every 1.125 s. Whenever a very strong signal was detected in a pre-selected channel, the shock alarm data mode was initiated in which the electric field spectrum, magnetic field, and plasma data were recorded into spacecraft memory for a period starting before and terminating after the triggering signal time. The maximum sampling rate of the spectrum data in this mode was 14.2 samples per second for each channel.

One half of the dipole antenna failed to extend properly and was short-circuited to the spacecraft ground. The resultant configuration was that of a monopole which was calculated to have an effective length of approximately 8 m. The primary detrimental effects were the loss of 6 dB in E-field sensitivity due to the shortened antenna and the increase in the noise level of the 178 kHz channel by 25 dB. Solar cell and sheath effects caused interference in the lowest 6 channels (which was less severe with increasing channel frequency). For more details, see J. Geophys. Res., v. 82, p. 632, 1977, and pp. 245-247 of Raumfahrtforschung, v. 19, n. 5, 1975.
</Description>
      <Acknowledgement>Please acknowledge PI Donald Gurnett and The University of Iowa</Acknowledgement>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Donald.A.Gurnett</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Siegfried.J.Bauer</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Paul.J.Kellogg</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Robert.G.Stone</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/H.Kent.Hills</PersonID>
        <Role>TechnicalContact</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>Helios 1 and 2 Plasma Wave Experiment</Name>
        <URL>http://www-pw.physics.uiowa.edu/plasma-wave/helios/home.html</URL>
        <Description>Access to Science Summary, Publications and Data from The University of Iowa Helios E5A Plasma Wave Experiment</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>Helios Final Report-May 1986</Name>
        <URL>http://www-pw.physics.uiowa.edu/plasma-wave/helios/data1/doc/helios1.txt</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Solar Wind Plasma Wave scientific objectives, instrumentation, anomalies, and details on the data format from the E5a experiment on the Helios-1 mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1974-097A-04</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Solar Wind Plasma Wave experiment on the Helios-A mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Antenna</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Solar Wind Plasma Wave on Helios-1</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Helios1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Helios1/E1</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Helios 1 E1 Plasma Experiment</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>Helios 1 E1</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2009-05-20T21:10:02Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>
The E1 plasma experiment aboard the Helios solar probes consists of four independent instruments designed to investigate the solar wind plasma.
By measuring the velocity distribution functions of the different kinds of particles, all important hydrodynamic parameters of the solar wind plasma can be derived.
Three instruments (I1a, I1b, and I3) analyze the positive components (protons and heavier ions with energy-per-charge values from 0.155 to 15.32 kV) of the solar wind.
Two of them allow for an angular resolution in both directions of incidence. The experiment employed a combination of a hemispherical, a quadrispherical, and a sinusoidally-shaped electrostatic analyzer.

All detectors were mounted normal to the spin axis. 

One instrument (I2) measures electrons in the energy range from 0.5 the 1660 eV with one-dimensional angular resolution
using a hemispherical electrostatic analyzer.

For more detailed information see p. 226 of Raumfahrtforschung, v. 19, n. 5, 1975.
      </Description>
      <Acknowledgement>User will acknowledge the Helios 1 Plasma Experiment PI F. H. R. Rosenbauer in any publication resulting from the use of these data.</Acknowledgement>
      <Contact>
        <!-- Dr. Rainer Schwenn -->
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Rainer.Schwenn</PersonID>
        <Role>DataProducer</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <!-- Dr. Helmut R. Rosenbauer -->
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Helmut.R.Rosenbauer</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>ElectrostaticAnalyser</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>E1 Plasma Experiment</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Helios1</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Helios1/Ephemeris</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Helios 1 Position</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>Helios 1 Ephemeris</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2009-05-20T21:10:02Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>Helios 1 spacecraft position in various coordinate systems</Description>
      <Contact>
        <!-- Robert Candey -->
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Robert.M.Candey</PersonID>
        <Role>DataProducer</Role>
      </Contact>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Platform</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Spacecraft position</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Helios1</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Helios1/E6</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Cosmic Ray Particles</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The objective of the experiment (E6) was to study high-energy, charged, cosmic-ray particles of solar, planetary, and galactic origin in interplanetary space. Protons and alpha particles with energies &gt;1.3 MeV/nucleon, and electrons &gt;0.3 MeV were measured within interplanetary space over the range from 0.3 to 1.0 AU. The instrument, a particle telescope with a 55-deg field of view, consisted of five semiconductor detectors, one sapphire Cerenkov counter, and one scintillation counter, all enclosed by an anticoincidence cylinder. The telescope was calibrated prior to launch using radioactive sources, particle accelerators, and ground-level muons. It measured protons and alpha particles in six channels (1.3-3.3, 3.3-13, 13-27, 27-37, 37-45, and &gt;45 MeV/nucleon) and electrons in five energy channels (0.3-0.8, 0.8-2, 2-3, 3-4, and &gt;4 MeV). For more detail see pp. 253-257 of Raumfahrtforschung, v. 19, n. 5, 1975.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Horst.W.Kunow</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1974-097A&amp;ex=7</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Cosmic Ray Particle experiment on the Helios-A mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Cosmic Ray Particles Experiment on Helios-A</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Helios1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
      <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Helios1/E8</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>Energetic Electron and Proton Detector</ResourceName>
         <ReleaseDate>2022-02-20T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
         <RevisionHistory>
            <RevisionEvent>
               <ReleaseDate>2022-02-20T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
               <Note>Assorted Observatories and Instruments: Files reformated. Metadata submitted by J.M. Weygand on 2021-11-16, reviewed by LFB</Note>
            </RevisionEvent>
         </RevisionHistory>
         <Description>The objective of the experiment (E8) was to study the origin and the distribution mechanism of low-energy electrons and protons. The instrument, a magnetic spectrometer, consisted of six semiconductor detectors with the field of view in the plane of the ecliptic. Species separation was achieved by an inhomogeneous magnetic field oriented perpendicular to the particle path. Four electron and two proton detectors measured electrons from 17 to 835 keV and protons from 21 to 677 keV. The proton measurements were made with a two-detector telescope employing coincidence and anticoincidence logic. Both particle species were measured in 16 energy channels through pulse-height analysis. For further information see pp. 261-263 of Raumfahrtforschung, v. 19, n. 5, 1975.</Description>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Erhard.Keppler</PersonID>
            <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/James.M.Weygand</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Lee.Frost.Bargatze</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>NSSDC Data Set Catalog</Name>
            <URL>https://spdf.gsfc.nasa.gov/pub/documents/old/documentation_from_nssdc/dataset_catalogs/DSC_0488.pdf</URL>
            <Description>The NSSDC Data Set Catalog contains within itself a PI-generated detailed description of the experiment and data handling.</Description>
         </InformationURL>
      </ResourceHeader>
      <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
      <InvestigationName>Energetic Electron and Proton Detector on Helios-A</InvestigationName>
      <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Helios1</ObservatoryID>
   </Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Helios1/E4</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Search Coil Magnetometer</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This experiment (E4) was designed to investigate the magnetic component of electromagnetic waves in the solar wind from 0.3 to 1.0 AU. By means of its waveform channel (WFC) the rapid variations of the magnetic field were measured up from plus or minus 8.75 nT to plus or minus 275 nT in three orthogonal directions from 4 to 128 Hz. A spectrum analyzer observed the field components in the ecliptic plane and perpendicular to it, to obtain the power spectral density and peak values for eight logarithmically spaced channels in the range from 4.7 to 2200 Hz. Because of the large amount of data produced by this experiment, an adaptive data reduction was applied. For interesting time intervals selected by the fluxgate magnetometer (74-097A-01, Neubauer) or Gurnett (-04), waveform data could be read into an on-board memory at a rapid rate to be transmitted slowly afterwards. For more detailed information see p. 241 in Raumfahrtforschung, v. 19, n. 5, 1975.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Fritz.M.Neubauer</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1974-097A&amp;ex=3</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Search Coil Magnetometer experiment on the Helios-A mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Search Coil Magnetometer on Helios-A</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Helios1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Helios1/E3</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Fluxgate Magnetometer for Average Fields</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This experiment (E3) consisted of a boom-mounted, triaxial-fluxgate magnetometer. An automatic inflight range switch system selected the optimum of four ranges that were minus to plus 16, 48, 144, and 432 nT per sensor. These had corresponding digitization resolutions of minus to plus 0.03, 0.09, 0.28, and 0.84 nT, respectively. A sensor flipper was actuated every 36 h to assist in sensor zero level determination. For telemetry bit rates above 256 bps, vector measurements were made at rates between 1 and 16 per s, depending on bit rates. At lower bit rates, averages and variances were computed on board for transmission to earth.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Norman.F.Ness</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1974-097A&amp;ex=2</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Fluxgate Magnetometer for Average Fields experiment on the Helios-A mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Fluxgate Magnetometer for Average Fields on Helios-A</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Helios1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Helios1/E7</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Galactic and Solar Cosmic Rays</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The detector complement of this experiment (E7) consisted of
three separate dE/dx vs E telescopes and a proportional counter for monitoring
solar X rays in the range 2-8 keV. The high-energy telescope had a geometric
factor of 0.22 sq cm-sr and measured electrons in three ranges between 2 and 8 MeV,
and protons and alpha particles in three ranges between 20 and 56 MeV/n. Protons
above 230 MeV were also measured. The first low-energy telescope (geometric factor
was 0.155 sq cm-sr) measured protons and Z&gt;1 particles in three ranges between
3 and 21 MeV/n. The second low-energy telescope (geometric factor was 0.015 sq cm-sr)
measured protons in several ranges between 0.12 and 2.1 MeV, alpha particles in the
ranges 0.6-2.1 and 6-21.2 MeV/n, and electrons in four ranges between 0.12 and 2 MeV.
For a number of coincidence modes, counting-rate data sectored into eight 45-deg
sectors were obtained. The data cycle time was dependent on the spacecraft telemetry
rate (variable between 4096 and 8 bits/s) and format. Under optimum conditions, five
events per second were pulse-height analyzed and the rate data cycle was of the order
of 5 min. At the slowest combination of bit rate and format, a complete data cycle
required about 2.5 h. See IEEE Trans. on Nuc. Sci., NS-22, p. 570, 1975, and
Raumfahrtforschung, v. 19, n. 5, pp. 258-260, 1975, for further details.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Nand.Lal</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1974-097A&amp;ex=8</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Solar and Galactic Cosmic Ray experiment on the Helios-A mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Galactic and SolarCosmic Ray Experiment on Helios-A</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Helios1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Norman.F.Ness</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Norman F. Ness</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>University of Delaware</OrganizationName>
    <Email>nfness@bartol.udel.edu</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+1 302 831 8116</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/H.Kent.Hills</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. H. Kent Hills</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>NASA Goddard Space Flight Center</OrganizationName>
    <Address>Code 690.1, QSS Group Inc</Address>
    <Email>hills@nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+1 301 286 1771</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Fritz.M.Neubauer</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Prof. Fritz M. Neubauer</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Universitat zu Koln</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Robert.M.Candey</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Mr. Robert M. Candey</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>NASA Goddard Space Flight Center</OrganizationName>
    <Address>Code 672, Greenbelt, MD 20771, USA</Address>
    <Email>robert.m.candey@nasa.gov</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>1-301-286-6707</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Siegfried.J.Bauer</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Siegfried J. Bauer</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Universitat Graz</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
      <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Lee.Frost.Bargatze</ResourceID>
      <ReleaseDate>2012-06-13T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
      <PersonName>Lee Frost Bargatze</PersonName>
      <OrganizationName>Institute of Geophysics and Planetary Physics and the Department of Earth and Space Sciences, University of California, Los Angeles</OrganizationName>
      <Address>Institute of Geophysics and Planetary Physics, University of California Los Angeles, Box 951567, Los Angeles, CA 90095-1567</Address>
      <Email>lfb@igpp.ucla.edu</Email>
      <PhoneNumber>+1 310 206 6073</PhoneNumber>
   </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Erhard.Keppler</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Erhard Keppler</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Max-Planck-Institut fur Aeronomie</OrganizationName>
    <Email>keppler@linmpi.mpe.de</Email>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Paul.J.Kellogg</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Paul J. Kellogg</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>University of Minnesota</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Donald.A.Gurnett</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Prof. Donald A. Gurnett</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>University of Iowa</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/James.M.Weygand</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2018-05-30T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>James M. Weygand</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Department of Earth, Planetary, and Space Sciences; University of California, Los Angeles</OrganizationName>
    <Address>Department of Earth, Planetary, and Space Sciences, University of California Los Angeles, Box 951567, Los Angeles, CA 90095-1567</Address>
    <Email>jweygand@igpp.ucla.edu</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+1 310 825 3547</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Rainer.Schwenn</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Rainer Schwenn</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Max-Planck-Institut fur Aeronomie</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Herbert.Porsche</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Herbert Porsche</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>DLR</OrganizationName>
    <PhoneNumber>+1-49-8153-28-505</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Robert.G.Stone</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Robert G. Stone</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>GSFC-Code 690</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Helmut.R.Rosenbauer</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Helmut R. Rosenbauer</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Max Planck Institut fur Aeronomie</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Nand.Lal</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Nand Lal</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>GSFC-Code 612.4</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/James.H.Trainor</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. James H. Trainor</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Deceased - formerly at GSFC</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Horst.W.Kunow</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Horst W. Kunow</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Universitat Kiel</OrganizationName>
  </Person></Spase>


