<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.0</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Interball-1</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Interball-1</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>1995-039A</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>Interball Tail Probe</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>Prognoz 11</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Interball Project is a multi-national effort that consists of four spacecraft: two main spacecraft of the Prognoz series, made in Russia, each with a small subsatellite made in Czechoslovakia. The main objective is to study the physical mechanisms responsible for the transmission of solar wind energy to the magnetosphere, its storage there, and subsequent dissipation in the tail and auroral regions of the magnetosphere, ionosphere, and atmosphere during magnetospheric substorms. A ground-based support group will provide coordinated and simultaneous ground-based data of many types, including observations from auroral and polar cap regions. Interball is an IACG-related mission. Key physical parameters will be generated, and will be available for exchange with other projects.

             One pair of spacecraft, Tail Probe and its subsatellite S2-X (X for the first letter of the Russian word for ``Tail''), will be launched into the magnetospheric tail. The second pair, Auroral Probe and S2-A (A for ``Auroral''), will have an orbit that crosses the auroral oval to observe the acceleration of auroral particles and the flow of electric currents that connect the magnetospheric tail with the conducting ionosphere. To study the equilibrium tail structure, during about half of each year the Tail Probe pair will cross the main parts of the magnetotail every four days. The Auroral Probe pair will support the Tail Probe pair with auroral region measurements.

             Each main spacecraft has more than twenty scientific instruments. The spacecraft is cylindrical, with spin axis toward the sun (within 10 degrees), and with spin period of ~120 s. The electric and magnetic field sensors are on booms connected to the ends of the solar panels. The subsatellites are small, each with about ten scientific instruments. The spin axis will be directed within 10 degrees of the sun, with a spin period of ~120 s, as with the main spacecraft. The subsatellites also carry gas-jet thrusters for limited control of the orbit. Separation distance will range from hundreds of kilometers to several tens of thousands of kilometers for the Tail Probe pair. Separation distance will range from hundreds of meters to hundreds of kilometers for the Auroral Probe pair.

             The Tail Probe has two telemetry systems, at up to 32 Kbps in real-time, with a memory mode capacity of 30 Mb in the RTK telemetry system and 120 Mb in the SSNI system. The Auroral Probe has similar capability plus the additional real-time-only STO system, capable of 40 Kbps. Each subsatellite has only the STO real-time telemetry system. For S2-X the rate can be varied from 2--40 kbps. The Tail Probe has an adapting alert mode while in the memory mode, allowing time resolutions that are the same as in the real-time mode. The aim is to have the highest time resolution available at the thin borders of magnetospheric regions or the sharp borders of some features. In the alert mode (triggered by an on-board computer monitoring plasma and field parameters), the bit rate is increased for plasma, field, and wave measurements. The duration of these alert periods is about 10 minutes, and there can be 5--6 of them during one orbit.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Jan.Merka</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>Interball Project</Name>
        <URL>http://www.iki.rssi.ru/interball/</URL>
        <Description>Interball project home page at IKI RSSI.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/spacecraft/display.action?id=1995-039A</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Interball Tail Probe mission</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <ObservatoryGroupID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Interball-Tail</ObservatoryGroupID>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Heliosphere.NearEarth</ObservatoryRegion>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Magnetosheath</ObservatoryRegion>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere</ObservatoryRegion>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Main</ObservatoryRegion>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Polar</ObservatoryRegion>
</Location>
</Observatory>
<Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Interball-1/RF15I</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Solar X-ray Bursts (RF-15I)</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The RF-15I instrument is designed to study solar flare X-ray radiation with emphasis on flare energetics. It consists of two parts: soft and hard X-ray photometer observing the whole disk solar emission with high time resolution; and solar soft X-ray imager KRF (Rotating Modulation Collimator) called the tomograph.
The detectors nominally point toward the Sun. The spacecraft spin axis is to be repointed towards the centre of the solar disk each time it move more than 10 degrees from the Sun due to motion of the Earth around the Sun. One satellite revolution takes about 118 seconds.
The soft and hard X-ray photometer has two detector systems:&lt;br&gt; &lt;sp&gt;(1) A proportional argon gas-filled (350 Torr) detector of aperture 4.5 mm**2 with a Be filter of 150 mm thickness. The largest cross-sectional area of the detector for gamma radiation is 10.5 cm**2. This detector nominally registers the soft X-ray solar flux in the three energy channels 2-3-5-8 keV every 2 seconds.&lt;br&gt; &lt;sp&gt;(2) A Na(I) scintillation detector of 15.2 cm**2 aperture and crystal thickness 8 mm. This detector registers every 0.125 seconds the hard X-ray flux in five energy bands 10-15-30-60-120-240 keV provided that appropriate rate thresholds are exceeded in each of the upper four energy ranges. In the lowest energy range 10-15 keV, the data are collected every 2 seconds simultaneously with the softer proportional detector channels.
The tomograph images solar flare emission in two energy bands 2-4 keV and 4-8 keV by means of the numerical reconstruction of the soft X-ray signal modulated by the collimator due to the rotation of the satellite.
The signals coming from both low and high energy channels are processed in real time by the onboard PRAM computer and the decision is made whether to store the modulated signal (about 10 kbytes) to memory for image reconstruction on the ground. If so, before being stored, the information is compressed and periods when the source is outside narrow fields of view are discarded. About 80 images can be stored between telemetry dumps. Generally the intention is that for each flare of the GOES class above C5, at least one sequence of modulated signal will be recorded, usually at the flare maximum when the time variation of the signal influences the image restoration process least. Average unmodulated signals from both energy channels are recorded once per revolution. The data gather time unit is 1/128 s for the X-ray detector while outside the radiation belts. During belt crossing the detector high voltage is turned off.
The web pages at http://www.cbk.pan.wroc.pl/RF15-I_www/default.htm provide more information on the instrument and also access to the data</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/O.Likin</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039A&amp;ex=11</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Solar X-ray Bursts (RF-15I) experiment on the Interball Tail Probe mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Photometer</InstrumentType>
    <InstrumentType>Imager</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Solar X-ray Bursts (RF-15I) on Interball Tail Probe</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Interball-1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Interball-1/DOK2</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Energetic Proton/Electron Spectrometer DOK-2</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The study of energetic particle acceleration and transport within the magnetosphere and on its boundaries is the main goal of this experiment. Two particle spectrometers: DOK-2 and its small version DOK-2S were installed on the main satellite and small subsatellite. The DOK-2 experiments on the Tail and Auroral Probes of INTERBALL continue the studies of energetic particle population on Prognoz 10 in 1985 (Intershock project). Due to much higher energy, angular and time resolution, and better separation of electrons and ions, it is expected that the DOK-2 experiment will allow to re-examine in more detail the energetic particle population and related processes in magnetosphere regions covered by the spacecraft orbit.
DOK-2 uses two pairs of energetic particle telescopes. Each telescope has a single, passively cooled, totally depleted, surface-barrier silicon detector. One detector of each pair (1e, 2e) is of 0.3 mm thick. Thin foil in front of the detector absorbs protons with energies E &lt; 400 keV so this detector measures electron spectrum in 20 - 420 keV range. The second detector (1p, 2p) of 0.15 mm thick is supplied with a broom magnet, deflecting electrons up to 1500 keV. It measures the spectrum of ions (protons) in 20-850 keV range. Full aperture angles and geometric factors of electron telescopes are 27 degrees and 0.066 cm2*sr. For proton telescopes these values are 12.7 degrees and 0.015 cm2*sr. Particle flux angular distribution is measured using spacecraft rotation with a ~2-minute period around the axis directed to the Sun and mechanical scanning of the second telescope pair in a plane containing the rotation axis. So a 3-dimensional particle distribution function is measured during each 2-minute rotation period. About seven full scanning cycles are carried out for every rotation. The first detector pair (1e, 1p) is fixed in the antisolar direction. The moving detector pair (2e, 2p) can either scan from 45 to 180 degrees (to the Sun direction) or stay in one of 4 positions: 45, 90, 135 and 180 degrees.
Analog electronics for each of 4 detectors consists of a charge sensitive preamplifier (in a cooled part of the instrument), a shaping pulse amplifier and 56-57 channel amplitude analyser AA (logarithmic ADC). The measurements base is formed of "elementary measurement" (EM) - one full 56-57 channel spectrum measured every 1 second for each of 4 telescopes. This information is available only during the most informative Real Time mode of DOK-2. In storing modes there are two kinds of output information formed from EM's: (1) full 56-57 channel spectra accumulated during time intervals from 10 to 1464 seconds depending on particle intensity; and (2) three time profile (TP) parameters for each detector. TP parameters are counting rates in 3 narrow (&lt;30%) energy intervals from about 20 to 132 keV. An accumulation time for TP is variable in basic Monitoring modes (1-260 seconds). It depends on the variability of particle intensities. A special algorithm ensures time resolution of 1 second when the intensity change is statistically valuable. In Fast modes the accumulation time interval is &lt;1 second.
The mechanical scanning occurs only in Fast and Real Time modes. Transition from Monitoring to more informative Fast modes occurs automatically when particle flux variability is high enough or after a sharp increase of fluxes. Return to Monitoring mode is also automatic.
Spectrometer DOK-2 was switched on 5 hours after the launch on 3 August, 1995, and operates continuously except 3-4 hours switched off in the radiation belts once on each orbit. In-flight calibrations show that the energy resolution of the detectors is 5-7 keV. Some problems existed with the 2e-detector ADC, which was blocked from 11 November, 1995 to 31 December, 1995 and from 3 March, 1996 until today. From 1 November, 1995 the moving detector pair stay at 62 degrees. All other systems, both hardware and software, are working normally. DOK-2 has a WWW site at http://www.iki.rssi.ru/interball/dok.html.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Karel.Kudela</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039A&amp;ex=10</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Energetic Proton/Electron Spectrometer DOK-2 experiment on the Interball Tail Probe mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Energetic Proton/Electron Spectrometer DOK-2 on Interball Tail Probe</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Interball-1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Interball-1/PRAM</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Adaptive Processing of Wave Information (PRAM)</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The PRAM instrument on the Interball Tail Probe is a digital waveform processor unit. According to the mode of operation, the on-board algorithm performs the selection between amplificatioin ranges, averaging of DC field and filter data, decimation of the AC data and formatting of the telemetry frames. Frames are transmitted to the digital telemetry system. Burst modes, switched on by the event selection algorithym, are possible with a buffer size equivalent to about 4 minutes of the prehistory information in the fastest mode.
Fields and waves are measured on the Tail Probe by the ASPI consortium of experiments, which includes: MIF-M -- fluxgate and search-coil magnetometers; FGM-I -- triaxial fluxgate sensor and plasma current sensor; OPERA -- a complex of electric field instruments; and PRAM -- the digital waveform processor unit. Two more ASPI instruments, ADS and IFPE, failed to switch on, likely due to hardware problems.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Stanislav.A.Romanov</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039A&amp;ex=16</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Adaptive Processing of Wave Information (PRAM) experiment on the Interball Tail Probe mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>WaveformReceiver</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Adaptive Processing of Wave Information (PRAM) on Interball Tail Probe</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Interball-1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Interball-1/SOSNA3</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Dosimetric measurements SOSNA-3</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This instrument makes dosimetric measurements.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/V.Bengin</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039A&amp;ex=21</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Dosimetric measurements SOSNA-3 experiment on the Interball Tail Probe mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Unspecified</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Dosimetric measurements SOSNA-3 on Interball Tail Probe</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Interball-1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Interball-1/VDP</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Omnidirectional Plasma Sensor Faraday Cups (VDP)</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The VDP instrument was designed for determination of the integral flux vector or integral energetic spectrum over the range 0.2 - 2.4 keV of ions or electrons of magnetospheric plasma. The instrument includes 6 identical Faraday cups. Cup #1 is directed toward the Sun; its main axis lies along the spacecraft spin axis (+X). Cup #6 has antisunward direction (-X). Cups #2 - #5 are directed along +Y, +Z, -Y, -Z spacecraft axes respectively. Each cup has a field of view of 134 degrees full angle.
The positive grid (C2) and negative grid (C3) are used to select ion or elecron measurement. In case of constant voltage, the sensor supplies the total flux of ions plus the flux of electrons above 2400 eV energy, or the total flux of electrons plus the flux of ions above 2400 eV energy. To get ion or electron spectra the voltage of C2 or C3 is changed step by step over 16 steps in the range 0 - 2400 V. Cup #1 does not have negative grid and supplies the ion flux plus electron flux with energy more then 170 eV.
The maximum data rate is 16 samples per second. In the case of measuring spectra, one step is held during one second and a full spectrum takes 16 seconds. The output range of the direct current amplifier is -6.0 to + 6.0 V. The flux can be calculated as P = V * 0.43E+9 1/cm*cm*s. The minimum digitised flux is 6.0E+5 1/cm*cm*s and the maximum is 2.6E+9 1/cm*cm*s.
The VDP instrument began operating August 14, 1995. Faraday cups #4 and #6 have problems and are not in use.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Jana.Safrankova</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039A&amp;ex=3</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Omnidirectional Plasma Sensor Faraday Cups (VDP) experiment on the Interball Tail Probe mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>FaradayCup</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Omnidirectional Plasma Sensor Faraday Cups (VDP) on Interball Tail Probe</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Interball-1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Interball-1/Ephemeris</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Interball-1 Orbit</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>Interball-1 Ephemeris</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2009-05-20T21:10:11Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>Interball Tail orbital and attitude modeling</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Victoria.I.Prokhorenko</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Jan.Merka</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>IKI Satellite Situation Center</Name>
        <URL>http://www.iki.rssi.ru/vprokhor/</URL>
        <Description>This page maintains the Situation Analysis for the IKI International Space Missions and its coordination with the Inter-Agency multimission campaigns.</Description>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Platform</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Spacecraft position</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Interball-1</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Interball-1/RKI2</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Hard ionizing radiation and solar UV radiation RKI-2</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This instrument measures ionizing radiation at 5, 15, 40, 100, and 500 MeV, and UV radiation from the Sun.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Tamara.V.Kazachevskaya</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039A&amp;ex=20</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Hard ionizing radiation and solar UV radiation RKI-2 experiment on the Interball Tail Probe mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Unspecified</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Hard ionizing radiation and solar UV radiation RKI-2 on Interball Tail Probe</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Interball-1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Interball-1/SKA1</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>3D Ion Distribution (SKA-1) (EU-1)</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The fast plasma analyzer EU-1 of the SCA-1 complex plasma spectrometer provides fast three-dimensional measurements of the ion distribution function. The EU-1 ion spectrometer with virtual aperture consists of two detectors with 16 E/Q narrow-angle analyzers and electrostatic scanners. This configuration allows the measurement of the ion distribution function in three dimensions (over 15 logarithmically-spaced energy steps in the range 50 eV/Q - 5.0 keV/Q) in 64 directions in 7.5 seconds, which makes it independent of the slow rotation speed (period about 2 minutes) of the satellite. The FWHM of the energy passband is about 10 %. Both 15-step and 30-step energy scans are used in different modes of the instrument. One analyzer, EU-1/1, has its field of view pointed along the spin axis toward the Sun, while the other, EU-1/2, is oriented in the opposite, antisolar direction.
Due to memory and telemetry limits, the full information capacity of SCA-1 can be used only along a limited part of the satellite trajectory, and the rest of the orbit is covered by slow modes. The typical data rate from EU-1 in fast mode is 256 bytes/second.
Modes are selected by telecommand, as a result of internal data processing, or by alert signals from other instruments (IMAP, ELECTRON, PRAM, OPERA, DOK, VDP). Turning on the accelerated mode from a slow mode occurs if one of the instruments gives an unconditional alert signal or if three or more instruments give conditional alert signals.
The instrument is described in detail in the paper by Vaisberg et al. in Ann. Geophysicae 15, 570-586 (1997), which is available online at the following URL:&lt;br&gt; http://www.copernicus.org/EGU/annales/15/ag15/570.pdf [EOB]</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Oleg.L.Vaisberg</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039A&amp;ex=1</URL>
        <Description>Information about the 3D Ion Distribution (SKA-1) (EU-1) experiment on the Interball Tail Probe mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Unspecified</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>3D Ion Distribution (SKA-1) (EU-1) on Interball Tail Probe</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Interball-1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Interball-1/PROMICS3</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Ion Composition 3D Spectrometer (PROMICS-3)</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>PROMICS-3 is a plasma experiment and performs three-dimensional measurements of ions in the energy range 4 eV to 70 keV with mass separation (M = 1 - 32), and of electrons in the energy range 12 eV to 35 keV. The instrument uses toroidal electrostatic analyzers. MEPS is the electron spectrometer, and TRICS is the ion mass spectrometer.
Interball Tail Probe and Interball Auroral Probe both carry identical PROMICS-3 instruments, thus facilitating direct comparisons of the particle distributions.
See the web page at http://www.irf.se/rpg/interball.html for further information.
PROMICS-3 Tail was one of the first instruments to measure the three-dimensional ion distribution function in the high latitude boundary layer regions of the magnetosphere.
The PROMICS-3 instrument was developed in cooperation between the Swedish Institute of Space Physics (IRF), the Finnish Meteorological Institute (FMI) and the Space Research Institute, Moscow (IKI). The major part of the hardware of PROMICS-3 was designed and built at IRF in Kiruna. Much of the electronics was built in Finland by FMI, Hollming OY, and VTT.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Ingrid.Sandahl</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039A&amp;ex=8</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Ion Composition 3D Spectrometer (PROMICS-3) experiment on the Interball Tail Probe mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>MassSpectrometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Ion Composition 3D Spectrometer (PROMICS-3) on Interball Tail Probe</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Interball-1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Interball-1/OPERA</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Measurements of Electric Field in Range 0 to 250 KHz (OPERA)</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>OPERA is an electric field experiment designed to measure Ex, Ey, Ez from DC to 200 kHz. OPERA (Onde de Plasma E Radiazioni Aurorali) is part of the ASPI complex devoted to the study of plasma waves. The ASPI package is made up of OPERA itself, the MIF-M experiment (95-039A-13) for magnetic field fluctuations (a fluxgate and two search coils), and the IFPE (95-039A-14) which studies the particle density fluctuations by means of three Faraday cups. Other parts of the ASPI complex are PRAM (95-039A-16), which is a data processor, and ADS (95-039A-15), which is a sort of spectrum analyzer.
The electric field along 3 axes is measured by detecting the potential differences among probe pairs located at the end of long booms that constitute 3 dipoles of 22, 4.4, and 4.4 m, respectively. All the probes are far away from the spacecraft, which is very important in order to minimize spacecraft electromagnetic contamination. Each probe is made of a sphere of aluminum painted with a special conductive carbon colloidal (graphite). The 6 signals are sent to 3 differential amplifiers from which 3 outputs are obtained: the quasi-static electric field DC to 0.2 Hz in 3 components; the potential of each probe with respect to the spacecraft ground; and the 3 AC signals 0.2 Hz to 200 kHz. These last signals are handled in different ways: three bandpass filters (0.2 - 32 Hz) to measure the waveform; a wideband filter 10 - 1000 Hz; and a bank of six filters, each capable of covering 4 adjacent frequency bands. Aside from the data sent directly to the digital telemetry, six channels are provided to the analog telemetry: the DC electric field components and the waveform components.
The DC electric field sensitivity is 0.25 to 5 mV/m, depending on gain and dipole length. The waveform measurement sensitivity ranges from 1 to 0.1 mV/m Hz^0.5 for 0.1 - 32 Hz signals. For the 10-1000 Hz channel, at 10 Hz with a gain of 1 it is 1 to 0.03 mV/m Hz^0.5. At 1000 Hz with gain 10, it is .1 to 3E-3 mV/m Hz^0.5. For the AC signals (10 Hz - 200 kHz) the sensitivity is 1E-8 V/m Hz^0.5 with high gain, and 20 dB less with low gain.
The overall dynamical range for both DC electric field and waveform measurements is +635 to -640 mV/m. The AC dynamical range is 80 dB. Nominal accuracy for all measurements is 2 %.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Ermanno.Amata</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Sergey.Savin</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039A&amp;ex=12</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Measurements of Electric Field in Range 0 to 250 KHz (OPERA) experiment on the Interball Tail Probe mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Antenna</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Measurements of Electric Field in Range 0 to 250 KHz (OPERA) on Interball Tail Probe</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Interball-1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Interball-1/AMEI2</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Energy-Mass Analyzer (AMEI-2)</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The low energy plasma composition spectrometer AMEI-2 is built to be able to find in the low energy range of the phase space (E, q, j) and separate the fluxes of the major ion species in the magnetotail (H+, He++, He+ and O+), and analyse their energy and angular distributions. It scans an energy range 0.3 - 10 keV/q, respectively (m/q)*(E/q) = 0.3 - 160 a.m.u.*keV/q2. Masses m/q =1,2,4 and 16 are measured simultaneously. Energy bandpass is about 20%. Electrostatic angular scanning in one direction and the use of the spin of the satellite to sample the other angle give the ability to measure 2-D distributions for each ion specie several times per spin. Onboard identification of ion mass and flexible information capacities are provided.
The measurement cycle of the instrument is controlled by the "top of spin" signal and the 1/1024 part of spin period signals, produced by the BNS instrument. The 4pi solid angle is separated into three parts: a solar cone with angle 80 degrees; an antisolar cone with angle of 44 degrees; and a band (+25, -40 degrees) perpendicular to the spin axis. The deflection voltages necessary to measure 210 energy-angular steps and mass spectra are programmed in the microcomputer. Sets of 128, 64 or 32 energy-angular steps can be selected by ground commands. The measurement cycle consists of an angular scan in a given cone for one set of energies, and then the scans for the same sequence of energies are made for other angular ranges. In slow modes, measurements at each energy-angular step can be integrated over different ranges of azimuth angle, i.e. data obtained at each step for several measurement cycles are summed.
AMEI-2 is a joint Bulgarian-Russian instrument, developed and manufactured by STILL-BAS, Sofia and IKI-RAN, Moscow. The instrument began operating August 17, 1995 after the BNS system was switched on in automatic mode. There are some quota problems due to failure in the flag circuit to SSNI information system. Though the instrument was designed for measurements in the tail, some events of ion beams in the magnetosheath have been observed.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Rositza.T.Koleva</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039A&amp;ex=6</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Energy-Mass Analyzer (AMEI-2) experiment on the Interball Tail Probe mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>MassSpectrometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Energy-Mass Analyzer (AMEI-2) on Interball Tail Probe</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Interball-1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Interball-1/ELECTRON</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>3D Electron Distribution Function (ELECTRON)</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The objective of the ELECTRON experiment is to perform 3-D measurements of the plasma electrons in the energy range from 10 eV to 26 keV, with good angular resolution, sensitivity and large dynamical range. The instrument was designed, built and calibrated by the Centre d'Etudes Spatiales des Rayonnements (CNRS/ University of Toulouse, France) and financed by a CNES (French National Space Center) grant. The integration tests were performed jointly with the Space Research Institute, Moscow (IKI).
The spectrometer consists of a quadri-spherical analyzer associated with microchannel plates. The analyser is a symmetrical "top hat" electrostatic analyzer which provides a 180 x 6 degree field of view with a uniform response. The angular resolution is 22.5 x 6 degrees. Electrons are multiplied by a chevron-mounted pair of MCP associated with 8 anode sectors. Due to the spacecraft rotation, the full 4 solid angle is scanned once per spin period (~120 seconds). The number of energy sweeps per spin can be changed, as well as the energy range, according to the mode of operation. The spectrometer can be operated in 15 main modes. Standard modes allow to obtain 32 energy spectra with 32 energies per spin; high speed modes can be used to quickly sweep 4 energies.
The ELECTRON experiment began operating August 14, 1995. It does not operate through the radiation belts. The detector has a very low background and a good sensitivity. The satellite apogee was located at midnight in November 1995.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Jean-Andre.C.Sauvaud</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039A&amp;ex=4</URL>
        <Description>Information about the 3D Electron Distribution Function (ELECTRON) experiment on the Interball Tail Probe mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>QuadrisphericalAnalyser</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>3D Electron Distribution Function (ELECTRON) on Interball Tail Probe</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Interball-1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Interball-1/AKR2</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Kilometric Radioemission 100 KHz - 1.5 MHz (AKR-2)</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The AKR-2 instrument records the intensity of electromagnetic emission in the frequency range of 100 - 1500 KHz in 6 frequency channels at 100, 250, 500, 750, 1000, and 1500 KHz. The width of each channel is about 10 KHz. The emission is received by the loop antenna with area of about 1.5 square meters. The antenna is shielded from the local electrostatic perturbations so that only electromagnetic modes of radiation are recorded. Maximum sensitivity is realized in the high-frequency channels. At the 750 KHz channel the instrument records minimum radiation flux of the order of 5.E-20 Wm**2Hz**-1.
The input signal is fed into a broadband amplifier with a built-in calibration noise source. In calibration mode (commanded once per day) the amplifier is switched periodically from the antenna to the noise source. The instrument operates continuous; there are no other commands for controlling the instrument.
Instrument mass is 2.8 kg and nominal power consumption is &lt;4 W.
The instrument is further described by Grigorieva et al. at pp. 233 - 238 of "Interball Mission and Payload," a joint RKA-IKI-CNES publication (1995).</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/L.Fischer</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039A&amp;ex=18</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Kilometric Radioemission 100 KHz - 1.5 MHz (AKR-2) experiment on the Interball Tail Probe mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Antenna</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Kilometric Radioemission 100 KHz - 1.5 MHz (AKR-2) on Interball Tail Probe</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Interball-1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Interball-1/MIFM</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Multicomponent Investigations of Fluctuations of Magnetic Fields (MIF-M)</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The MIF-M instrument on the Interball Tail Probe consists of triaxial fluxgate sensors (DC: 0 - 2 Hz and AC: 2 - 25 Hz), a search-coil measuring the AC magnetic field along the spacecraft Z-axis at 1 Hz - 40 kHz, and a filter bank with seven analog passband filters.
Fields and waves are measured on the Tail Probe by the ASPI consortium of experiments, which includes: MIF-M -- fluxgate and search-coil magnetometers; FGM-I -- triaxial fluxgate sensor and plasma current sensor; OPERA -- a complex of electric field instruments; and PRAM -- the digital waveform processor unit. Two more ASPI instruments, ADS and IFPE, failed to switch on, likely due to hardware problems.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Stanislav.A.Romanov</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039A&amp;ex=13</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Multicomponent Investigations of Fluctuations of Magnetic Fields (MIF-M) experiment on the Interball Tail Probe mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Multicomponent Investigations of Fluctuations of Magnetic Fields (MIF-M) on Interball Tail Probe</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Interball-1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Interball-1/CORALL</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Interball-1 Wide-range 3D Ion Spectrometer (CORALL)</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>CORALL is a hemispherical electrostatic ion energy spectrometer with a fan-shaped field-of-view of 10 x 150 degrees. Satellite rotation with period about 2 minutes enables one to perform quasi-3D measurements of the energy/charge ion distribution function in the range from 30 to 24200 eV/q in 32 steps. The accumulation time on 1 energy step is 1/1024-th of the satellite rotation period, i.e. about 100 msec, and the scan period of 1 energy spectrum (32 steps) is equal to about 4 minutes. Energy resolution is +/- 5%, and the separation of the energy channels is 24%. There are 5 polar channels, at angles of 45, 70, 95, 120, and 145 degrees from the sun. Angular resolution is +/- 25 degrees in the polar angle and +/- 5 degrees in the azimuthal angle.
            Instrument CORALL was designed and fabricated jointly by IKI RAN and INTERCOSMOS of the Republic of Cuba.
            The instrument began operating August 14, 1995. However, there were problems with the telemetry system BNS which provides satellite rotation pulses. CORALL uses this pulse for performance of measurements in the inertial coordinate system. As of August 31, 1995 the complex BNS + CORALL is operating properly.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Reynal.Jimenez</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039A-05</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Wide-range 3D Ion Spectrometer (CORALL) experiment on the Interball Tail Probe mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Wide-range 3D Ion Spectrometer (CORALL) on Interball Tail Probe</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Interball-1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Interball-1/FGMI</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Interball-1 Tri-axial Fluxgate Magnetometer FGM-I</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>MFI</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The FGM-I instrument on the Interball Tail Probe consists of a triaxial fluxgate magnetometer and a Langmuir split probe plasma current sensor. The analog signal is transmitted to the telemetry system and to the MIF-M filter bank.
            Fields and waves are measured on the Tail Probe by the ASPI consortium of experiments, which includes: MIF-M -- fluxgate and search-coil magnetometers; FGM-I -- triaxial fluxgate sensor and plasma current sensor; OPERA -- a complex of electric field instruments; and PRAM -- the digital waveform processor unit. Two more ASPI instruments, ADS and IFPE, failed to switch on, likely due to hardware problems.
            The FGMI magnetometer has the next parameters: measured range 0.3-37.5 nT, frequency range 0-2 Hz, sampling rate from 1/4 to 8 measurements per second.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/J.Rustenbach</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Sergey.Savin</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039A-19</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Tri-axial Fluxgate Magnetometer FGM-I experiment on the Interball Tail Probe mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Tri-axial Fluxgate Magnetometer FGM-I on Interball Tail Probe</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Interball-1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Interball-1/ALFA3</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Ion Trap (ALFA-3)</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The ALPHA-3 experiment is designed to study cold magnetospheric plasma, and identical instruments are installed on both Interball Tail and Interball Auroral Probe. The instrument uses planar electrostatic analyzers, with a planar modulating potential analyzer. The collector effective area is 11.3 square cm, and the range of current measurements is 1.E-13 to 1.3E-8 A. The energy range of the registered particles is 0 - 25.5 eV. The minimum measurable density of protons is 1 per cc for an ion temperature of 1.E4 K and for the analyzer directed along the velocity vector.
For more details, see the article by V. V. Bezrukikh and K. I. Gringauz at pp. 215 - 221 of "Interball Mission and Payload," a joint publication of RKA, IKI, and CNES (1995).</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/V.V.Bezrukikh</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039A&amp;ex=9</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Ion Trap (ALFA-3) experiment on the Interball Tail Probe mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>ElectrostaticAnalyser</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Ion Trap (ALFA-3) on Interball Tail Probe</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Interball-1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Interball-1/SKA2</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Low and Energetic Charged Particle Composition and Anisotropy (SKA-2)</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This instrument makes measurements of the solar wind ion fluxes and energy-angular distributions of H+ and He++ around the Sun direction with high time resolution.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/E.I.Morozova</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039A&amp;ex=2</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Low and Energetic Charged Particle Composition and Anisotropy (SKA-2) experiment on the Interball Tail Probe mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Low and Energetic Charged Particle Composition and Anisotropy (SKA-2) on Interball Tail Probe</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Interball-1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Interball-1/FM3I</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Fluxgate DC Magnetometer FM-3I</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The FM-3I instrument consists of two flux-gate magnetometers M1 and M2 covering two different ranges: -200 to +200 nT and -1000 to +1000 nT. The M2 instrument is mostly used to perform the attitude control of the INTERBALL 1 spacecraft. M1 magnetometer data are transmitted to the scientific SSNI telemetry system at rates 0.125-16 vectors/s depending on the instrument operating mode. The magnetic field data from the M2 magnetometer are transmitted at the rate 1 vector per 6 seconds to the BNS attitude control system.
     
FM-3 M2 magnetometer failed in February 1996.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Mikhail.Nozdrachev</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039A-17</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Fluxgate DC Magnetometer FM-3I experiment on the Interball Tail Probe mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Fluxgate DC Magnetometer FM-3I on Interball Tail Probe</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Interball-1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Interball-1/MONITOR3</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Solar Wind Analyzer (MONITOR-3)</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This instrument makes measurements of the solar wind ion fluxes and energy-angular distributions of H+ and He++ around the Sun direction with high time resolution.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Zdenek.Nemecek</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1995-039A&amp;ex=7</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Solar Wind Analyzer (MONITOR-3) experiment on the Interball Tail Probe mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Solar Wind Analyzer (MONITOR-3) on Interball Tail Probe</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Interball-1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Jana.Safrankova</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Jana Safrankova</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Charles University</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Ingrid.Sandahl</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Ingrid Sandahl</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Swedish Institute of Space Physics</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/O.Likin</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. O. Likin</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Academy of Sciences</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/E.I.Morozova</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. E. I. Morozova</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Russian Academy of Sciences</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Zdenek.Nemecek</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Zdenek Nemecek</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Charles University</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Rositza.T.Koleva</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Rositza T. Koleva</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Bulgarian Academy of Sciences</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Reynal.Jimenez</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Reynal Jimenez</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Academia de Ciencias de Cuba</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Sergey.Savin</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Sergey Savin</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Russian Academy of Sciences</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Stanislav.A.Romanov</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Stanislav A. Romanov</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Russian Academy of Sciences</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Karel.Kudela</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Mr. Karel Kudela</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Slovak Academy of Sciences</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/V.V.Bezrukikh</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. V. V. Bezrukikh</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Academy of Sciences</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Jean-Andre.C.Sauvaud</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Jean-Andre C. Sauvaud</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Center d Etudes Spatiales des Rayonnemen</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/V.Bengin</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. V. Bengin</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Institute of Biomedical Problems</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Mikhail.Nozdrachev</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Mikhail Nozdrachev</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Russian Academy of Sciences</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/L.Fischer</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. L. Fischer</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Comenius University</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Jan.Merka</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Jan Merka</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>NASA Goddard Space Flight Center</OrganizationName>
    <Address>Code 672, Greenbelt, MD 20771, USA</Address>
    <Email>jan.merka@nasa.gov</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+1 301 286 8751</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Victoria.I.Prokhorenko</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Victoria I. Prokhorenko</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Space Research Institute</OrganizationName>
    <Address>Space Research Institute, Russian Academy of Sciences, ul. Profsouznaya, 84/32, Moscow, 117997, RUSSIA</Address>
    <Email>vprokhor@iki.rssi.ru</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+7(095) 9361258</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Oleg.L.Vaisberg</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Oleg L. Vaisberg</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Russian Academy of Sciences</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Tamara.V.Kazachevskaya</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Tamara V. Kazachevskaya</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Institute of Applied Geophysics</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/J.Rustenbach</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. J. Rustenbach</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Max Planck Institut fur Extraterrestrische Physik</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Ermanno.Amata</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Ermanno Amata</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Consiglio Nazionale delle Ricerche</OrganizationName>
  </Person></Spase>


