<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_3.xsd">
	<Version>2.2.3</Version>
	<Observatory>
		<ResourceID>spase://ASWS/Observatory/Ground/Darwin</ResourceID>
		<ResourceHeader>
			<ResourceName>Darwin</ResourceName>
			<AlternateName>None</AlternateName>
  			<ReleaseDate>2020-09-28T18:31:52Z</ReleaseDate>
			<Description>Darwin station is located in Darwin, NT. It has been in operation since December 1982.</Description>
			<Acknowledgement>Please acknowledge: Space Weather Network, Bureau of Meteorology, Australia</Acknowledgement>
			<Contact>
				<PersonID>spase://ASWS/Person/Kehe.Wang</PersonID>
				<Role>GeneralContact</Role>
				<Role>DataProducer</Role>
			</Contact>
			<Contact>
				<PersonID>spase://ASWS/Person/Kehe.Wang</PersonID>
				<Role>MetadataContact</Role>
			</Contact>
                	<InformationURL>
                  		<Name>ASWS Observatory Information: Darwin</Name>
        		     	<URL>http://www.sws.bom.gov.au/World_Data_Centre/2/1/3</URL>
       				<Description>includes observatory/station name, location, lifetime, identity and datasets informtion.</Description>
       				<Language>en</Language>
      			</InformationURL>
		</ResourceHeader>
		<Location>
			<ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Surface</ObservatoryRegion>
			<Latitude>-12.45</Latitude>
			<Longitude>130.95E</Longitude>
		</Location>
		<OperatingSpan>
			<StartDate>1982-12-01T00:00:00.000</StartDate>
		</OperatingSpan>
	</Observatory>
<Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://ASWS/Instrument/Ground/Darwin/Magnetometer</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Darwin Magnetometer</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2017-07-21T17:20:00Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Darwin Magnetometer station in Darwin, NT, Australia, has a Magnetometer since August 2000. 
      
        30 August, 2000
	---------------
	Installation of magnetometer VM3:
	Magnetometer enclosure was clean and dry. Magnetometer PC was setup under the bench underneath the Comms PC (tried setting up in the corner of the station hut but the ethernet cable wasn't long enough). The monitor didnt work with the magnetometer (rack mount) PC so it the monitor was swapped with the COMMS PC monitor which did work (magnetometer monitor worked with COMMS PC).  The magnetometer recording system PC then tested OK. The GPS unit was attached using an adaptor to a long piece of PVC piping. The piping was secured to the side of the building with the GPS antenna extending up above the roof of the building ~0.5 m's. The cable was run through the pipe and an existing entry point into the building. The entry point was sealed with silastic to stop intruders. The signal from the antenna was connected to the GPS-200 unit and tested to see if the date and time of the PC were being corrected properly. The date/time correction was functioning properly. The magnetometer signal cable was connected into the signal junction box. The bayonet connector was fitted at the enclosure end of the cable and the cable inlet to the enclosure was sealed with silastic. The magnetometer was placed in the enclosureand connected to test if sensible voltages could be measured coming from the instrument, which was found to be the case. The magnetometer was removed from the enclosure and stored in the building overnight. The acquisition software was on the COMMS PC was upgraded to Version 1.1.

	For more information, please read its log file.     
      </Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://ASWS/Person/Kehe.Wang</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>ASWS Darwin Instrument Fluxgate Magenetometer Log File</Name>
	<URL>ftp://ftp-out.sws.bom.gov.au/wdc/wdc_mag/data/dwn/stn.log</URL>
	<Description>Includes Darwin magnetometer log file.</Description>
	<Language>en</Language>
      </InformationURL>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Darwin Magnetometer</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://ASWS/Observatory/Ground/Darwin</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
      <ResourceID>spase://ASWS/Instrument/Ground/Darwin/Ionosonde</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>Darwin Ionosonde</ResourceName>
         <ReleaseDate>2019-05-01T12:34:56.789Z</ReleaseDate>
         <Description>The Darwin Ionosonde station near Darwin, NT, Australia, has ionosondes since 10 December 1982. According to the SWS archived Weekly Station Summary, the first ionosonde was an IPS 4B ionosonde with 16 mm film since 10/12/1982 to 06/10/1995. There was an IPS 4D digital ionosonde between 24/08/1994 and 27/11/2002, an IPS 5C between 16/05/1995 and 31/10/1998, and a CADI in June 1999 for only 4 days. There is an IPS 5D since 30/06/1999 to now. The IPS 5D vertical sounding ionosonde normally sweeps in frequency from about 1.0 to 21.5 MHz. Frequency step resolution for the 5D is 5 kHz, with up to 4095 steps available. The step interval is variable, becoming more coarse at higher frequencies as ionograms are generally displayed on a logarithmic scale.</Description>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://ASWS/Person/Kehe.Wang</PersonID>
            <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Lee.Frost.Bargatze</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
      </ResourceHeader>
      <InstrumentType>Radar</InstrumentType>
      <InvestigationName>Darwin Ionosonde</InvestigationName>
      <ObservatoryID>spase://ASWS/Observatory/Ground/Darwin</ObservatoryID>
   </Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
      <ResourceID>spase://ASWS/Instrument/Ground/Darwin/Ionospheric_Scintillation_Monitor</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>Darwin Ionospheric Scintillation Monitor</ResourceName>
         <ReleaseDate>2019-05-01T12:34:56.789Z</ReleaseDate>
         <Description>An Ionospheric Scintillation Monitor (ISM) is a single- or dual-frequency GPS receiver specifically designed to monitor ionospheric scintillation levels in real time. The ISM has wide-bandwidth tracking loops to maintain lock longer during intervals of strong ionospheric scintillation, and samples at a rate of 50 Hz to calculate the scintillation statistics S4 and Prms. The wide-bandwidth tracking improves tracking through strong scintillation however loss of lock on single or multiple satellites can still occur during extreme events, requiring re-acquisition of the GPS signal(s).

SWS Radio and Space Services uses GPS Silicon Valley's GPS Ionospheric Scintillation and TEC Monitor (GISTM) system Model GSV4004B to monitor Ionospheric Scintillation in real time. The GSV4004B consists of an L1/L2 GPS Antenna, a dual-frequency GPS receiver (NovAtel's Euro-3M with modified firmware), and a low phase noise oven-controlled crystal oscillator (OCXO), housed in NovAtel's EuroPak-3M enclosure. The OCXO is required for monitoring phase scintillation.

The primary purpose of the ISM system is to collect ionospheric scintillation statistics (S4 and Prms) for all visible GPS satellites (up to eleven satellites) and store these (ISMR) binary data logs on the receiver controller hard disk for post processing. The ISM control software can be programmed to collect the ISMR data logs that are generated every 1 minute. Alternatively, raw phase and amplitude data at 0.02 second temporal resolution (50 Hz) and code/carrier divergence at 1 s (1 Hz) can be recorded from the ISM. These data can be used to reconstruct the statistical scintillation indices, such as S4 recorded in the ISMR data log, from raw data. This allows the user to modify the parameters used in the derivation of scintillation indices, such as de-trending and filter cut-off parameters.

The Darwin Ionospheric Scintillation Monitor station near Darwin, NT, Australia, has a digital Ionospheric Scintillation Monitor GPS since June 2010.</Description>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://ASWS/Person/Kehe.Wang</PersonID>
            <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Lee.Frost.Bargatze</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <PriorID>spase://ASWS/Instrument/Ground/Darwin/Ionospheric_Scintillation_Monitor.xml</PriorID>
      </ResourceHeader>
      <InstrumentType>ScintillationDetector</InstrumentType>
      <InvestigationName>Darwin Ionospheric Scintillation Monitor</InvestigationName>
      <ObservatoryID>spase://ASWS/Observatory/Ground/Darwin</ObservatoryID>
   </Instrument><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://ASWS/Person/Kehe.Wang</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2017-06-28T17:03:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Kehe Wang</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Space Weather Services (SWS), Bureau of Meteorology, Australia</OrganizationName>
    <Email>kehe.wang@bom.gov.au</Email>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
      <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Lee.Frost.Bargatze</ResourceID>
      <ReleaseDate>2012-06-13T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
      <PersonName>Lee Frost Bargatze</PersonName>
      <OrganizationName>Institute of Geophysics and Planetary Physics and the Department of Earth and Space Sciences, University of California, Los Angeles</OrganizationName>
      <Address>Institute of Geophysics and Planetary Physics, University of California Los Angeles, Box 951567, Los Angeles, CA 90095-1567</Address>
      <Email>lfb@igpp.ucla.edu</Email>
      <PhoneNumber>+1 310 206 6073</PhoneNumber>
   </Person></Spase>


