<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.0</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/CRRES</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>CRRES</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>1990-065A</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>Combined Release and Radiation Effects Satellite</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Combined Release and Radiation Effects Satellite (CRRES) was launched into a geosynchronous
   transfer orbit (GTO) for a nominal three-year mission to investigate fields, plasmas, and energetic particles
   inside the Earth's magnetosphere. As part of the CRRES program the SPACERAD (Space Radiation Effects) project,
   managed by Air Force Geophysics Laboratory, investigated the radiation environment of the inner and outer
   radiation belts and measured radiation effects on state-of-the-art microelectronics devices. Other
   magnetospheric, ionospheric, and cosmic ray experiments were included onboard CRRES and supported by NASA or
   the Office of Naval Research. The chemical release project was managed by NASA/MSFC and utilized the release of
   chemicals from onboard cannisters at low altitudes near dawn and dusk perigee times and at high altitudes near
   local midnight. The chemical releases were monitored with optical and radar instrumentation by ground-based
   observers to measure the bulk properties and movement of the expanding clouds of photo-ionized plasma along
   field lines after the releases occurred. In order to study the magnetosphere at different local times during
   the mission, the satellite orbit was designed to precess with respect to the earth-sun line such that the local
   time at apogee decreased by 2.5 minutes/day from 08:00 (LT) just after launch and returned to this position in
   nineteen-month cycles. The CRRES spacecraft had the shape of an octagonal prism with solar arrays on the top
   side. The prism is 1 m high and 3 m between opposite faces. Four of the eight compartments were for the chemical
   canisters and the other four housed SPACERAD and other experiments. The spacecraft body was spun at 2.2 rpm about
   a spin axis in the ecliptic plane and kept pointed about 12 degrees ahead of the Sun's apparent motion in
   celestial coordinates. Pre-launch and in-flight operations were supported by the Space Test and Transportation
   Program Office of the U.S. Air Force Space Division. Contact with the CRRES spacecraft was lost on October 12,
   1991 and was presumed to be due to onboard battery failure.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Susan.Gussenhoven-Shea</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/David.L.Reasoner</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/spacecraft/display.action?id=1990-065A</URL>
        <Description>Information about the CRRES mission</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Journal of Spacecraft and Rockets Article</Name>
  <URL>https://arc.aiaa.org/doi/10.2514/3.55641</URL>
  <Description>Detailed information on the CRRES mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Magnetosphere.Main</ObservatoryRegion>
</Location>
</Observatory>
<Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/CRRES/RPD</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Relativistic Proton Detector</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This experiment package was changed before launch and then became a group of Cerenkov and solid-state silicon sensors based on earlier Pioneer 10/11 experiments (NSSDC ID 72-012A-05 and 73-019A-05). It was designed to measure energetic electrons above 200 keV and higher energy electrons and protons in trapped radiation belts. The two Cerenkov sensors employed alcohol-water and fused-silica radiators, viewed by photomultiplier tubes, with respective refractive indices of 4/3 and 3/2 and with corresponding proton energy thresholds of 440 and 320 MeV. These sensors were also sensitive to electrons above 7-8 MeV. An electron scatter sensor measured electrons above 200 keV by using a V-shaped brass collimator and a gold aperture plug to guide scattered electrons into the silicon E detector. A similar detector (M) behind E was heavily shielded and responded to penetrating electrons above 35 MeV and protons above 80 MeV. A photometer system was also included in this package to view GTO chemical releases and measured narrow-band emissions from lithium, barium, and europium in four wavelength channels simultaneously using a split-anode microchannel plate photomultiplier tube. This experiment was part of the SPACERAD project sponsored by AFGL.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Wojciech.A.Kolasinski</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/E.Gary.Mullen</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1990-065A&amp;ex=13</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Relativistic Proton Detector experiment on the CRRES mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Relativistic Proton Detector on CRRES</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/CRRES</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/CRRES/Ephemeris</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>CRRES Spacecraft Position</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>CRRES Ephemeris</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2010-02-24T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>CRESS spacecraft position information</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Lee.Frost.Bargatze</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
      </Contact>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Platform</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Spacecraft position</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/CRRES</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/CRRES/MICS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Magnetospheric Ion Composition Sensor</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Magnetospheric Ion Composition Sensor (MICS) was part of the Mass Composition Instruments group which measured mass and energy/Q spectra of magnetospheric ions in the range 40 eV/Q to 15 MeV per ion to identify mechanisms that could energize charged particles and transport them from their parent populations in the magnetosphere. MICS measured mass and energy/Q spectra of ions in the range 30 to 400 keV/Q. This sensor consisted of a conically shaped electrostatic energy analyzer (EES) and a time-of-flight (TOF) analyzer. The EES specified the energy/charge of the incident ion and the TOF provided the speed. Together they enabled determination of the energy spectrum for each mass up to 56 amu. After passing through the EES, an ion would pass through a thin carbon foil and then through another carbon foil at the end of the flight path. The secondary electrons emitted by the foils provided the time of flight and hence the speed. The field of view was a 2-deg cone, at an angle of 90 deg from the spin axis of the satellite. The energy resolution was 10% at each energy and the geometric factor was 1.0E-2 sq cm-sr. The sensitivity ranged from single particle events to a flux of 5.E7 particles/(sq cm-sr-s). This experiment was part of the SPACERAD project sponsored by AFGL.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Berend.Wilken</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/E.Gary.Mullen</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1990-065A&amp;ex=16</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Magnetospheric Ion Composition Sensor experiment on the CRRES mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Magnetospheric Ion Composition Sensor on CRRES</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/CRRES</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/CRRES/MEA</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Medium Electron Sensor</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Medium Electron Sensor, also called MEA or Sensor A, was one of the two parts of the Medium Energy Electron Spectrometer and measured the temporal, spectral, and directional variations of the electron fluxes at approximate energies of 100-2000 KeV. This sensor consisted of a 0.085 T magnet assembly, a tungsten collimator, 18 lithium-drifted solid-state detectors placed in the focal plane of the 180 degree focusing magnet, shielding, Indox V pole pieces, and both internal and external disk-loaded collimators. The internal collimators prevented scattered particles from being measured and, along with the external collimators, defined the acceptance angle for the instrument. The acceptance angle in the horizontal direction (parallel to the pole piece faces) was +/-11 degrees and independent of energy. In the vertical direction the angle varied with energy; it was +/-11 degrees for the lowest energy channel (46.8-107 KeV) and dropped to +/-3 degrees for the highest energy channel (2100-2200 KeV). The 15 energy channels between these extremes provided a Delta-E/E starting at about 0.5 and decreased with energy to about 0.06. The final counter was shielded to provide a background measurement for protons and bremsstrahlung. The geometric factors, in units of mm**2-sr-KeV, varied with energy, starting at 4.74 for the first, or lowest, energy channel, peaking at 5.67 for the third energy channel, and falling monotonically to 2.15 for the highest energy channel. The aperture was perpendicular to the spin axis of the spacecraft with the horizontal direction pointing along the spin axis. This experiment was part of the SPACERAD project sponsored by AFGL.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Alfred.L.Vampola</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/E.Gary.Mullen</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1990-065A&amp;ex=10</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Medium Electron Sensor experiment on the CRRES mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Medium Electron Sensor on CRRES</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/CRRES</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/CRRES/PT</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Proton Telescope</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This instrument measured protons in the energy range 1 to 100 MeV. It consisted of two separate sensor units and a data processing unit. The low-energy sensor head (LE) measured 1 - 9 MeV protons in eight contiguous energy channels and the high-energy sensor head (HE) measured 6 - 100 MeV protons in 16 channels. The entire energy spectrum was obtained each second. Both heads had passive shielding, a collimator made of aluminum and tungsten, an electron sweeping magnet with a field strength of 0.5 T, and a silicon detector stack. The acceptance angles (FWHM) were 9.53 and 16.7 deg for the low- and high-energy units, respectively. The magnets removed up to 4- and 8-MeV electrons, respectively. The low-energy sensor used five surface barrier detectors in the stack. The back detector was used behind some additional shielding to fix the highest energy channel. The high-energy unit used five lithium-drifted silicon detectors with guard rings to reject penetrating particles and one surface barrier detector. The last detector was used in anticoincidence to define the upper energy channel. This experiment was part of the SPACERAD project sponsored by AFGL.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Michael.D.Violet</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/E.Gary.Mullen</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1990-065A&amp;ex=15</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Proton Telescope experiment on the CRRES mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Proton Telescope on CRRES</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/CRRES</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/CRRES/EPAS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Electron-Proton-Angle-Spectrometer</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Electron-Proton-Angle Spectrometer (EPAS) was one of the two parts of the Medium Energy Electron Spectrometer and measured electrons in the energy range of 16-300 keV and protons in the range of 20-3300 keV. EPAS, also called MEB or Sensor B, was composed of two identical units each consisting of a collimator, a focusing magnet assembly, a support structure, five solid-state detectors in the focal curve of the magnet assembly for electron detection, and two 2-element solid-state telescopes viewing the collimator through the magnetic field for ion (mainly proton) detection. The magnetic field was homogeneous over most of the volume defined by the pole pieces with a strength of about 0.08 T. The magnetic field geometry was such that electrons of all energies between 16 and 300 keV were deflected through about 180 deg and focused at a point corresponding to the entrance angle of the electron. The five detectors provided five angular intervals within the 60-deg field of view of each unit. The electron energy spectrum was determined by pulse-height analysis of a selected solid-state detector and the energy range was divided into 15 approximately logarithmically spaced channels, which provided a delta E/E of about 0.35. An integral energy channel above 22 keV was also provided. The look directions of the 10 electron detectors with respect to the spacecraft spin axis were 10, 20, 30, 40, 50, 80, 90, 100, 110, and 120 deg. Angular resolutions, in degrees, were: elevation - 3; azimuth - 2. The geometric factor for each detector element was 5.E-5 sq cm-sr. The proton/ion telescopes employed pulse-height analysis of a selected front counter and the 20 to 3300-keV energy interval was divided into 12 approximately logarithmically spaced channels, which provided a delta E/E of about 0.3, except for the highest channel, which covered the range 403 - 3300 keV. An integral energy channel above 27 keV was also provided. The ion angles with respect to the spacecraft spin axis were centered at 23, 46, 83, and 106 deg. Angular resolutions in degrees were: elevation - 5; azimuth - 2. The geometric factor for each telescope is 2.E-4 sq cm-sr. This experiment was part of the SPACERAD project sponsored by AFGL.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Axel.Korth</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/E.Gary.Mullen</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1990-065A&amp;ex=11</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Electron-Proton-Angle-Spectrometer experiment on the CRRES mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Electron-Proton-Angle-Spectrometer on CRRES</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/CRRES</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/CRRES/PWE</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Plasma Wave Experiment</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This experiment consisted of the Search Coil Magnetometer (AFGL-701-13-2) and Passive Plasma Sounder (PPS, AFGL-701-15) instruments and was designed to measure the plasma wave environment in the radiation belts. Emphasis was on high frequency and time resolution, on low noise levels and high sensitivities, and on broad frequency response in the range of interest in which most magnetospheric emission occurs. Receiver dynamic range was about 100 dB (factor of 1E5 in amplitude). The Search Coil Magnetometer measured the magnetic field component of plasma waves in the frequency range of 5.6 Hz - 10 kHz and contained a high permeability mu-metal core, 0.4 m long, with 10,000 turns of 42-gauge wire wound around it, and a preamplifier. The output was fed to a multichannel spectrum analyzer, with 14 simultaneous channels. The bandwidth of each channel is 0.3 times the center frequency, except at the frequencies of 5.62 kHz and 10.0 kHz at which the bandwidth is 1.5 times the center frequency. Each of the 14 outputs is sampled 8 times per second for telemetering. The PPS measured the electric field components of plasma waves in the frequency range of 100 Hz to 400 kHz. Signals induced in a 100-m-long dipole were channeled to a 4-band sweep-frequency receiver. Band 1 (100 - 810 Hz) was swept through in 32 s; band 2 (810 Hz - 6.4 kHz) in 16 s; band 3 (6.4 - 51.7 kHz) and band 4 (51.7 - 400 kHz) in 8 s. The sweeps were not continuous, but in discrete step frequencies, with 32 frequency channels in each band. The channel bandwidths of the four bands were, respectively, 7 Hz, 56 Hz, 448 Hz, and 3.6 kHz. The dynamic range of each channel was 100 dB. The 100-m electric antenna in the Langmuir Probe Experiment (NSSDC ID 90-065A-20) provided a third sensor input for the sweep frequency receiver and multichannel spectrum analyser in the Plasma Wave Experiment. This experiment was part of the SPACERAD project sponsored by AFGL.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Roger.R.Anderson</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/E.Gary.Mullen</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1990-065A&amp;ex=20</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Plasma Wave Experiment experiment on the CRRES mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/CRRES/PWS</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>SearchCoil</InstrumentType>
    <InstrumentType>Sounder</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Plasma Wave Experiment on CRRES</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/CRRES</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/CRRES/PS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Proton Switch</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This experiment consisted of two lithium-drifted silicon detectors which were each centered under a hemispherical aluminum dome. These detectors measured the omnidirectional flux of protons in the energy range 20 - 80 MeV and were made insensitive to electrons by high electronic discriminator thresholds. The main use of this instrument was to signal the spacecraft Data Processing Unit that protons were present so that the telemetry allocations for certain experiments could be changed. This experiment was part of the SPACERAD project sponsored by AFGL.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/J.Bernard.Blake</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/E.Gary.Mullen</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1990-065A&amp;ex=14</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Proton Switch experiment on the CRRES mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Proton Switch on CRRES</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/CRRES</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/CRRES/LEPA</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Low Energy Plasma Analyzer</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Low Energy Plasma Analyser (LEPA) consisted of two 260-deg spherical electrostatic analyzers and associated digital boards and microprocessors to allow a number of sophisticated measurements to be made. One analyzer was used to measure electrons in the 10 eV - 30 keV energy range; the other one measured ions over the same interval. An analyzer aperture limited the entrance angles to a 5.6- by 128-deg fan and the analyzer detector was a microchannel plate with discrete anodes. The anodes allowed the 128-deg fan to be sensed in 16 windows each 8 deg wide. One of these windows could be selected and then angular resolution down to 1 deg could be obtained. The analyzers provided a delta E/E of 0.03. A particle correlator board was used to sense the arrival time of each electron or ion within each 8-deg zone so that wave-particle interactions could be sensed. In addition, the correlator used the ac signal from the electric field antenna. The number of voltage steps per sweep on the analyzers could be set between 1 and 128. A 30-point spectrum could be obtained in 0.5 s; increasing the number of points increased the time linearly. A sequence of measurements could be stored in the experiment memory so that such measurements could be repeated each half spin period (about 15 s). This experiment was part of the SPACERAD project sponsored by AFGL.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/David.A.Hardy</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/E.Gary.Mullen</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1990-065A&amp;ex=12</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Low Energy Plasma Analyzer experiment on the CRRES mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>ElectrostaticAnalyser</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Low Energy Plasma Analyzer on CRRES</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/CRRES</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/CRRES/HIT</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Heavy Ion Telescope</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Heavy Ion Telescope (HIT) was part of the Mass Composition Instruments group and used a three-element solid state detector to measure the energy loss, incident ion energy and the time of flight along a fixed length. The three measured parameters enabled unique determination of the ion mass, elemental identification and incident energy over the range of 100 keV to 15 MeV per ion for H-Ar. The first HIT detector measured the differential (dE/dx) energy loss of the penetrating ion, the second measured the residual energy of ions stopping in that detector, and the third vetoed ions penetrating the first two. The time of flight along a 7.6-cm track was measured by the almost instantaneous emission of secondary electrons by the first and second detectors. The measured energy loss, total energy and the time of flight were digitized and transferred to the data processing unit for telemetering. This experiment was part of the SPACERAD project sponsored by AFGL.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Theodore.Allan.Fritz</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/E.Gary.Mullen</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1990-065A&amp;ex=17</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Heavy Ion Telescope experiment on the CRRES mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Heavy Ion Telescope on CRRES</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/CRRES</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/CRRES/IMS-HI</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Medium Energy Ion Mass Spectrometer</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Medium Energy Ion Mass Spectrometer (IMS-HI) was designed to measure the ring current ions in the energy/Q range of 20 keV/Q to 8 MeV/Q for protons, but with proportionately smaller ranges for the heavier atomic mass ions. This was accomplished by making a narrowly collimated stream of incident ions pass into a cross-magnetic field chamber with a field strength of 7 kG, which curved the trajectory toward one of the six cooled (-50 C) solid state detectors (n-type silicon). The momentum per charge of an ion determined the detector that it would reach. In turn, the energy of that ion was measured by that detector. The instrument could therefore provide differential energy spectra for all ions from hydrogen through barium, in the appropriate energy ranges. A broom magnet at the entrance to the magnetic field chamber expelled all electrons of energy less than 1 MeV and helped to minimize spurious counts. In addition to the ions, the instrument could also measure the energetic neutral atoms by means of a seventh detector (p-type silicon) located straight across from the entrance hole. The collimator had a conical field of view of 4 deg and a view direction at an angle 75 deg with respect to the spin axis of the satellite.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Richard.R.Vondrak</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1990-065A&amp;ex=23</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Medium Energy Ion Mass Spectrometer experiment on the CRRES mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>MassSpectrometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Medium Energy Ion Mass Spectrometer on CRRES</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/CRRES</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/CRRES/IMS-LO</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Low Energy Ion Mass Spectrometer</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Low Energy Ion Mass Spectrometer (IMS-LO) was designed to measure the energy and mass spectra in the energy/Q range 0.1 - 32 keV/Q and in the mass range 1.0 - 32 amu/Q. The design was very similar to the spectrometers of the Lockheed group on board the SCATHA and S3-3 satellites. Two identical instruments, IMS-LO-1 and IMS-LO-2 were used: one looking at 45 deg and the other at 75 deg with respect to the spin axis of the satellite. The field of view was 5 deg, conical. Each IMS was actually a triplet of spectrometers, covering the three ranges, 0.1 - 0.6 keV/Q, 0.7 - 4.5 keV/Q, and 5 - 32 keV/Q. In turn, each energy range was covered by 15 discrete energy steps, with a duration of 2.084 s at each step. Each of the 6 (3 x 2) spectrometers consisted of a Wein velocity filter, followed by an electrostatic energy analyzer (EEA) and then by a channel multiplier. The geometric factor at any energy was about 4.E-4 sq cm-sr. At each energy step, the velocity filter sequentially sampled for 2.084 s the masses in 32 mass steps. The instruments could also be operated in a LOCK submode, in which the mass was held fixed and the range of 0.1 - 32 keV/Q was swept in steps during a total duration of 1.024 s. The two IMS-LO systems could be independently commanded to operate in the SWEEP or the LOCK submode. Four fixed-energy electron detectors were attached to each IMS-LO system, and together the eight electron detectors covered the energy range 50 eV - 25 keV, in 512 ms.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Richard.R.Vondrak</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1990-065A&amp;ex=22</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Low Energy Ion Mass Spectrometer experiment on the CRRES mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>MassSpectrometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Low Energy Ion Mass Spectrometer on CRRES</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/CRRES</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/CRRES/LPI</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Langmuir Probe Instrument</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Langmuir probe was designed to measure the temperature and density of cold electrons and the electric fields in the magnetosphere, as well as their spatial and temporal fluctuations. The purpose was to better understand the wave-particle interactions. The probe instrument consisted of two pairs of orthogonal booms with tip-to-tip separations of 100 m. They were located in the spin plane of the satellite. One pair of booms carried spherical sensors and the other cylindrical antennas. An onboard microprocessor controlled the operating mode. In the Langmuir probe mode the spherical sensors were biased at fixed potentials relative to the ambient plasma and the currents collected by the sensors provided the temperature and the density of the plasma electrons. In the electric field mode both pairs of sensors were current-biased and monitored the electric field. The energy range of the measured ambient plasma was up to 10 eV and the frequency range of the measured electric field was from dc to 1 kHz. This experiment was part of the SPACERAD project sponsored by AFGL.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Forrest.S.Mozer</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/E.Gary.Mullen</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1990-065A&amp;ex=21</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Langmuir Probe Instrument experiment on the CRRES mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>LangmuirProbe</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Langmuir Probe Instrument on CRRES</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/CRRES</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/CRRES/MAG</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Fluxgate Magnetometer</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The purpose of this experiment was to measure the ambient geomagnetic field and low-frequency variations in that field up to 10 Hz. This measurement was used together with the look angles of the particle experiments (1) to obtain pitch angles of the measured particles, (2) as a diagnostic of global geomagnetic disturbances, (3) as a diagnostic of very low frequency waves in the ambient environment, (4) to provide plasma gyrofrequencies, (5) to measure V x B electric fields, and (6) to provide a secondary source of spacecraft attitude information. Each axis of a triaxial fluxgate magnetometer was sampled 20 times per second in the range of +/- 45,000 nT. The instrument required a large dynamic range to measure fields near perigee where the field was approximately 45,000 nT and in the vicinity of synchronous orbit where the field was approximately 100 nT or less with periodic variations of amplitude down to fractions of 1 nT. Because of the instrument ranges and the 12-bit analog-to-digital converter the least significant bit resolution in each sensor was approximately 20 nT and approximately 0.4 nT at low and high resolutions, respectively. On command, the signal from one axis of the magnetometer could be amplified six times to provide better amplitude resolution at low field strengths near apogee. The improved sensitivity, which permitted the detection of high-frequency, low-amplitude wave signals from this particular axis, was also used to add confidence to the increased accuracy obtained from the other axes by digital averaging. This experiment was part of the SPACERAD project sponsored by AFGL.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Howard.J.Singer</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/E.Gary.Mullen</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1990-065A&amp;ex=19</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Fluxgate Magnetometer experiment on the CRRES mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Fluxgate Magnetometer on CRRES</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/CRRES</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/CRRES/HEEF</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>High-Energy Electron Fluxmeter (HEEF)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>HEEF</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This instrument consisted of a three-element electron telescope with an anticoincidence element that provided for the measurement of the differential energy spectrum in the range 1 to 10 MeV. Two solid-state detectors, 700 micrometers thick, formed the first two elements of this system. The detector areas, in units of square mm, were: front - 100; second - 50. The final element of the the telescope was a BGO scintillation crystal coupled to a photomultiplier tube (PMT). An annular plastic scintillator surrounding the BGO crystal and viewed by two PMTs comprised the guard counter. The system was mounted in a magnesium housing with an inner tungsten shield around the BGO and plastic crystal detectors. Two slabs of tungsten served as collimators to define the entrance aperture. The geometric factor for the system was 1.2E-2 sq cm-sr. Only electrons with energies above 1 MeV stopping in the BGO crystal were pulse-height analyzed into 10 bins. The lower six bins provided 0.5-MeV windows; the next 2 bins provided 1-MeV windows; and the last two provided 2-MeV windows. Consequently, the detail of the spectrum was good enough for radiation belt modeling. Proton rejection was quite good since the shielding, the pulse-height information in the three telescope elements, and the guard counter anticoincidence all contributed. The time accumulation of 0.5 s determined the time resolution of the investigation. This experiment was part of the SPACERAD project sponsored by AFGL.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Donald.H.Brautigam</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/E.Gary.Mullen</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1990-065A&amp;ex=9</URL>
        <Description>Information about the High-Energy Electron Fluxmeter (HEEF) experiment on the CRRES mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>High-Energy Electron Fluxmeter (HEEF) on CRRES</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/CRRES</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/CRRES/LOMICS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Low Energy Magnetospheric Ion Composition Sensor</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Low Energy Magnetospheric Ion Composition Sensor (LOMICS) was part of the Mass Composition Instruments group and measured fluxes and composition of ions up to mass 56 amu in the energy/Q range of 40 eV/Q to 40 keV/Q. The energy of an ion entering the instrument was determined by a 90-deg spherical section electrostatic energy analyzer (EEA). It was followed by a time-of-flight (TOF) analyzer which yielded the speed of the ion. Together the two analyzers specified the mass and energy/charge of each ion. Generally, TOF analyzers were unsuitable for low energy ions; but it was overcome by providing each ion with an extra energy of 10 keV after it passed through the EEA. To determine the time of flight of the ion through a known path length, two very thin carbon foils (100 A), one at the entrance and the other at the exit of the TOF chamber, were used. The secondary electrons emitted by these foils were accelerated, deflected and focused onto an 18-mm diameter microchannel plate to provide the start and stop times of the flight. Three stop foils were used, corresponding to the three incident angles of the ions: 60, 90, and 120 deg from the spin axis of the satellite. The field of view at each of these angles was 12 deg by 15 deg. The energy resolution was 7.5% of the ion energy and the geometric factor was 3.8E-4 sq cm-sr. The system could detect the incidence of a single ion as well as fluxes up to 5.E7 particles/(sq cm- sr-s). LOMICS was initially inoperative after launch but later become functional. This experiment was part of the SPACERAD project sponsored by AFGL.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/David.T.Young</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1990-065A&amp;ex=18</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Low Energy Magnetospheric Ion Composition Sensor experiment on the CRRES mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>EnergeticParticleInstrument</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Low Energy Magnetospheric Ion Composition Sensor on CRRES</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/CRRES</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Donald.H.Brautigam</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Donald H. Brautigam</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>USAF Phillips Laboratory</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Theodore.Allan.Fritz</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Prof. Theodore Allan Fritz</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Boston University</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Alfred.L.Vampola</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2011-02-23T16:25:29Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Alfred L. Vampola</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Aerospace Corporation</OrganizationName>
    <Note>Retired</Note>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/E.Gary.Mullen</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. E. Gary Mullen</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>USAF Geophysics Laboratory</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Berend.Wilken</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Berend Wilken</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Deceased - formerly at MPI fur Aeronomie, Germany</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Forrest.S.Mozer</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Prof. Forrest S. Mozer</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>University of California, Berkeley</OrganizationName>
    <Address>Room 306
Space Science Laboratory
University of California, Berkeley
Berkeley CA
   94720</Address>
    <Email>mozer@sunspot.ssl.berkeley.edu</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+1-510-642-0549</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Wojciech.A.Kolasinski</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Wojciech A. Kolasinski</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Aerospace Corporation</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Axel.Korth</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Axel Korth</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Max-Planck-Institut fur Aeronomie</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
      <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Lee.Frost.Bargatze</ResourceID>
      <ReleaseDate>2012-06-13T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
      <PersonName>Lee Frost Bargatze</PersonName>
      <OrganizationName>Institute of Geophysics and Planetary Physics and the Department of Earth and Space Sciences, University of California, Los Angeles</OrganizationName>
      <Address>Institute of Geophysics and Planetary Physics, University of California Los Angeles, Box 951567, Los Angeles, CA 90095-1567</Address>
      <Email>lfb@igpp.ucla.edu</Email>
      <PhoneNumber>+1 310 206 6073</PhoneNumber>
   </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/David.T.Young</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. David T. Young</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Southwest Research Institute</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Richard.R.Vondrak</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Richard R. Vondrak</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>GSFC-Code 690</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/David.L.Reasoner</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. David L. Reasoner</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Deceased - formerly at NASA-MSFC</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Roger.R.Anderson</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Roger R. Anderson</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>University of Iowa</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Susan.Gussenhoven-Shea</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Susan Gussenhoven-Shea</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>USAF Geophysics Laboratory</OrganizationName>
    <PhoneNumber>+1-781-377-3212</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/David.A.Hardy</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. David A. Hardy</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>USAF Geophysics Laboratory</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/J.Bernard.Blake</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. J. Bernard Blake</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Aerospace Corporation</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Michael.D.Violet</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Mr. Michael D. Violet</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>USAF Geophysics Laboratory</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Howard.J.Singer</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Howard J. Singer</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>NOAA Space Weather Prediction Center</OrganizationName>
    <Address>Space Weather Prediction Center, W/NP9 325 Broadway, Boulder CO 80305</Address>
    <Email>Howard.Singer@noaa.gov</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>303-497-6959</PhoneNumber>
  </Person></Spase>


