<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.0</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ISEE1</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>ISEE 1</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>1977-102A</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>International Sun-Earth Explorer-A</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>Explorer 56</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>ISEE-A</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Explorer-class mother spacecraft, International Sun-Earth Explorer 1, was part of the mother/daughter/heliocentric mission (ISEE 1, ISEE 2, ISEE 3). The purposes of the mission were: (1) to investigate solar-terrestrial relationships at the outermost boundaries of the Earth's magnetosphere, (2) to examine in detail the structure of the solar wind near the Earth and the shock wave that forms the interface between the solar wind and the Earth's magnetosphere, (3) to investigate motions of and mechanisms operating in the plasma sheets, and (4) to continue the investigation of cosmic rays and solar flare effects in the interplanetary region near 1 AU. The three spacecraft carried a number of complementary instruments for making measurements of plasmas, energetic particles, waves, and fields. The mission thus extended the investigations of previous IMP spacecraft. The mother/daughter portion of the mission consisted of two spacecraft (ISEE 1 and ISEE 2) with station-keeping capability in the same highly eccentric geocentric orbit with an apogee of 23 Earth radii. During the course of the mission, the ISEE 1 and ISEE 2 orbit parameters underwent short-term and long-term variations due to solar and lunar perturbations. These two spacecraft maintained a small separation distance, and made simultaneous coordinated measurements to permit separation of spatial from temporal irregularities in the near-Earth solar wind, the bow shock, and inside the magnetosphere. By maneuvering ISEE 2, the inter-spacecraft separation as measured near the Earth's bow shock was allowed to vary between 10 km and 5000 km; its value is accurately known as a function of time and orbital position. The spacecraft were spin stabilized, with the spin vectors maintained nominally within 1 degree of perpendicular to the ecliptic plane, pointing north. The spin rates were nominally 19.75 rpm for ISEE 1 and 19.8 rpm for ISEE 2, so that there was a slow differential rotation between the two spacecraft. The ISEE 1 body-mounted solar array provided approximately 175 watts initially and 131 watts after three years, at 28 volts during normal operation. The ISEE 1 data rate was 4096 bps most of the time and 16384 bps during one orbit out of every five (with some exceptions). Both ISEE 1 and ISEE 2 re-entered the Earth's atmosphere during orbit 1518 on September 26, 1987. Seventeen of 21 on-board experiments were operational at the end. For instrument descriptions written by the investigators, see IEEE Trans. on Geosci. Electron., v. GE-16, no. 3, July 1978.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Keith.W.Ogilvie</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/spacecraft/display.action?id=1977-102A</URL>
        <Description>Information about the ISEE 1 mission</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <ObservatoryGroupID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ISEE</ObservatoryGroupID>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Heliosphere.NearEarth</ObservatoryRegion>
</Location>
</Observatory>
<Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ISEE1/LEPEDEA</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Low-Energy Proton and Electron Differential Energy Analyzer (LEPEDEA)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>LEPEDEA</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This experiment was designed to study, by means of identical instrumentation on the mother/daughter spacecraft, the spatial and temporal variations of the solar wind and magnetosheath electrons and ions. Protons and electrons in the energy range from 1 eV to 45 keV were measured in 64 contiguous energy bands with an energy resolution (delta E/E) of 0.16. A quadrispherical low-energy proton and electron differential energy analyzer (LEPEDEA), employing seven continuous channel electron multipliers in each of its two (one for protons and one for electrons) electrostatic analyzers was flown on both the mother and the daughter spacecraft. All but 2% of the 4-pi-sr solid angle was covered for particle velocity vectors. A GM tube was also included, with a conical field of view of 40-deg full-angle, perpendicular to the spin axis. This detector was sensitive to electrons with E&gt;45 keV, and to protons with E&gt;600 keV.</Description>
      <Acknowledgement/>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/H.Kent.Hills</PersonID>
        <Role>TechnicalContact</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Charles.F.Kennel</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Vytenis.M.Vasyliunas</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Louis.A.Frank</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1977-102A-03</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Low-Energy Proton and Electron Differential Energy Analyzer (LEPEDEA) experiment on the ISEE 1 mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>ElectrostaticAnalyser</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Low-Energy Proton and Electron Differential Energy Analyzer (LEPEDEA) on ISEE 1</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ISEE1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ISEE1/Ephemeris</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>ISEE1 Positions</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>ISEE1 Ephemeris</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2013-04-09T00:00:00Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>ISEE1 spacecraft positions in various coordinate systems</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Robert.E.McGuire
</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
      </Contact>
        </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Platform</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Spacecraft position</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ISEE1</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ISEE1/LFEF</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Quasi-static and low-frequency electric fields (0.1-200 mV/m, frequency &lt; 1000Hz)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName/>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The objective of this experiment was to study quasi-static and low-frequency electric fields in the plasmasphere, magnetosphere, magnetosheath, and solar wind. Measurements were made of the potential difference between a pair of 8-cm diameter vitreous carbon spheres which were separated by 73.5 m and mounted on the ends of wire booms in the satellite spin plane. To attempt to overcome the spacecraft sheath (a potential problem which plagues all electric field detectors), an electron gun for changing the spacecraft potential was included, and all exposed spacecraft surfaces were made electrically conducting. The instrument was designed to be sensitive to fields from 0.1 to 200 mV/m in the frequency band of 0 to 12 Hz. The experiment also measured the electric field component of waves at frequencies below 1000 Hz.</Description>
      <Acknowledgement/>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Cynthia.A.Cattell</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/H.Kent.Hills</PersonID>
        <Role>TechnicalContact</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Michael.C.Kelley</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Forrest.S.Mozer</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1977-102A-06</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Quasi-static and low-frequency electric fields (0.1-200 mV/m, frequency &lt; 1000Hz) experiment on the ISEE 1 mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>DoubleSphere</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Quasi-static and low-frequency electric fields (0.1-200 mV/m, frequency &lt; 1000Hz) on ISEE 1</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ISEE1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ISEE1/FPE</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>ISEE 1 Fast Plasma Experiment (FPE) and Solar Wind Ion Experiment (SWE)</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This experiment was designed, in conjunction with a similar instrument (77-102B-01) provided by G. Paschmann of Max Planck Institute for flight on the daughter spacecraft, to study the plasma velocity distribution and its spatial and temporal variations in the solar wind, bow shock, magnetosheath, magnetopause, magnetotail, and magnetosphere. The FPE consists of three high efficience 90 degree spherical section electrostatic analyzers using large secondary emitters and discrete dynode multipliers to detect analyzed particles. Two of them, viewing in opposite directions, produce complete 2D velocity distribution measurements of both protons and electrons every spacecraft revolution. A third FPE analyzer with a divided emitter measures 3D distributions at a slower rate. Protons from 50 eV to 40 keV and electrons from 5 eV to 20 keV were measured The experiment operated in two ranges, with energy resolution for the several steps in each range of 10% of the center energy level. The Solar Wind Experiment (SWE) measures solar wind ions. It is composed of two 150 degree spherical section analyzers using the same set of plates. The two acceptance fans are tilted with respect to each other so that 3D characteristics of the ion distributions can be derived. The ion experiment had degraded by April 1980 and the density values are suspected to be too low in later years. To protect the instrument, this experiment was turned off whenever the spacecraft was below 30,000 km. The Fast Plasma Experiment (FPE) had degraded by January 1978.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Samuel.J.Bame</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/H.Kent.Hills</PersonID>
        <Role>TechnicalContact</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Helmut.R.Rosenbauer</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Edward.W.Hones.Jr</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Karl.Schindler</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Michael.D.Montgomery</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/John.R.Asbridge</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Goetz.Paschmann</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/H.Miggenrieder</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Heinrich.J.Volk</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/William.C.Feldman</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/John.T.Gosling</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1977-102A-01</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Fast Plasma Experiment (FPE) and Solar Wind Ion Experiment (SWE) experiment on the ISEE 1 mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://nssdc/instrument/1977-102A-01</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>ElectrostaticAnalyser</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Fast Plasma Experiment (FPE) and Solar Wind Ion Experiment (SWE) on ISEE 1</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ISEE1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ISEE1/MAG</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>ISEE 1 Fluxgate Magnetometer, Tri-axial</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The magnetic fields investigation selected for ISEE 1 and 2 had as its principal objectives the study of the magnetic signatures of magnetospheric phenomena and magnetohydrodynamic waves in and around the magnetosphere, and to provide supporting data for other experiments on the spacecraft such as the electric field, particle and plasma wave investigations. In this triaxial fluxgate magnetometer, three ring-core sensors in an orthogonal triad were enclosed in a flipper mechanism at the end of the magnetometer boom. The electronics unit was on the main body of the spacecraft at the foot of the boom. The magnetometer had two operating ranges of +/- 8192 nT and +/- 256 nT in each vector component. The data were digitized and averaged within the instrument to provide increased resolution and to provide Nyquist filtering. There were two modes for the transmission of the averaged data. In the double-precision mode of operation, 16-bit samples of data were transmitted. This provided a maximum resolution of +/- 1/4 nT or 1/128 nT in th low-sensitivity and high-sensitivity ranges. In the single-precision mode, any 8 consecutive bits of the above 16 bits were selected by ground command for transmission and the telemetry bandwidths of the magnetometer were doubled. This bandwidth varied from 2 Hz for the low-telemetry-rate, double-precision experiment mode to 32 Hz for the high-telemetry-rate, single-precision experiment mode. Operation of this experiment was near nominal until spacecraft re-entry on September 26, 1987. Users of data from this experiment should be aware of the fact that the averaging of 12-bit samples to create 16-bit samples worked well in the spin plane, but in situations during which the field along the spin axis was quiet relative to the size of a digital window, the magnetometer returned only a 12-bit sample. This was particularly noticeable when the spacecraft was in the solar wind and the instrument was operated in its low gain (8192 nT) range, and when the spacecraft was in quiet regions of the magnetosphere in the low gain mode. The former situation limited the resolution of the field measured to 4 nT in the double precision mode in which the magnetometer usually was operated, and the latter situation created, as the spacecraft moved through the large gradient in the Earth's magnetic field, a stair step pattern of field changes of size 4 nT which may be mistaken for waves. Another operational anomaly was the saturation of a sensor during gain changes. At these times, the 3 components of the magnetic field were deduced from one spin tone and the field along the spin axis, limiting the temporal resolution of the instrument to below the spin frequency. Every effort was made to minimize zero level errors, clerical errors and other data processing anomalies within the available resources. However, these resources were very constrained and funding ceased before the entire submitted data set could be checked. It is expected that eventually quality checks of the entire database will be possible, but in the meantime, users of the ISEE-1 and 2 magnetometer data are requested to report all suspicions about data quality to the principal investigator, C. T. Russell, for verification.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Christopher.T.Russell</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1977-102A-04</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Fluxgate Magnetometer, Tri-axial experiment on the ISEE 1 mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Fluxgate Magnetometer, Tri-axial on ISEE 1</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ISEE1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ISEE1/PWE</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>ISEE-1 Plasma wave experiment</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>ISEE-1 Plasma wave investigation</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>
This experiment, in conjunction with a similar (but simpler) experiment on ISEE 2, was designed to measure wave phenomena occurring within the magnetosphere and solar wind. Three electric dipole antennas (215 m, 73.5 m, and 0.61 m) and a triaxial search-coil antenna were used. The instrumentation consisted of four main elements: (1) a narrow-band sweep-frequency receiver with 32 frequency steps in each of four bands from 100 Hz to 400 kHz, a complete sweep required 32 s; (2) a high-time-resolution spectrum analyzer with 20 channels from 5.62 Hz to 311 kHz for electric field and 14 identical channels from 5.62 Hz to 10 kHz for magnetic field information, the electric and magnetic channels were sampled simultaneously; (3) a wave-normal analyzer to provide components for computing the wave normal and the Poynting flux, this analyzer had a 10-Hz bandwidth, and covered 32 frequencies from 100 Hz to 5 kHz; and (4) a wide-band receiver to condition electric and magnetic waveforms for transmission to the ground via the special-purpose analog transmitter, this receiver also provided the signals for long-baseline-interferometer measurements between ISEE 1 and ISEE 2. There were two basic frequency channels: 10 Hz to 1 kHz and 650 Hz to 10 or 40 kHz. In addition, the frequency range could be shifted by a frequency-conversion scheme to any of eight ranges up to 2 MHz.

Selected References:

Gurnett, D. A., et al., ISEE-1 and ISEE-2 plasma wave investigation, IEEE Trans. Geosci. Electron., GE-16, No. 3, 225-230, July 1978.

Gurnett, D. A., et al., Survey of plasma wave observations from ISEE 1 and ISEE 2, In -- The 13th ESLAB Symp., Innsbruck, Austria, June 5-7, 1978.

Gurnett, D. A., et al., Initial results from the ISEE-1 and -2 plasma wave investigation, Space Sci. Rev., 23, 103-122, 1979.
</Description>
      <Acknowledgement/>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Donald.A.Gurnett</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Frederick.L.Scarf</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Robert.W.Fredricks</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Edward.J.Smith</PersonID>
        <Role>CoInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/H.Kent.Hills</PersonID>
        <Role>TechnicalContact</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1977-102A-07</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Plasma waves experiment on the ISEE 1 mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Antenna</InstrumentType>
    <InstrumentType>SearchCoil</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Plasma wave experiment on ISEE 1</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ISEE1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ISEE1/VES</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>ISEE 1 Vector Electron Spectrometer (VES)</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>Two triaxial systems of 127-deg cylindrical
                electrostatic analyzers were used to make three-dimensional
                measurements of the electron distribution function. There were
                three modes of operation, with the following nominal energy ranges:
                solar wind, 7 to 500 eV; magnetosheath, 10 eV to 2 keV;
                and magnetotail and solar, 105 eV to 7.05 keV. The energy
                resolution (delta E/E) was 0.07. The entire set of six simultaneous
                spectrometer measurements was taken while the satellite rotated
                through 60 deg. Each spectrometer consisted of a curved-plate
                analyzer and two channeltron detectors.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Keith.W.Ogilvie</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1977-102A-02</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Vector Electron Spectrometer on the ISEE 1 spacecraft.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>ElectrostaticAnalyser</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Vector Electron Spectrometer (VES)</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ISEE1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/ISEE1/UCB</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>ISEE 1 UCB Particle Detectors</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This experiment was designed to determine, by using identical instrumentation (see 77-102B) on the mother/daughter spacecraft, the spatial extent, propagation velocity, and temporal behavior of a wide variety of particle phenomena. Electrons were measured at 2 and 6 keV and in two bands: 8 to 200 keV and 30 to 200 keV. Protons were measured at 2 and 6 keV and in three bands: 8 to 200 keV, 30 to 200 keV, and 200 to 380 keV. The 30 keV threshold could be commanded to 15 or 60 keV. Identical instrumentation on each spacecraft consisted of a pair of surface-barrier semiconductor-detector telescopes (one with a foil and one without a foil) and four fixed-voltage cylindrical electrostatic analyzers (two for electrons and two for protons). Channel multipliers were used as detectors with the fixed-voltage analyzers. The telescopes had a viewing cone with a 40-deg half-angle, oriented at about 20 deg to the spin axis.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Kinsey.A.Anderson</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1977-102A-10</URL>
</InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://nssdc/instrument/1977-102A-10</PriorID>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>ElectrostaticAnalyser</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Electron and Proton Fluxes in the Outer magnetosphere</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/ISEE1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Louis.A.Frank</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Prof. Louis A. Frank</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>University of Iowa</OrganizationName>
    <Address>Department of Physics and Astronomy, University of Iowa, Iowa City, IA 52242</Address>
    <Email>frank@iowasp.physics.uiowa.edu</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+1 319 335 1695</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Karl.Schindler</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Prof. Karl Schindler</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Ruhr Universitat</OrganizationName>
    <Address>Bochum, Germany</Address>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Kinsey.A.Anderson</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Prof. Kinsey A. Anderson</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>University of California, Berkeley</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Michael.C.Kelley</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Michael C. Kelley</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Cornell University</OrganizationName>
    <Address>School of Electrical Engineering
Cornell University
318 Rhodes Hall
Ithaca NY
   14853</Address>
    <Email>mikek@ee.cornell.edu</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+1-607-254-5331</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/H.Kent.Hills</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. H. Kent Hills</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>NASA Goddard Space Flight Center</OrganizationName>
    <Address>Code 690.1, QSS Group Inc</Address>
    <Email>hills@nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+1 301 286 1771</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
      <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Christopher.T.Russell</ResourceID>
      <ReleaseDate>2012-06-13T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
      <PersonName>Christopher T. Russell</PersonName>
      <OrganizationName>Institute of Geophysics and Planetary Physics and the Department of Earth and Space Sciences, University of California, Los Angeles</OrganizationName>
      <Address>Institute of Geophysics and Planetary Physics, University of California Los Angeles, Box 951567, Los Angeles, CA 90095-1567</Address>
      <Email>ctrussell@igpp.ucla.edu</Email>
      <PhoneNumber>+1 310 825 3188</PhoneNumber>
      <FaxNumber>+1 310 206 3051</FaxNumber>
   </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Forrest.S.Mozer</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Prof. Forrest S. Mozer</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>University of California, Berkeley</OrganizationName>
    <Address>Room 306
Space Science Laboratory
University of California, Berkeley
Berkeley CA
   94720</Address>
    <Email>mozer@sunspot.ssl.berkeley.edu</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+1-510-642-0549</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Goetz.Paschmann</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Goetz Paschmann</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Max Planck Institut fur Extraterrestrische Physik, Garching, Germany</OrganizationName>
    <Email>gep@mpe.mpg.de</Email>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/John.T.Gosling</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. John T. Gosling</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Los Alamos National Laboratory</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Michael.D.Montgomery</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Michael D. Montgomery</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Unknown, formerly at Los Alamos National Laboratory</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Vytenis.M.Vasyliunas</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Prof. Vytenis M. Vasyliunas</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Max-Planck-Institut fur Aeronomie</OrganizationName>
    <Address>Max-Planck-Institut fur Aeronomie
Postfach 20
37191 Katlenburg
Germany</Address>
    <Email>vasyliunas@linmpi.mpg.de</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+1-49-5556-401435</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Edward.J.Smith</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Edward J. Smith</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Jet Propulsion Laboratory</OrganizationName>
    <Email>edward.j.smith@jpl.nasa.gov</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+1 818 354 2248</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Keith.W.Ogilvie</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Keith W. Ogilvie</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>NASA Goddard Space Flight Center</OrganizationName>
    <Address>Code 673, Greenbelt, MD 20771, USA</Address>
    <Email>keith.w.ogilvie@nasa.gov</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+1 301 286 5904</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Frederick.L.Scarf</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-10-01T18:53:39Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Frederick L. Scarf</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Deceased - formerly at TRW, CA</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Charles.F.Kennel</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Prof. Charles F. Kennel</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>University of California, Los Angeles</OrganizationName>
    <Address>Department of Physics
University of California, Los Angeles
405 Hilgard
Los Angeles CA
   90095-1567</Address>
    <Email>kennel@uclaph.ucla.edu</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+1-310-825-2052</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Donald.A.Gurnett</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Prof. Donald A. Gurnett</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>University of Iowa</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/John.R.Asbridge</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. John R. Asbridge</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Los Alamos National Laboratory</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Robert.W.Fredricks</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Robert W. Fredricks</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>TRW Incorporated</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Samuel.J.Bame</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Samuel J. Bame</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Los Alamos National Laboratory, Retired</OrganizationName>
    <Email>sbame@lanl.gov</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+1 505 662 7415</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Cynthia.A.Cattell</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Cynthia A. Cattell</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>University of Minnesota</OrganizationName>
    <Address>Tate Laboratory of Physics
School of Physics and Astronomy
University of Minnesota
116 Church Street SE
Minneapolis MN
   55455-0112</Address>
    <Email>cattell@belka.spa.umn.edu</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+1-612-626-2029</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Helmut.R.Rosenbauer</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Helmut R. Rosenbauer</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Max Planck Institut fur Aeronomie</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/H.Miggenrieder</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. H. Miggenrieder</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Unknown, formerly at Max Planck Institut fur Extraterrestrische Physik</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Heinrich.J.Volk</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Prof. Heinrich J. Volk</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Max Planck Institut fur Kernphysik</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/William.C.Feldman</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. William C. Feldman</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Los Alamos National Laboratory</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Edward.W.Hones.Jr</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Edward W. Hones, Jr.</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Los Alamos National Laboratory</OrganizationName>
  </Person></Spase>


