<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_3.xsd">
	<Version>2.2.3</Version>
	<Observatory>
		<ResourceID>spase://ASWS/Observatory/Ground/Macquarie_Island</ResourceID>
		<ResourceHeader>
			<ResourceName>Macquarie_Island</ResourceName>
			<AlternateName>None</AlternateName>
  			<ReleaseDate>2020-11-13T20:35:01Z</ReleaseDate>
			<Description>Macquarie_Island station is located on Macquarie Island. It has been in operation since June 1950.</Description>
			<Acknowledgement>Please acknowledge: Space Weather Network, Bureau of Meteorology, Australia</Acknowledgement>
			<Contact>
				<PersonID>spase://ASWS/Person/Kehe.Wang</PersonID>
				<Role>GeneralContact</Role>
				<Role>DataProducer</Role>
			</Contact>
			<Contact>
				<PersonID>spase://ASWS/Person/Kehe.Wang</PersonID>
				<Role>MetadataContact</Role>
			</Contact>
                	<InformationURL>
                  		<Name>ASWS Observatory Information: Macquarie Island</Name>
        		     	<URL>http://www.sws.bom.gov.au/World_Data_Centre/2/1/26</URL>
       				<Description>includes observatory/station name, location, lifetime, identity and datasets informtion.</Description>
       				<Language>en</Language>
      			</InformationURL>
                        <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/Ground/Macquarie.Island</PriorID>
                        <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/WDC/Macquarie.Island</PriorID>
		</ResourceHeader>
		<Location>
			<ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Surface</ObservatoryRegion>
			<Latitude>-54.50</Latitude>
			<Longitude>158.95E</Longitude>
		</Location>
		<OperatingSpan>
			<StartDate>1950-06-01T00:00:00.000</StartDate>
		</OperatingSpan>
	</Observatory>
<Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
      <ResourceID>spase://ASWS/Instrument/Ground/Macquarie_Island/Ionosonde</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>Macquarie Island Ionosonde</ResourceName>
         <ReleaseDate>2019-05-01T12:34:56.789Z</ReleaseDate>
         <Description>The Macquarie Island Ionosonde station in Macquarie Island, Tasmania, Australia, had ionosondes since June of 1950. The first was an analog ionosonde with nitrate film from 13/06/1950 to 01/09/1951. Between 04/09/1951 and 30/11/1958, there was an ionosonde with 35 mm film. Between 13/11/1983 and 17/11/1995, there was an ionosonde with 16 mm film in operation. There was an IPS 4D digital ionosonde between 22/12/1993 and 28/11/2000, and a CADI ionosonde between 01/12/2000 and 29/06/2015.</Description>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://ASWS/Person/Kehe.Wang</PersonID>
            <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Lee.Frost.Bargatze</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
      </ResourceHeader>
      <InstrumentType>Radar</InstrumentType>
      <InvestigationName>Macquarie Island Ionosonde</InvestigationName>
      <ObservatoryID>spase://ASWS/Observatory/Ground/Macquarie_Island</ObservatoryID>
   </Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
      <ResourceID>spase://ASWS/Instrument/Ground/Macquarie_Island/Ionospheric_Scintillation_Monitor</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>Macquarie Island Ionospheric Scintillation Monitor</ResourceName>
         <ReleaseDate>2019-05-01T12:34:56.789Z</ReleaseDate>
         <Description>An Ionospheric Scintillation Monitor (ISM) is a single- or dual-frequency GPS receiver specifically designed to monitor ionospheric scintillation levels in real time. The ISM has wide-bandwidth tracking loops to maintain lock longer during intervals of strong ionospheric scintillation, and samples at a rate of 50 Hz to calculate the scintillation statistics S4 and Prms. The wide-bandwidth tracking improves tracking through strong scintillation however loss of lock on single or multiple satellites can still occur during extreme events, requiring re-acquisition of the GPS signal(s).

SWS Radio and Space Services uses GPS Silicon Valley's GPS Ionospheric Scintillation and TEC Monitor (GISTM) system Model GSV4004B to monitor Ionospheric Scintillation in real time. The GSV4004B consists of an L1/L2 GPS Antenna, a dual-frequency GPS receiver (NovAtel's Euro-3M with modified firmware), and a low phase noise oven-controlled crystal oscillator (OCXO), housed in NovAtel's EuroPak-3M enclosure. The OCXO is required for monitoring phase scintillation.

The primary purpose of the ISM system is to collect ionospheric scintillation statistics (S4 and Prms) for all visible GPS satellites (up to eleven satellites) and store these (ISMR) binary data logs on the receiver controller hard disk for post processing. The ISM control software can be programmed to collect the ISMR data logs that are generated every 1 minute. Alternatively, raw phase and amplitude data at 0.02 second temporal resolution (50 Hz) and code/carrier divergence at 1 s (1 Hz) can be recorded from the ISM. These data can be used to reconstruct the statistical scintillation indices, such as S4 recorded in the ISMR data log, from raw data. This allows the user to modify the parameters used in the derivation of scintillation indices, such as de-trending and filter cut-off parameters.

The Macquarie Island Ionospheric Scintillation Monitor station near Macquarie Island, Tasmania, Australia, has a digital Ionospheric Scintillation Monitor GPS since March 2008.</Description>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://ASWS/Person/Kehe.Wang</PersonID>
            <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Lee.Frost.Bargatze</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <PriorID>spase://ASWS/Instrument/Ground/Macquarie_Island/Ionospheric_Scintillation_Monitor.xml</PriorID>
      </ResourceHeader>
      <InstrumentType>ScintillationDetector</InstrumentType>
      <InvestigationName>Macquarie Island Ionospheric Scintillation Monitor</InvestigationName>
      <ObservatoryID>spase://ASWS/Observatory/Ground/Macquarie_Island</ObservatoryID>
   </Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://ASWS/Instrument/Ground/Macquarie_Island/Magnetometer</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Macquarie Island Magnetometer</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2020-11-13T20:35:01Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Macquarie Island Magnetometer station in Macquarie Island, Tasmania, Australia, has a Induction Magnetometer since August 2000. 
     
     	15 August, 2000
     	---------------
     	Data type: "p"
     	Data being received in ASFC from ANTDIV. The instrument is an induction magnetometer for recording geomagnetic pulsations and is owned by the University of Newcastle and operated by ANTDIV. Presently there is no calibration information available for converting the data to variations in nanoTesla. This information has been requested from the University of Newcastle Space Plasma Waves Research Group and as yet there has been no reply. 
     	(RAM - 16/10/00)
     
     	3 April, 2006 (ANTDIV/RAM)

     	Telecommunications wish to advise of the following outage, currently affecting data circuits to Casey, Davis, Macquarie Island and Mawson.
        
	For more information, please read its log file.     
      </Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://ASWS/Person/Kehe.Wang</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
      </Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>ASWS Macquarie Island Instrument Induction Magenetometer (UoN/AAD) Log File</Name>
	<URL>ftp://ftp-out.sws.bom.gov.au/wdc/wdc_mag/data/mcq/stn.log</URL>
	<Description>Includes Macquarie Island magnetometer log file.</Description>
	<Language>en</Language>
      </InformationURL>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/Ground/Macquarie.Island/Magnetometer</PriorID>
      <PriorID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/IAGA/Macquarie.Island/Magnetometer</PriorID>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Macquarie Island Magnetometer</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://ASWS/Observatory/Ground/Macquarie_Island</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://ASWS/Instrument/Ground/Macquarie_Island/Riometer</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Macquarie Island Riometer</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2017-07-24T17:20:00Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Macquarie Island station of Tasmania, Australia has a riometer since 11 September 1987.
     
	Ionosondes are ground-based swept-frequency vertical radars that are used to determine the electron density of the ionosphere. They provide information about the E and F layers in the altitude range of about 100 to 500 km. However, most of the absorption that occurs when a radio wave transits the ionosphere occurs in the D-region from about 70 to 100 km in height.

	The riometer (relative ionospheric opacity meter) is one of the few instruments that can be used to determine ionospheric absorption. The first riometers were single beam units and operated at or near a frequency of 30 MHz. The principle of operation is to compare the currently received cosmic radio noise with a calibration curve (called a quiet day curve or QDC). The difference between the two is the current ionospheric absorption over the region monitored by the antenna at the time.

	Most of the cosmic noise monitored by a riometer comes from our own galaxy, and varies over the sky. It has a maximum when looking at the galactic centre (in the direction of Sagittarius) and a minimum at right angles to this direction. To minimize contamination with terrestrial RFI, riometers either employ a wide bandwidth (eg 500 kHz) to dilute the interference and/or sweep rapidly in frequency over several 100 kHz and use the minimum signal detected in this range.

	Riometers are most often employed at high latitude and polar regions where they are used to detect polar cap absorption. This provides a measure of solar-generated high energy protons. The absorption is caused by the particles precipitating down to D-region altitudes. Riometers can also be deployed at lower latitudes, and although natural absorption is much less here, they have been used to monitor atmospheric nuclear explosions.

	Australian Bureau of Meteorology's Space Weather Services (SWS) operates several riometers in Antarctica and the data is available in real-time on the SWS web site at Riometer Data.
      </Description>
      <Acknowledgement>We are thankful to AAD and the Space Weather Network, Bureau of Meteorology of Australia for the observations of Macquarie Island riometer data.</Acknowledgement>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://ASWS/Person/Kehe.Wang</PersonID>
        <Role>GeneralContact</Role>
      </Contact>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Riometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Macquarie Island Riometer</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://ASWS/Observatory/Ground/Macquarie_Island</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://ASWS/Person/Kehe.Wang</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2017-06-28T17:03:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Kehe Wang</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Space Weather Services (SWS), Bureau of Meteorology, Australia</OrganizationName>
    <Email>kehe.wang@bom.gov.au</Email>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
      <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Lee.Frost.Bargatze</ResourceID>
      <ReleaseDate>2012-06-13T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
      <PersonName>Lee Frost Bargatze</PersonName>
      <OrganizationName>Institute of Geophysics and Planetary Physics and the Department of Earth and Space Sciences, University of California, Los Angeles</OrganizationName>
      <Address>Institute of Geophysics and Planetary Physics, University of California Los Angeles, Box 951567, Los Angeles, CA 90095-1567</Address>
      <Email>lfb@igpp.ucla.edu</Email>
      <PhoneNumber>+1 310 206 6073</PhoneNumber>
   </Person></Spase>


