<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_1.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.1</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/GIRO</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>GIRO Group</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>Global Ionospheric Radio Observatory Group</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>GIRO provides accurate specification of the electron density in the Earth's
   ionosphere at &gt;60 locations in the world. 37 GIRO locations provide real-time ionospheric
   data to the central server in Lowell, Massachusetts within several minutes. GIRO sites
   are equipped by Digisonde instruments that use the high frequency remote sounding
   technique to probe the bottomside ionosphere from 80 km up to the peak of ionospheric
   plasma density. Real-time and retrospective data from GIRO locations are ingested in Lowell
   Digital Ionogram DataBase (DIDBase) GIRO data are open for public access via DIDBase and
   DriftBase Web Portals, and custom software tools for digisonde data analysis, SAO Explorer
   and Drift Explorer.</Description>
      <Acknowledgement>A heavy investment of time, effort, expertise, and funds continues to
   be made to produce, collect, quality control, interpret, and store digisonde ionograms. It
   is important that data providers and the UML DIDBase developers are appropriately acknowledged
   in scientific publications that involve analysis of data obtained from the Lowell DIDBase.
</Acknowledgement>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Bodo.W.Reinisch</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Ivan.A.Galkin</PersonID>
        <Role>TechnicalContact</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>GIRO (Global Ionospheric Radio Observatory) Home Page.</Name>
        <URL>http://giro.uml.edu/</URL>
        <Description>Access to real-time data and software tools</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Global Ionospheric Radio Observatory (GIRO) Article</Name>
        <URL>https://link.springer.com/article/10.5047%2Feps.2011.03.001</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Global Ionospheric Radio Observatory.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.Surface</ObservatoryRegion>
</Location>
</Observatory>
<Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/GIRO/Ionosonde</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>GIRO Ionospheric Sounder</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>Ionosonde</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2012-03-21T09:08:00Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>

The GIRO (Global Ionospheric Radio Observatory) comprises records of subpeak
ionospheric characteristics, including altitude profiles of electron 
density and plasma drift velocity, in the altitude range 90 km to the 
peak height of the F2 layer, measured by a global ground-based network 
of active high frequency (HF) radiowave remote sensing instruments, 
ionosondes. The ionosonde uses stepped- or fixed-frequency probing 
radio signals transmitted from the ground for propagation into ionosphere, 
total reflection from an area of matching plasma density, and return to 
the same or different ionosonde location for detection. The detected 
echoes are evaluated for their travel time and other characteristics 
such as amplitude, phase, polarization, Doppler frequency shift, and 
angle of arrival. The signal travel time is commonly translated to 
the virtual range to the reflecting area in the ionosphere in the 
assumption of the signal propagating at the speed of light.
Stepped-frequency measurements provide adequate information to compute
true range of reflections by accounting for refractive properties of plasma.

The ionosonde designs are commonly divided in two classes, (1) a pulsed sounder
with stepped frequency that transmits short pulses to detect the echo arrival
in the time domain, and (2) a chirp-sounder that transmits a continuous
swept-frequency signal to detect its reflections in the frequency domain.
The stepped- or swept-frequency sounders produce inherently 2-dimensional
data record (frequency x travel time), ionogram. Each element of the 2D
ionogram structure holds multiple signal characteristics measured in the
ionosonde's receiver channels. Thus acquired information is processed to
detect echoes and use their attributes to derive ionospheric characteristics
along the propagation path.

The fixed-frequency measurement, while using the same concept of radio
sounding by total reflection, targets specific plasma densities in the 
ionosphere, and usually provides higher Doppler frequency resolution by 
transmitting pulses at the same frequency for several seconds. 
Simultaneously occurring reflection points in a structured ionosphere 
are identified by their different echo Doppler frequencies allowing the
computation of Doppler skymaps and plasma drift velocity.
      </Description>
      <Acknowledgement>
A heavy investment of time, effort, expertise, and 
funds continues to be made to produce, collect, quality control, interpret, 
and store ionograms. It is important that data suppliers and the 
UML DIDBase developers are appropriately acknowledged in scientific 
publications that involve analysis of data obtained from the GIRO repositories
such as DIDBase and DriftBase.
      </Acknowledgement>
      <Contact>
         <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Bodo.W.Reinisch</PersonID>
         <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
      </Contact>
      <Contact>
         <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Ivan.A.Galkin</PersonID>
         <Role>DataProducer</Role>
         <Role>TechnicalContact</Role>
      </Contact> 
      <InformationURL>
      <Name>GIRO (Global Ionospheric Radio Observatory) Home Page</Name>
      <URL>http://giro.uml.edu</URL>
      <Description>Access to real-time data and software tools</Description>
      <Language>en</Language>
      </InformationURL>
      <Association>
         <AssociationID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/GIRO</AssociationID>
         <AssociationType>Other</AssociationType>
      </Association>
    </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Sounder</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Global Ionospheric Radio Observatory</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/GIRO</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Ivan.A.Galkin</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:46Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Ivan A. Galkin</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>University of Massachusetts Lowell, Center for Atmospheric Research</OrganizationName>
    <Address>600 Suffolk Street, Lowell, MA 01851 U.S.A.&gt;</Address>
    <Email>Ivan_Galkin@uml.edu</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>978-934-4912</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Bodo.W.Reinisch</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Prof. Bodo W. Reinisch</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>University of Massachusetts at Lowell</OrganizationName>
  </Person></Spase>


