<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.0</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/DynamicsExplorer1</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Dynamics Explorer 1</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>1981-070A</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>Explorer 62</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>DE-A</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>DE 1</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>Dynamics Explorer-A</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>
          The Dynamics Explorer (DE) mission's general objective is to
          investigate the strong interactive processes coupling the hot,
          tenuous, convecting plasmas of the magnetosphere and the
          cooler, denser plasmas and gases corotating in the earth's
          ionosphere, upper atmosphere, and plasmasphere. Two
          satellites, DE 1 and DE 2, were launched together and were
          placed in polar coplanar orbits, permitting simultaneous
          measurements at high and low altitudes in the same field-line
          region.
         
          The DE 1 spacecraft (high-altitude mission) uses an
          elliptical orbit selected to allow
         
          * (1) measurements extending
          from the hot magnetospheric plasma through the plasmasphere to
          the cool ionosphere;
          * (2) global auroral imaging, wave
          measurements in the heart of the magnetosphere, and crossing
          of auroral field lines at several earth radii; and
          * (3) measurements for significant periods along a magnetic field
          flux tube.
         
          The spacecraft approximated a short polygon 137 cm
          in diameter and 115 cm high. The antennas in the X-Y plane
          measured 200-m tip-to-tip, and on the Z-axis are 9 meters tip-
          to-tip. Two six-meter booms are provided for remote
          measurements. Power is supplied by a solar cell array, mounted
          on the side and end panels. The spacecraft is spin stabilized,
          with the spin axis normal to the orbital plane, and the spin
          rate at ten plus or minus 0.1 rpm. A pulse code modulation
          (PCM) telemetry data system is used that operates in real time
          or in a tape-recorder mode. Data have been acquired on a
          science-problem-oriented basis, with closely coordinated
          operations of the various instruments, both satellites, and
          supportive experiments. Data acquired from the instruments are
          temporarily stored on tape recorders before transmission at an
          8:1 playback-to-record ratio. Additional operational
          flexibility allows a playback-to-record ratio of 4:1. The
          primary data rate is 16,384 bits per second. Since commands
          are stored in a command memory unit, spacecraft operations are
          not real time, except for the transmission of the wideband
          analog data from the Plasma Wave Instrument (81-070A-02).
         
          On October 22, 1990 science operations were terminated. On
          February 28, 1991 Dynamics Explorer 1 operations were
          offically terminated.
         
          Additional details may be found in R. A.
          Hoffman et al., Space Sci. Instrum., v. 5, n. 4, p. 349, 1981.
</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Robert.A.Hoffman</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/spacecraft/display.action?id=1981-070A</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Dynamics Explorer 1 mission</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <ObservatoryGroupID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/DE</ObservatoryGroupID>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.NearSurface</ObservatoryRegion>
</Location>
</Observatory>
<Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/DynamicsExplorer1/EICS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>DE 1 Energetic Ion Composition Spectrometer</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The energetic ion composition spectrometer (EICS) on the DE-A spacecraft is a high sensitivity, high resolution (M/Delta M greater than 10 FWHM at focus) instrument. It covers the entire mass range from less than 1 amu/e to greater than 150 amu/e in 64 mass channels, at each of 32 energy per charge steps covering the range from 0 to approximately 17 keV/e. The measurements obtained from this instrument will be used primarily to investigate the coupling between the magnetosphere and the ionosphere via the auroral acceleration region. Additional uses of the data will be to investigate the ring current loss processes, the coupling of the dayside cusp particles to the magnetosheath, and the tracing of artificially injected ions.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Edward.G.Shelley</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1981-070A-06</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Energetic Ion Composition Spectrometer on DE 1</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Spectrometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Energetic Ion Composition Spectrometer on DE 1</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/DynamicsExplorer1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/DynamicsExplorer1/Ephemeris</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>DynamicsExplorer1 Positions</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>DynamicsExplorer1 Ephemeris</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2013-04-09T00:00:00Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>DynamicsExplorer1 spacecraft positions in various coordinate systems</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Robert.E.McGuire
</PersonID>
        <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
      </Contact>
        </ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Platform</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Spacecraft position</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/DynamicsExplorer1</ObservatoryID>
  </Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/DynamicsExplorer1/PWI</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Dynamics Explorer 1 Plasma Waves Instrument (PWI)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>DE 1 PWI</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>
        The Plasma Wave Instrument (PWI) measured ac electric fields
        over the frequency range from 1 Hz to 2 MHz, and an amplitude
        range of 0.03 microvolt per meter to 100 mV per meter. Magnetic
        fields were measured from 1 Hz to 400 kHz over an approximately
        100-dB range.
       
        The objectives of this investigation were to
        measure the spatial, temporal, spectral, and wave
        characteristics (particularly the Poynting vector component
        along the magnetic field line) and the wave polarization for
        extremely-low-frequency (ELF), very-low-frequency (VLF), and
        high-frequency (HF) noise phenomena. Of special interest were
        the auroral kilometric radiation and VLF hiss, and a variety of
        electrostatic waves that may cause field-aligned acceleration of
        particles.
       
        The investigation made use of the long dipole
        antennas in the spin plane and along the Z axis, and a magnetic
        loop antenna. A single-axis search coil magnetometer and a short
        electric antenna were included for low-frequency measurements
        and electrostatic noise measurements at short wavelengths.
       
        The electronics consisted of
       
        * (1) a wideband/long baseline receiver
        with a bandwidth of 10 or 40 kHz in the range 0-2 MHz;
        * (2) a step-frequency correlator, containing two sweep-frequency
        receivers and phase detectors, sweeping 100 Hz to 400 kHz in 32
        s, and giving the phase between magnetic and electric components
        of the field;
        * (3) a low-frequency correlator containing two
        filter receivers and phase detectors (eight filters in the range
        1.78-100 Hz). The sweep rate is 8 s/spectra at the high frequency end
        (above 18 Hz); it is 32 s/spectra for frequencies for 1.8-10 Hz;
        * (4) dc monitors that measured
        the voltage difference between the two sets of long dipole
        antennas; and
        * (5) a linear wave receiver, selectable from
        1.5 to 3.0, 3 to 6, or 10 to 16 kHz bands.
       
        The wideband receiver
        was flown to transmit wideband waveform signals to the ground
        via an analog transmitter, so that detailed high-resolution
        frequency-time analysis could be performed.
       
        Since June 23, 1984
        a malfunction in the spacecraft data- handling system has
        prevented access to some PWI data. Digital measurements from the
        sweep frequency receiver system were no longer accessible.
       
        More
        details are found in S. D. Shawhan et al., Space Sci. Instrum.,
        v. 5, n. 4, p. 535, 1981.
</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Donald.A.Gurnett</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1981-070A-02</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Plasma Waves Instrument (PWI) experiment on the Dynamics Explorer 1 mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>ElectrostaticAnalyser</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Plasma Waves Instrument (PWI) on Dynamics Explorer 1</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/DynamicsExplorer1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/DynamicsExplorer1/MAGA</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Magnetic Field Observations (MAG-A)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>MAG-A</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>
         This investigation used a triaxial fluxgate magnetometer (MAG-A),
         similar to one on board DE 2, to obtain vector magnetic
         field data needed to study the magnetosphere-ionosphere-
         atmosphere coupling.
        
         The primary objective of this
         investigation was to obtain measurements of field-aligned
         currents in the auroral oval and over the polar cap at two
         different altitudes. This was accomplished using the two
         spacecraft and correlations of these measurements with
         observations of electric fields, plasma waves, suprathermal
         particles, thermal particles, and auroral images obtained from
         investigation 81-070A-03. Ultra low frequency (ULF) waves were
         also studied.
        
         The magnetometer incorporated its own 12-bit
         analog-to-digital converter, a 4-bit digital compensation
         register for each axis, and a system control to generate a 48-
         bit data word consisting of a 16-bit representation of the
         field measured along each of the three magnetometer axes. Track
         and hold modules were used to obtain simultaneous samples on
         all three axes. Instrument bandwidth was 25 Hz. The instrument
         dynamic range was plus or minus 6.2E4 nT, and the resolution
         was plus or minus 1.5 nT in the 6.2E4 nT region, plus or minus
         0.25 nT in the 1.E3 nT region, and plus or minus 0.02 nT in the
         80 nT region. The magnetometer's digital compensation of the
         ambient field was nominally in 8.E3 nT increments.
        
         Further
         details are in W. H. Farthing et al., Space Sci. Instrum., v.
         5, n. 4, p. 551, 1981.
</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Masahisa.Sugiura</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1981-070A&amp;ex=1</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Magnetic Field Observations (MAG-A) experiment on the Dynamics Explorer 1 mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Magnetometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Magnetic Field Observations (MAG-A) on Dynamics Explorer 1</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/DynamicsExplorer1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/DynamicsExplorer1/SAI</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>DE 1 Spin-Scan Auroral Imager</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The Spin-Scan Auroral Imager (SAI) provided global auroral imaging at visible and ultraviolet wavelengths. It acquired (1) images at several visible wavelengths; (2) images within a vacuum ultraviolet "window", which allowed usable imaging of the aurora in the sunlit ionosphere; and (3) photometric measurements of the hydrogen corona. This investigation provided data that advanced the knowledge of (1) the spatial and temporal character of the entire auroral oval at both visible and vacuum ultraviolet wavelengths (with good time resolution); (2) the association of auroral and magnetospheric plasmas with the diverse auroral emission features; (3) the relationship of the auroral emissions with field-aligned currents; (4) the energy deposited in the auroral ionosphere by charged particles; (5) the acceleration mechanism responsible for "inverted-V" precipitation events; (6) the role of the polar cap and magnetotail in auroral and magnetospheric dynamics; and (7) the time-dependent distribution of neutral hydrogen in the ring current and polar regions. Of the three photometers, two measured radiation in the visible wavelength range and one measured it in the UV. A full image was 36 deg by 120 deg. Some of the wavelengths were 3914, 5577, 6300, 3175, 1304, 1216, 1400-1600, and 1400-1700 A. The spatial resolution of a pixel (picture element) at auroral altitudes in the nadir direction was 28 km at a spacecraft altitude of 1 earth radius (Re). At 3.9 Re altitude this resolution was 109 km. For each photometer, the time resolution was 3 to 12 minutes per image. For visible wavelengths, the photometers had a wide-angle collimator; a super-reflecting scanning mirror; a mirror-drive motor; a quartz field lens; an image-viewing assembly of field-stop, pinhole and collimating lens; a filter wheel with narrow-band interference filters; and a small photomultiplier tube with an extended red photocathode. The vacuum ultraviolet imaging photometer was a spin-scan Newtonian telescope. The first optical element was an aluminum scanning mirror with a MgF2 overcoat. The collimation and mirror drive were similar to that used for the visible imaging photometer. A filter wheel with MgF2, CaF2, and BaF2 filters allowed global imaging from 1370 to 1700, and at 1304, 1356, and 1216 A. The detector was a photomultiplier tube with a CsI photocathode and a MgF2 window. Additional details are found in L. A. Frank et al., Space Sci. Instrum., v. 5, n. 4, p. 369, 1981.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Louis.A.Frank</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1981-070A-03</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Spin-Scan Auroral Imager on DE 1</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Imager</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Spin-Scan Auroral Imager on DE 1</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/DynamicsExplorer1</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
      <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/DynamicsExplorer1/RIMS</ResourceID>
      <ResourceHeader>
         <ResourceName>Retarding Ion Mass Spectrometer, RIMS</ResourceName>
         <ReleaseDate>2019-06-12T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
         <Description>The Retarding Ion Mass Spectrometer, RIMS, Experiment onboard the DE-1 Satellite was designed to perform Energy and Mass per Charge Analysis on Low Energy Ions (Energy less than 50 eV) with Mass/Charge ranging from 1 amu/Z to 40 amu/Z. RIMS significantly improved capabilities over previous Retarding Potential Analyzer, RPA, Instrumenpt by providing Ion Mass/Charge Separation so that RPA and Spin Curves are obtained separately for each programmed Species. These enhanced Instrument Capabilities, combined with the DE-1 Orbit, produced a unique opportunity to investigate the variable Dynamics and Composition of the Low Energy Ion Population in the near Earth Space Environment.

DE-1/RIMS consists of four Instrument Assemblies interconnected to form one Experiment. Three of the Assemblies are Sensor Heads and one is the Central Electronics Assembly, CEA. The three Heads are labeled according to the Mounting Axis on the DE-1 Spacecraft: Radial, +Z, and -Z. The radial Sensor Views perpendicular to the Spacecraft Spin Axis, while the +Z and -Z Sensors on the Ends of the Spacecraft View parallel and anti-parallel to the Spin Axis. The Central Electronics Assembly provides the Spacecraft Interface, all Data Processing, Command Decoding, and complete Timing Control of the entire RIMS Experiment. The Description Text is adapted from Content on the DE-1 Retarding Ion Mass Spectrometer, RIMS, Overview Web Page, listed in the Information URL below.</Description>
         <Acknowledgement>Please acknowledge the Principal Investigator, C.R. Chappell</Acknowledgement>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Charles.R.Chappell</PersonID>
            <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
         </Contact>
         <Contact>
            <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Lee.Frost.Bargatze</PersonID>
            <Role>MetadataContact</Role>
         </Contact>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>DE-1 Retarding Ion Mass Spectrometer, RIMS, Overview Web Page, MSFC</Name>
            <URL>https://spacephysics.msfc.nasa.gov/projects/rims/</URL>
            <Description>Information on the Dynamics Explorer 1, DE-1, Retarding Ion Mass Spectrometer, RIMS, at Marshall Space Flight Center</Description>
         </InformationURL>
         <InformationURL>
            <Name>NSSDC Master Catalog Listing for the Dynamics Explorer 1, DE1, Retarding Ion Mass Spectrometer, RIMS Instrument</Name>
            <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1981-070A-04</URL>
            <Description>Information about the Dynamics Explorer 1, DE-1, Retarding Ion Mass Spectrometer, RIMS</Description>
         </InformationURL>
      </ResourceHeader>
      <InstrumentType>RetardingPotentialAnalyser</InstrumentType>
      <InvestigationName>Dynamics Explorer 1, DE1, Retarding Ion Mass Spectrometer, RIMS</InvestigationName>
      <OperatingSpan>
         <StartDate>1981-09-15T00:00:00.000</StartDate>
         <StopDate>1991-02-18T23:59:59.999</StopDate>
      </OperatingSpan>
      <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/DynamicsExplorer1</ObservatoryID>
   </Instrument><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Louis.A.Frank</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Prof. Louis A. Frank</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>University of Iowa</OrganizationName>
    <Address>Department of Physics and Astronomy, University of Iowa, Iowa City, IA 52242</Address>
    <Email>frank@iowasp.physics.uiowa.edu</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+1 319 335 1695</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Edward.G.Shelley</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Edward G. Shelley</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Lockheed Palo Alto Research Laboratory</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Masahisa.Sugiura</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Masahisa Sugiura</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Tokai University</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
      <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Lee.Frost.Bargatze</ResourceID>
      <ReleaseDate>2012-06-13T12:34:56.789</ReleaseDate>
      <PersonName>Lee Frost Bargatze</PersonName>
      <OrganizationName>Institute of Geophysics and Planetary Physics and the Department of Earth and Space Sciences, University of California, Los Angeles</OrganizationName>
      <Address>Institute of Geophysics and Planetary Physics, University of California Los Angeles, Box 951567, Los Angeles, CA 90095-1567</Address>
      <Email>lfb@igpp.ucla.edu</Email>
      <PhoneNumber>+1 310 206 6073</PhoneNumber>
   </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Robert.A.Hoffman</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Robert A. Hoffman</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>GSFC-Code 696</OrganizationName>
    <Email>bob_barb@earthlink.net</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+1-301-286-7386</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Donald.A.Gurnett</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Prof. Donald A. Gurnett</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>University of Iowa</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Charles.R.Chappell</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Charles R. Chappell</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Vanderbilt University</OrganizationName>
  </Person></Spase>


