<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<Spase xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema/spase-2_2_0.xsd">
  <Version>2.2.0</Version>
  <Observatory>
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/AE-C</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>AE-C</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>1973-101A</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>Atmosphere Explorer-C</AlternateName>
      <AlternateName>Explorer 51</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The purpose of the AE-C mission was to investigate the thermosphere, with emphasis on the energy transfer and processes that govern its state. The study of photochemical processes accompanying the absorption of solar UV radiation in the earth's atmosphere was accomplished by making closely coordinated measurements of reacting constituents and the solar input. The AE-C spacecraft was a multi-sided polyhedron with a diameter of approximately 1.4 m. It weighed about 660 kg including 85 kg of instrumentation. The initial elliptical orbit was altered many times in the first year of life by means of an onboard propulsion system employing a 3.5-lb thruster. The purpose of these changes was to alter the perigee height to 129 km. After this period, the orbit was circularized and was raised periodically to about 390 km when it would decay to 250 km altitude. During the first year, the latitude of perigee moved from about 10 deg up to 68 deg north and then down to about 60 deg south. During this period about two cycles through all local times were completed. The spacecraft could be operated in either of two modes: spinning at a nominal 4 rpm or despun to 1 revolution per orbit. The spin axis was perpendicular to the orbit plane. Power was supplied by a solar cell array. The spacecraft used a PCM telemetry data system that operated in real time or in a tape recorder mode. The payload included instrumentation for the measurement of solar UV; the composition of positive ions and neutral particles; the density and temperature of neutral particles, positive ions and electrons; the measurement of airglow emissions, photoelectron energy spectra, and proton and electron fluxes up to 25 keV. More details can be found in A. Dalgarno et al., Radio Sci.,v. 8, n. 4, p. 263, 1973.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Nelson.W.Spencer</PersonID>
        <Role>ProjectScientist</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/spacecraft/display.action?id=1973-101A</URL>
        <Description>Information about the AE-C mission</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <ObservatoryGroupID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/AE</ObservatoryGroupID>
    <Location>
      <ObservatoryRegion>Earth.NearSurface</ObservatoryRegion>
</Location>
</Observatory>
<Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/AE-C/BIMS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Bennett Ion-Mass Spectrometer (BIMS)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>BIMS</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This experiment was flown to measure, throughout the AE-C orbit, the individual concentrations of
   all thermal ion species in the mass range of 1 to 72 atomic mass units (u), and in the ambient
   density range from 8.E1 to 5.E6 ions/cc. Any combination of the following three mass ranges,
   expressed in u, were selected by ground command: range A, -1 to 4, range B, -2 to 18,
   range C, -8 to 72. Each range was normally scanned in 1.7 s (approximately 12 km along orbit).
   Normal operation consisted in sequence ABCABC (1 to 72 u in 5.1 s). Laboratory and inflight
   determination of spectrometer efficiency and mass discrimination permitted direct conversion
   of measured ion currents to ambient concentrations. The experiment's four primary mechanical
   components were guard ring and ion-analyzer tube, collector and preamplifier assembly, vent,
   and main electronics housing. The guard ring was normally at ground potential, but it could
   be placed at -6 V by command if desirable, e.g., if the spacecraft acquired a positive charge.
   A three-stage Bennett tube with 7 to 5 cycle drift spaces was flown and was modified to permit
   ion concentration measurements to be obtained at low altitudes. The frequency of the 30 V
   peak-to-peak RF voltage varied with the mass range measured: range A, -10 MHz, range B, -5
   MHz, and range C, -2.5 MHz. Primary analog instrument output was a compressed ion current
   spectrum which displayed the full dynamic range of the amplifier system on a single
   telemetry channel. Onboard data processing provided a readout of primary experiment
   data in the form of two digital words for each peak in the ion spectrum. One 8-bit word
   indicated peak amplitude (current) and the other 8-bit word identified sweep position,
   i.e., species identification. More complete details can be found in H. C.
   Brinton et al., Radio Sci., v. 8, n. 4, p. 323, 1973. NSSDC has all the useful data that
   exist from this investigation.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Henry.C.Brinton</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1975-107A-10</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Bennett Ion-Mass Spectrometer (BIMS) experiment on the AE-C mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Radio Science Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1029/RS008i004p00323</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Bennett Ion-Mass Spectrometer (BIMS) on the AE-C mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>MassSpectrometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Bennett Ion-Mass Spectrometer (BIMS) on AE-C</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/AE-C</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/AE-C/PES</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Photoelectron Spectrometer (PES)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>PES</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This experiment was designed to provide information on the intensity, angular distribution,
   energy spectrum, and net flow along field lines, of electrons in the thermosphere with energies between
   1 and 500 eV. The instrument consisted of two identical oppositely directed hemispherical electrostatic
   analyzers, and 30 operating modes. Each spectrometer had a relative energy resolution of plus or minus
   2.5% and a geometric factor on the order of 0.001 sq cm sr, independent of electron energy. Three separate
   energy ranges could be sensed: 0 to 25, 0 to 100, or 0 to 500 eV. Measurements from these intervals could
   be sequenced in five different ways. Data could be taken from either sensor separately, or alternately with
   time resolution varying from 0.25 to 8 s. There were two deflection voltage scan rates determined by
   spacecraft clock. This voltage was changed in 64 steps, and was done at 4 or 16 steps per telemetry frame.
   With 16 frames/s, this allowed a choice of either one 64-point spectrum, or four 16-point spectra in 1 s.
   The longest (8 s) cycle of data involved observations using increasing voltage steps for the lowest,
   middle, lowest, then highest energy ranges (in that order) for 1 s each. A repeat for decreasing voltage
   step completed the cycle. A more detailed description of this experiment may be found in
   J. P. Doering et al., Radio Sci., v. 8, n. 4, p. 387, 1973. NSSDC has all the useful data that
   exist from this investigation.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/John.P.Doering</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1973-101A-03</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Photoelectron Spectrometer (PES) experiment on the AE-C mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Radio Science Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1029/RS008i004p00387</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Photoelectron Spectrometer (PES) experiment on the AE-C mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>ElectrostaticAnalyser</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Photoelectron Spectrometer (PES) on AE-C</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/AE-C</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/AE-C/VAE</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Visible Airglow Photometer (VAE)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>VAE</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This experiment contained a filter photometer designed to measure various airglow and auroral
   features in the spectral range between 3000 and 7500 A. The primary information obtained from this experiment
   was the rates of excitation of the atomic and molecular constituents of the thermosphere. For the AE-C mission,
   the following six specific lines and bands were chosen for study since they play an important role in the
   photochemical energy balance of the atmosphere (expressed in Angstroms): 3371, 4278, 5200, 5577, 6300, and 7319.
   The emissions were measured in pairs: 5577 and 6300, 7319 and calibration, 3371 and 5577, 5200 and 7319, 4278
   and 3371, calibration and 5200, and 6300 and 4278. Two optical systems viewed at right angles to each other.
   Each one employed a combination of a simple objective lens and field stop to define the field of view, and
   each contained a multistage light baffle. The wide-angle high-sensitivity system (designated channel 2) had
   a field of view of 3 deg half-angle, and was used to measure the nightglow, dayglow above the satellite, and
   other weak emission features. The less sensitive system (designated channel 1) had a field of view of
   approximately 3/4 deg half-angle and was used for dayglow and nightglow horizon measurements, as well as
   discrete auroral features which showed strong spatial gradients. Both optical channels had a diameter of 2.2 cm.
   They shared a filter wheel that contained six interference filters at the wavelengths identified above, and
   two other positions. One was a dark position for noise measurements, and the other was a calibrate position.
   The dynamic range of the instrument was 1.E16 photons per s sq m (1.E6 rayleighs). In order that the sensors
   would respond in a fraction of a second to large changes in surface brightness without any noticeable enhancement
   in the background count rate, each one contained a 1/100 attenuator and an electronic circuit to back-bias
   the cathode. With these protective features it was possible to measure a dark feature with no apparent enhancement
   in background within 120 ms after a direct view of the sun. Photons reaching the cathode were recorded using a
   pulse-counting system. For more experiment details, see P. B. Hays et al., Radio Sci., v. 8, n. 4, p. 369, 1973.
   NSSDC has all the useful data that exist from this investigation.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Paul.B.Hays</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1973-101A-14</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Visible Airglow Photometer (VAE) experiment on the AE-C mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Radio Science Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1029/RS008i004p00369</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Visible Airglow Photometer (VAE) experiment on the AE-C mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Photometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Visible Airglow Photometer (VAE) on AE-C</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/AE-C</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/AE-C/OSS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Open-Source Neutral Mass Spectrometer</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>OSS</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The objective of this experiment was to contribute to a study of the chemical,
   dynamic, and energetic processes that control the structure of the thermosphere by providing
   direct, in situ measurements of both major and minor neutral atmospheric constituents having
   masses in the range from 1 to 48 atomic mass units (u). A double-focusing Mattauch-Herzog
   magnetic deflection mass spectrometer with an impact ion source was flown. Two ion collectors were
   included to measure ions differing in mass by a factor of 8, i.e., the two mass ranges covered were
   1 to 6 u and 6 to 48 u. In the ion source the neutral species were ionized by means of electron
   impact. At altitudes greater than 380 km, ion currents were measured with an electron multiplier
   counting individual ions. Counts were accumulated for 1/20 s before automatically switching to a
   different mass number. While complete mass spectra could be swept, in the common mode of operation
   peak stepping was employed, with readings on the principal peaks in the mass spectrum being repeated
   approximately every 0.5 s and on other species less frequently. Data below 380 km were measured using
   an electrometer. In addition to the peak stepping mode, there were several other operating modes which
   were selected by ground command. In the fly-through mode, the ion source voltages were adjusted so
   that there was no electric field to draw ions out of the electron beam when they were formed.
   Ambient particles striking the ion source retained energies less than 0.1 eV, which was not high
   enough to overcome the negative space charge potential holding the ions in the beam. Those
   ambient particles that did not strike the ion source retained their incoming energy of several
   eV after ionization and escaped into the accelerating region of the analyzer. The electron accelerating
   potential was 75 eV in normal mode operation and was 25 eV in the fly-through mode. In another
   operating mode, the instrument switched automatically to a sequence of masses of particular interest
   such as, e.g., between masses 16 and 32 or between masses 28 and 32. More details can be found in
   A. O. Nier et al., Radio Sci., v. 8, n. 4, p. 271, 1973. NSSDC has all the useful data that exist
   from this investigation.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Alfred.O.C.Nier</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1973-101A-07</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Open-Source Neutral Mass Spectrometer experiment on the AE-C mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Radio Science Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1029/RS008i004p00271</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Open-Source Neutral Mass Spectrometer on the AE-C mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>MassSpectrometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Open-Source Neutral Mass Spectrometer on AE-C</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/AE-C</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/AE-C/MESA</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Atmospheric Density Accelerometer (MESA)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>MESA</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The miniature electrostatic analyzer (MESA) obtained data on the neutral density of the
   atmosphere in the altitude range of 120 to 400 km from the measurements of satellite deceleration due
   to aerodynamic drag. The instrument consisted of three single-axis accelerometers, mounted mutually at
   right angles, two in the spacecraft X-Y plane and the other along the Z-axis. The instrument determined
   the applied acceleration from the electrostatic force required to recenter a proof mass. The output of
   the device was a digital pulse rate proportional to the applied acceleration. The measurements allowed
   determination of the density of the neutral atmosphere, monitored the thrust of the orbit-adjust
   propulsion system (OAPS), determined the satellite minimum altitude, measured spacecraft roll, and
   provided some attitude-sensing information. Spacecraft nutations of less than 0.01 deg were monitored.
   The instrument had three sensitivity ranges: 8.E-3 earth's gravity (G) in OAPS monitor mode; 4.E-4 G
   between 120 (plus or minus 2%) and 280 km (plus or minus 10%); and 2.E-5 G between 180 km (plus or minus 2%)
   and 400 km (plus or minus 10%). Numbers in parentheses represent errors; in addition, there may be a
   systematic error of up to plus or minus 5% due to drag coefficient uncertainty. The highest measurement
   altitude was determined assuming the instrument could sense to 0.2% of full scale. More details can be
   found in K. S. W. Champion et al., Radio Sci., v. 8, n. 4, p. 297, 1973. NSSDC has all the useful
   data that exist from this investigation.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Kenneth.S.W.Champion</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1973-101A-02</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Atmospheric Density Accelerometer (MESA) experiment on the AE-C mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Radio Science Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1029/RS008i004p00297</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Atmospheric Density Accelerometer experiment on the AE-C mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>ElectrostaticAnalyser</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Atmospheric Density Accelerometer (MESA) on AE-C</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/AE-C</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/AE-C/NATE</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Neutral Atmosphere Temperature (NATE)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>NATE</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This experiment measured the kinetic temperature of the neutral atmosphere by determining the
   instantaneous density of molecular nitrogen in a spherical chamber coupled to the atmosphere through a
   knife-edged orifice. Analysis of the measured molecular nitrogen density variation over a spin cycle with
   a knowledge of the satellite's motion and orientation led to a determination of the ambient temperature,
   independent of scale height. A measurement of the ambient nitrogen density was also obtained. An alternate
   measurement of neutral temperature was also undertaken, using a baffle inserted in front of the orifice to
   intercept a portion of the gas particle stream entering the chamber. When the satellite was in the despun
   mode, the baffle was made to oscillate in the stepwise fashion to interrupt the particle stream seen by
   the orificed chamber. These chamber density variations were interpreted to yield the neutral gas kinetic
   temperature. A dual-filament ion source sampled the thermalized molecular nitrogen in the chamber and
   produced an ion beam density proportional to the nitrogen chamber density. From the source, this ionized
   nitrogen beam was directed from a quadrupole analyzer, tuned to pass those particles whose mass-to-charge
   ratio (M/Q) is 28, on to an electron multiplier. The output pulses were amplified and counted in a 16-bit
   accumulator. The experiment also provided measurements of neutral atmospheric composition, when commanded
   into the appropriate mode and, for the first time measured the local wind (vertical motions). The wind values
   were determined by measurement of the "stream" position relative to the satellite velocity. When the spacecraft
   was in the despun mode, the nitrogen density was measured except when the particle stream was interrupted by
   the baffle. The sensor was vacuum-sealed prior to launch and opened to the atmosphere after the spacecraft
   was in orbit. More experiment details can be found in N. W. Spencer et al., Radio Sci., v. 8, n. 4, p. 287, 1973.
   NSSDC has all the useful data that exist from this investigation.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Nelson.W.Spencer</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1973-101A-09</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Neutral Atmosphere Temperature (NATE) experiment on the AE-C mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Radio Science Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1029/RS008i004p00287</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Neutral Atmosphere Temperature experiment on the AE-C mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Unspecified</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Neutral Atmosphere Temperature (NATE) on AE-C</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/AE-C</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/AE-C/CEP</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Cylindrical Electrostatic Probes (CEP)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>CEP</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>The CEP consisted of two identical instruments designed to measure electron temperatures,
   electron and ion concentrations, ion mass, and spacecraft potential. One probe was oriented along the
   spin axis of the spacecraft (normally perpendicular to the orbit plane), and the other radially so
   that it could observe in the direction of the velocity vector once each 15-s spin period. Each
   instrument was a retarding potential Langmuir probe device that produced a current-voltage (I-V)
   curve for a known voltage pattern placed on the collector. Electrometers were used to measure the
   current. There were two systems of operation (one with two modes and another with three modes)
   using collector voltage patterns between plus and minus 5 volts. Most modes involved an automatic or
   fixed adjustment of collector voltage limits (and/or electrometer output) such that the region of
   interest on the I-V profile provided high resolution. Each system was designed for use with only one
   of the probes, but they could be interswitched to provide backup redundancy. The best measurements
   in the most favorable modes provided 1-s time resolution; electron temperature between 300 and 1.0E4
   deg K (10% accuracy); ion density between 1.0E4 and 1.0E7 ions/cc (10-20% accuracy); electron
   density between 50 and 1.0E6 electrons/cc; and ion mass at ion densities above 1.0E4 ions/cc. Each
   probe had a collector electrode extending from the central axis of a cylindrical guard ring. The
   2.5-cm-long guard ring was at the end of a 25-cm boom, and the collector extended another 7.5 cm
   beyond the guard ring. The boom, guard, and collector were 0.2 cm in diameter. More detailed
   information can be found in L. H. Brace et al., Radio Sci., v. 8, n. 4, p. 341, 1973. NSSDC has
   all the useful data that exist from this investigation.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Larry.H.Brace</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1973-101A-01</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Cylindrical Electrostatic Probes experiment on the AE-C mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>Radio Science Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1029/RS008i004p00341</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Cylindrical Electrostatic Probes on the AE-C mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>LangmuirProbe</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Cylindrical Electrostatic Probes (CEP) on AE-C</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/AE-C</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/AE-C/UVNO</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Ultraviolet Nitric-Oxide (UVNO)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>UVNO</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This Ultraviolet Nitric-Oxide Experiment (UVNO) consisted of a two-channel fixed-grating
   Ebert-Fastie spectrometer which measured the airglow in the (1, 0) Gamma band in a 15-A region centered
   at 2149 A. The observed intensity was produced by resonance fluorescence of sunlight by the nitric-oxide
   molecules in the instrument's field of view. The intensity profiles obtained yielded altitude profiles of
   nitric-oxide density as a function of time and location. Profiles were measured along the track of the
   satellite at times when it was on the sunlit side of the earth. The remote sensing character of the UVNO
   experiment permitted measurements of nitric-oxide to be made at altitudes both above and below satellite
   perigee. As the spacecraft spun, the spectrometer, which looked outward through the rim of the satellite,
   repeatedly had its field of view carried down through the atmosphere onto the earth's limb, and altitude
   profiles of the emitted airglow intensity were obtained. Below some altitude the measured signal at
   2149 A was contaminated by rayleigh-scattered sunlight. To correct for this contamination, a second channel
   measured only scattered light intensity in a 12-A region centered at 2190 A. The two channels were
   optically and electrically independent. Nitric-oxide airglow intensity was determined by taking the
   difference between these two measurements. The sensor's spherical fused-quartz telescope mirror had a
   125-mm focal length, and focused incident light on the entrance slit of the spectrometer. From this
   slit the light struck one half of the Ebert mirror and was collimated onto the grating. The 3600-lines-per-mm
   grating returned it collimated to the other half of the mirror, and the light was focused on two exit slits.
   The spectrometer field of view was 4 deg X 1/4 deg, with the long axis parallel to the spacecraft's spin axis,
   and therefore parallel to the viewed limb. In normal operation each channel was integrated for 20.8 ms and
   was read out alternately at 10.4-ms intervals. The instrument was protected against contamination from
   internal scattering of off-axis undispersed light. More experiment details can be found in C. A.
   Barth et al., Radio Sci., v. 8, n. 4, p. 379, 1973. NSSDC has all the useful data that exist from
   this investigation.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Charles.A.Barth</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1973-101A-13</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Ultraviolet Nitric-Oxide (UVNO) experiment on the AE-C mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Radio Science Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1029/RS008i004p00379</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Ultraviolet Nitric-Oxide (UVNO) experiment on the AE-C mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>Spectrometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Ultraviolet Nitric-Oxide (UVNO) on AE-C</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/AE-C</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/AE-C/NACE</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Closed-Source Neutral Mass Spectrometer</ResourceName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This experiment measured in situ the spatial distribution and temporal changes of the
   concentrations of the neutral atmospheric species. In addition, new insight into in situ measurement
   techniques was obtained from comparisons of these measurements with those obtained from other on-board
   experiments; namely, open source spectrometer (73-101A-07), solar EUV spectrophotometer (73-101A-06),
   and density accelerometer (73-101A-02). The mass-spectrometer sensor had a gold-plated stainless steel
   thermalizing chamber and ion source, a hyperbolic-rod quadrupole analyzer, and an off-axis electron
   multiplier. Five different sequences of mass selections were available and, expressed in atomic mass
   units (u), were (a) geophysical -1, 2, 4, total, 16, 28, 32, selected, 40, (b) analytical -12, 14,
   18, 20, 22, 30, 44, calibrate, zero, (c) individual -selected, selected, selected, ... (any mass 1 to 44),
   (d) sweep digital -1, 2, 3, 4, 5, ... 45 (in 3/16 u steps), (e) sweep analog -2, 3, 4, 5, ... 45
   (continuous). Five operational formats were available and selected by ground command, and each one
   contained a different combination of the five mass selection sequences listed above. When operating in
   the "normal format," the analyzer measured all masses in the range 1 to 44 with emphasis on hydrogen,
   helium, oxygen, nitrogen, and argon. Another format was optimized for minor constituent studies of any
   individual gas species in the measured range. Spatial resolution was determined primarily by the mode
   of spacecraft operation. In orbit, the presealed spectrometer was opened, and the atmospheric
   constituents passed through a knife-edged orifice into the thermalization chamber and ion source.
   Selected ions left the quadrupole analyzer through a weak focusing lens and were accelerated into a
   14-stage electron multiplier, where they were turned 90 deg to strike the first dynode. For each impacting
   ion, the multiplier output was a pulse of 2.E6 electrons. These output pulses constituted the measurement,
   and the count rate was proportional to the chamber density of the selected species. These density values
   were then converted to ambient concentrations. The analyzer normally operated at a resolution of 1 u over
   the mass range. Pulses occurring during 0.015-s integration intervals were accumulated in a 16-bit counter.
   Multiple integration periods (up to 16) were assigned to each measurement for less dense atmospheric species.
   Automatically selected ranges of ionizing electron currents were used. The overall dynamic range of the
   measurements was greater than 1.E7. More experiment details can be found in
   D. T. Pelz et al., Radio Sci., v. 8, n. 4, p. 277, 1973. NSSDC has all the useful data that exist
   from this investigation.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/D.T.Pelz</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1973-101A-08</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Closed-Source Neutral Mass Spectrometer experiment on the AE-C mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Radio Science Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1029/RS008i004p00277</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the neutral-atmosphere composition experiment on the AE-C mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>MassSpectrometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Closed-Source Neutral Mass Spectrometer on AE-C</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/AE-C</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/AE-C/LEE</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Low-Energy Electrons (LEE)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>LEE</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This experiment provided direct measurements of the energy input into the upper
   atmosphere due to electrons and protons in the energy range of 0.2 to 25 keV. The experiment
   acquired differential measurements of the energy influx and angular distribution. There were
   two detectors measuring electrons and protons from 0.2 to 25 keV in 16 logarithmically spaced
   steps, and one detector measuring 5 keV electrons continuously. Each detector consisted of a
   cylindrical electrostatic analyzer for species and energy selection, and a Spiraltron electron
   multiplier for particle detection. Energy distributions were obtained by applying different
   fixed or stepped voltages to the deflection plates. Distributions in angle were measured using
   the spacecraft spin and the analyzers' positions on the spacecraft. In the despun modes,
   measurements were obtained at 45 deg to the spacecraft equator, and radially away from the
   earth. Detector look angles were chosen to give optimum magnetic pitch-angle coverage when the
   spacecraft was moving either poleward or equatorward. All detectors were identical in construction
   and used 1- x 6-mm entrance apertures. Counts were accumulated over 55.7 ms and read out each
   main telemetry frame (62.5 ms). The two stepped detectors moved one energy step once each main
   frame with the same accumulation time, requiring about 1 s for a complete cycle of steps. More
   complete details of this experiment may be found in
   R. A. Hoffman et al., Radio Sci., v. 8, n. 4, p. 393, 1973. NSSDC has all the useful data that
   exist from this investigation.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/Robert.A.Hoffman</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1973-101A-12</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Low-Energy Electrons (LEE) experiment on the AE-C mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Radio Science Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1029/RS008i004p00393</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Low-Energy Electrons experiment on the AE-C mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>ElectrostaticAnalyser</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Low-Energy Electrons (LEE) on AE-C</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/AE-C</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/AE-C/RPA</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Retarding Potential Analyser/Drift Meter (RPA)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>RPA</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>This experiment was designed to determine vector ion drift velocities, ion concentration and
   temperature, and spacecraft potential. An ionospheric irregularity index was also obtained from the ion
   concentration sensor. The experiment consisted of a retarding potential analyzer with four planar sensor
   heads. The sensor head used for ion drift measurements was co-located with another head, and all were spaced
   nearly equally, looking outward from the satellite equator. Since the satellite spin axis was perpendicular
   to the orbit plane, these heads could observe along the spacecraft velocity vector in either the spin or
   despun mode of the spacecraft. The primary objective of this experiment was to provide accurate ion
   temperatures with other measurements being of secondary importance. Three of the sensor heads were similar.
   They had two grounded entrance grids, two retarding grids, a suppressor grid, a shield grid, and a collector.
   A linear sweep voltage (32 or 22 to 0 V, up or down) was normally applied to the retarding grids in 0.75 s.
   Interpretation of the resulting current-voltage profiles provided the ion temperature, the ion and electron
   concentration, some ion composition information, vehicle potential and plasma drift velocity parallel to
   the velocity vector. Two of the three similar sensors had an additional grid between the entrance and
   retarding grids in order to protect inner grids from ion bombardment during electron measurements. The
   other significant feature of these two sensors was that a small positive collector bias could be applied
   to assure adequate access of thermal electrons to the collector. With the retarding grid at constant zero
   volts, current changes could be observed for 3-s periods to obtain gradients of ion concentration.
   Electron parameters were measured in a manner similar to ions. Ions in mass ranges 1 to 4, 14 to 16, 24 to 32
   and greater than 40 atomic mass units could be identified. The fourth sensor head was for the ion-drift
   velocity measurements, and consisted of four grounded grids, a negatively biased suppressor grid, and a
   four-segment collector. Differences in various collector segment currents provided ion-drift directional
   component information. More details of this experiment are available in
   W. B. Hanson et al., Radio Sci., v. 8, n. 4, p. 333, 1973. NSSDC has all the useful data that exist
   from this investigation.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/William.B.Hanson</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1973-101A-04</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Retarding Potential Analyser/Drift Meter (RPA) experiment on the AE-C mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Radio Science Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1029/RS008i004p00333</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Retarding Potential Analyser/Drift Meter (RPA) experiment on the AE-C mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>RetardingPotentialAnalyser</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Retarding Potential Analyser/Drift Meter (RPA) on AE-C</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/AE-C</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Instrument xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Instrument/AE-C/MIMS</ResourceID>
    <ResourceHeader>
      <ResourceName>Magnetic Ion-Mass Spectrometer (MIMS)</ResourceName>
      <AlternateName>MIMS</AlternateName>
      <ReleaseDate>2019-05-05T12:34:56Z</ReleaseDate>
      <Description>A magnetic ion-mass spectrometer was flown to measure in situ the concentrations of the
   ambient ion species in the mass range from 1 to 90 atomic mass units (u). It was mounted on the satellite
   equator normal to the spin axis, and the entrance aperture faced forward when the spacecraft was in the
   despun mode. The electric and magnetic fields were arranged to produce a mass spectrum along the focal
   plane following the magnetic analyzer. Three slits were placed along the focal plane in appropriate places
   to simultaneously collect ions in the mass ratios 1 to 4 to 16. Ionospheric ions were accelerated into the
   analyzer system by a negative voltage that varied from -1060 to -225 V. The three mass ranges measured
   simultaneously were 1 to 4, 4 to 16, and 16 to 90 u. Following each slit was an electron multiplier and
   a logarithmic electrometer-amplifier detector. The detector output could be measured directly for an
   analog output, or it could be fed to a "peak" circuit that determined the amplitude of each peak in the
   spectrum. Only the amplitude of each peak was telemetered in the primary peaks mode, and in this mode
   the time required to simultaneously sweep all three mass ranges was 1 s. Other modes of operation were
   possible. In the analog short mode, the three mass ranges were swept in 4 s, alternating with 1-s "peaks"
   mode scans. An 8-s sweep was required in the analog long mode, again alternating with 1-s peaks mode scan.
   An option existed in the locked mode to continuously measure any set of mass numbers in the ratio 1 to 4
   to 16 to give high spatial resolution. More experiment details can be found in
   J. H. Hoffman et al., Radio Sci., v. 8, n. 4, p. 315, 1973. NSSDC has all the useful data that exist
   from this experiment.</Description>
      <Contact>
        <PersonID>spase://SMWG/Person/John.H.Hoffman</PersonID>
        <Role>PrincipalInvestigator</Role>
</Contact>
      <InformationURL>
        <Name>NSSDC's Master Catalog</Name>
        <URL>https://nssdc.gsfc.nasa.gov/nmc/experiment/display.action?id=1973-101A-10</URL>
        <Description>Information about the Magnetic Ion-Mass Spectrometer (MIMS) experiment on the AE-C mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
   <InformationURL>
        <Name>Radio Science Journal Article</Name>
        <URL>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1029/RS008i004p00315</URL>
        <Description>Detailed information about the Magnetic Ion-Mass Spectrometer experiment on the AE-C mission.</Description>
</InformationURL>
</ResourceHeader>
    <InstrumentType>MassSpectrometer</InstrumentType>
    <InvestigationName>Magnetic Ion-Mass Spectrometer (MIMS) on AE-C</InvestigationName>
    <ObservatoryID>spase://SMWG/Observatory/AE-C</ObservatoryID>
</Instrument><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Larry.H.Brace</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Mr. Larry H. Brace</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>GSFC-Code 910.4</OrganizationName>
    <PhoneNumber>+1-301-286-8575</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Kenneth.S.W.Champion</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Kenneth S. W. Champion</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>USAF Phillips Laboratory</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Charles.A.Barth</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. Charles A. Barth</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>University of Colorado</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Robert.A.Hoffman</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Robert A. Hoffman</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>GSFC-Code 696</OrganizationName>
    <Email>bob_barb@earthlink.net</Email>
    <PhoneNumber>+1-301-286-7386</PhoneNumber>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/John.P.Doering</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. John P. Doering</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Johns Hopkins University</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Alfred.O.C.Nier</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:45Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Prof. Alfred O. C. Nier</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Deceased - formerly at University of Minnesota</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Paul.B.Hays</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Prof. Paul B. Hays</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>University of Michigan</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/D.T.Pelz</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Mr. D. T. Pelz</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Unknown - formerly at GSFC</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/John.H.Hoffman</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Dr. John H. Hoffman</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>University of Texas at Dallas</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Henry.C.Brinton</ResourceID>
    <PersonName>Mr. Henry C. Brinton</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>NASA Headquarters</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/William.B.Hanson</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Prof. William B. Hanson</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Deceased - formerly Director, CSS, U Texas, Dallas</OrganizationName>
  </Person><Person xmlns="http://www.spase-group.org/data/schema">
    <ResourceID>spase://SMWG/Person/Nelson.W.Spencer</ResourceID>
    <ReleaseDate>2010-08-05T17:35:47Z</ReleaseDate>
    <PersonName>Dr. Nelson W. Spencer</PersonName>
    <OrganizationName>Deceased - formerly at GSFC-Code 910</OrganizationName>
  </Person></Spase>


